<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"Life in a Mining company in Montana, All Fools' Day at Canyon Ferry"
At iho Canyon Ferry House). Iiepb by.
our old friend Cnnt. StalTord. is wont lo
meet occasionally tho Jolly bnrhelors of
mo Hujaeeni mines, wuu sot nroumi lltu
bnr.qunfl' their bovorog'cs nnil bewail lliclr
sad and lonoly lives of bachelorhood.
On Saturday evening, April 1st, whllo a
party of thoso dUcousnlato chap wero
engaged In Iho pastime mentioned. above,
a spanking team was drivHti. to tho par
lor door, by I. il. Tyler, ami by his side
sat n blooming and buxom lemule, who
wns politely, handed out of thu vehicle
nnd shown to tho parlor. A buz of nil
miration went up from tho crowd, nml
Mn Tyler wns interviewed ns to tho pn
ternlty and prdlgreo of tho lovely strnn
gor. These Inquiries wero snttuflcd by
thu stntntm nt that Mr. Stafford bail dls-
chnruetl his ittnlo cook, anu tho truly was
nn interesting widow, who lintl consen
ted to superintend tho cuisine affairs of
the household. Tho crowd otilotl v dron
ped olf their cabins, donned their "bllr-d."
shirts, shaved cl nu, nml dropped back
to the hotel, ono after nitothar, each ono
with it pnliiifntlng heart, nnd n quiet
chuckle to lil'tisell that ha- was looking
supremely smooth, and would recelrc
tho first introduction nnd smiles of the
widow. As they entered, Mr. Tyler
led their, one by one nnd presented them
to their fancied Idol, until the room wns
crowded with rivals, Captain Stafford,
wllh his eye on Iho knot-holo, tinted tho
happy countenances of tho baeholors,
nnd Iho witching smiles of tho widow,
whllo Tyler did tho nmlnblc. Tho
Judge of thu district, n happy, Jolly
bachelor, but, unfortunately, very thin
haired, borrowed n wig for tlio occnlon,
nnd appeared befose thv widow, with
his ours pinned back, nnd looking upon
tho minors with tho lofty contempt
which he felt bis position would give
him over bis rivals lo tho lair willow's
eyes. Tho guests having been all Intro
duced, Joo Stnirer, finally summoned
courngo to tako a sent by her sldo nml
engaged her in conversation ; but what
was his horror upon discovering tho
fair female gently raised her whlto skirts
nml shovo her hand Into tho pocket of n
greasy pair of buckskin brcechos, which
wero hidden by flowing garments, and
from which she hauled n plug of tobac
co, and pasFcd It to her admirer with a
winning smile, nnd tho polite invitation
of "Juo tuko n chaw '" Joo fell bnek iu
amazement, nml exclaimed, "Buys, if
this y'ar isn't Jim Fulsom iu pottlconts,
I'm a cnyuso." The April fool sell wns
then seen through, and Tyler had to
bent n hasty retreat, whllo thu supposed
widow niHilo her exit through tho bnek
door nnil hroko for tlic bush lo cscnpo
the wrnth of thu crowd. Tho Jtttlgo
now hicks only thirteen hnlrs of being
halt! headed, owing to the wrathful man
ner iu which hn ran his lingers through
bis thin locks, when ho learned that the
lovely widow was none olhor than Jim
Fulsnm, a smooth-faced miner, rigged
out for tho occasion. Helena Gazette.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/seq-2/#words=april+pranks+fools/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>April Fool.
The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
aod as impossible to determine as the birth?
day of the first fool who marred Nature's
original design of intellectual Man. We
trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
its birth ba files research. We are forced to
admit its existence, without being able to
assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer?
tainly carried its memory in all their con?
quests. Its observance was long cherished
among numer?os nations. Abandoned to
the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
refinement, Momus seems to revenge him?
self by selecting the most elevated and dig?
nified objects for bis practical jokes. Nor
man, cor nation, nor things visible, nor
things invisible can elude bis satire. Nature
herself seems convulsed with his sly sport.
Her groans over a fallen race turn into in?
voluntary, hysterical laughter at the bidding
of this giant Harlequin, on whose kingdom
tbe Ban never sets.
The most pathetic scenes provoke the
wildest mirth. We see men of bonor and
repaie taking advantage of National schemes
to secare private emolument; dividends the
only consideration, the divisor of no conse?
quence. April Fool 1 Divisor of scheme,
plus dividends, laughing at his dupes, and,
thanking Heaven he is not like other men,
proving bis integrity by tbe faith of his
fr ?en dB. April Fool !
The rightful Government of Louisiana
using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti?
ling Kellogg platform ; striking the first
blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
sending representatives to the Union at
large, convinced that her distress must be
of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
balance cac not be determined; giving a
gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of j
bowling it down. April Fool !
England's tories and whigs doing their
best to destroy the ablest minister of the
Crown on the question of the Irish Univer?
sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
"cummin" while neglecting the weightier j
matters of tbe law. April Fool !
France with Thiers more iban king, shoot?
ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la R?publique 1
"A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
April Fool !
Ukraine peasants revolting against an
?utocrat who owns half the Continent of
Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
br the mere chance of being discharged at
heir masters' heads. April Fool !
Each nation convinced that "the Par lia
"mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
:ree. April Fool 1
Each sect persuaded that the whole world
viii soon have bat one Faith, and that Faith
ta own especial creed. April Fool 1
Honor, probity, patriotism, troth and
rirtae sb/J! prove'a successful candidate
tgaiost rampaot Vice. April Fool I
All the world surging, restless, doped and
laping, cries: April Fooll
Deep calling onto deep in awfal sport-all
.be waves and waterspouts shoaling in
nocking derision : April Fool I And men in
childish rage and impotent wrath yell to
?ach other and the Universe at large: Toa
ire-April Fool 1</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/seq-11/#words=april+fools+pranks/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ON ALL FOOL'S BAT
i
Brainy Men Ten of First of April
Fancies.
Actor, Artist, BatlrUt, Lawyer, Preacher.
Etc, All Have Something to bar
About This, the Fool
Catcher's Day.
COPTBIOHi; 183 L
H E stage is in
Eomo measure
responsible for
All Fool's day.
So the histo.
rians tell us.
They say it
grew out of an
old Easter
miracle play in
Irhich the sending of Christ from An
bas to Caiaphas and from Pilot to
Herod was the basis of the mediaeval
Jramatist's plot. But I don't think
Hie stage has stuck to its offspring.
We actors are a serious lot of people,
particularly the comedians among us,
for paradoxical as it may seem, acting
Is all work and no play, and conse
quently Jack is a dull boy. We would
"MSTEIt, TXEASE GIVE ME A IIFT. JTLI.
TOU?"
T like to April fool our manager, perhaps,
but we don't April fool ourse'ves, be
cause that would be rather cruel.
I have outgrown the frolicsomenes
of April 1, of course; still I always look
carefully after my coat tails on that
day. And I greatly enjoy the motley
of those who are careless about their
parraental caudals during the Feast of
All Fools. The sight makes me feel
quite a boy again, for we youngsters
used to do that sort of thing in Phila
delphia thirty years ago. 0 yes, I did
It, too. I believe that some of the live
lier children of Philadelphia do it yet,
and have vitality and energy enough
left to laugh at the result, as a comio
paragrapher would say.
The most foolhardy of all the tricks
which I can recall in connection with
this carnival of jeering and nonsense
Is one that I have never seen played
Eince I was old enough to require two
digits to express my age. A bag and
two boys were the ingredients of the
trick, and it never failed to 6core a
great success on a quiet side street.
One boy got into the bag and the other
Stood by it waiting for the victim. The
rest of the boys who were "in on the
ground floor" were hiding in hallways
and doors and behind trucks across
the street. An innocent citizen came
W sauntering along. The boy who had
hold of the neck of the bag stopped
him with a "Say, mister, please give
toe a lift, will yer?" The innocent cit
izen usually acquiesced and took hold
of the bag to land it on the youngster's
shoulder. Just as he got it fairly in
his hands the boy in the bag suddenly
kicked and screamed. Innocent vic
tim, thinking it a bagful of wildcats
or hypnas. let go quickly and ran off
with palpitating heart and hair on end.
while all the boys across the street
pursued him with a villainous chorus
of "April fool 1 April fool! Wash
.your face and go to sclioU" or
something to the same effect. It
Talways seemed to me that the joke
was really on the boy in the bag;
he was sometimes dropped hastily
and heavily and was hurtand occa
sionally the April-fooled citizen gave
him a thrashing besides for being too
funny. But it was an effective trick.
and often an old codger lingered in the
shadow on the opposite pavement to
witness and enjoy the sport. You have
seen a man try to kick a plug hat full
of pig iron over into tho next state
Trell, bis discomfiture was no greater
IT MADE AIM SMD.E.
Good Ola reliOK Ali, hoT it warms ri7
bcart to see them playing their littlo inuoccm
tricks on the Brst or Apnlt Used to do It my
self when I was a toy. But ibey caa't fool me,
though I'm too oU a bird lor fiat.
than that of the man whoso blood was
frozen in his heart by the unexpected
scream emitted by the occupant of the
bag. Laugh? It would make a tomb
stone roll over in a fit of hysterics.
Jonx Drew.
fOMETIlIES IT GIVES PLEASURE TO OTHERS.
It doesn't seem right that the firs
flay of a month so full of pretty things
j is April is should be inseparably con
w nectcd in our minds with empty ard
dilapidated pocketbooks with string
in d-small-boy attachments, di&rep
ntable hats with bricks underneath
them, long streamers hanging from
l nnsuspecting coattails, door bells
rung by invisible hands, and all the
other dear old pleasantries that we
know by heart. And we should prob.
ibly have had a society for the pre
rention of Anril fool iokes Ions aso if
It were not for the pleasure that call
aren gel out of them.
When a certain boy of my acquaint-
fcnee on April Grst. before breakfast,
Informs me that somebody is waiting
ft;' see me in the library, not for the
world would I refuse to go downstairs
and pretend extreme surprise at find
ing nobody there. Nor would any
thing induce me to decline the suspicious-looking,
cotton-filled piece of
candy which is shortly after offered
--. . V.T. a fmnll rrirl I know. I bitA
UlUiD .- O "-
.-& End- Hotter SS6? itLISSrularly i
every year, ana Mr. rfat Gooxnvm or
Mr. Francis Wilson would be glad if
he could raise such a shout of laughter
as easily and unfailingly.
Apropos of this train of thought
there is a little picture of mine in Puck,
published some years since, which will
perhaps bear transplanting here, and
which I subjoin.
Fbedeiuck Buitn Oppeb.
"de bazoo" is suggested.
If yer want a good joke on some ot
yer frcn's, give dem de razoo, see?
Dat's de way dey do in Xew York oa
April Fool day.
Yer work it dis way:
Suppose a man owes yer ten dollars
and won't pay yen Go see him and
ask him for it. He ses he ain't got it.
Wipe de floor wid 'him and take all de
cash in his pockets and when he kicks
apologize and se.y yer didn't mean fer
ter hurt him it'b April Tool, see? Den
yer needn't pive him de money back,
'cause he owe s it, yer see? Course yer
don't want ter try de razoo on anyone
not under yer size, see?
Den yer kin pay off all yer old
grudges de same way. Or if yer hun-
gry and ain't got no money walk inter
de restrint, see, and eat all yer kin,
and say it's April Fool, see, and run
out widout payin' nothin'.
Dat's de racket fer April Fool de
razoo. Steve Erodie.
TO LESSEN THE DEVTL'S FOOLS.
I am abked for a sentiment concern
ing April Fool's day and pause in the
whirl and rush of a righteous warfare
to say that in my opinion time is far
too valuable and important a factor
for a moment to be lost in foolish jest
ing or senseless joking. The world,
especially in these days, is in far too
critical and dangerous a position, so
cially and religiously, to allow of a
man with average sense to saj' noth
ing of those who have consecrated
brains to indulge in any other than
profitable and upright intercourse.
It is a personal relief to me to feel
that in our ranks seventeen hundred
officers and sixteen thousand unpaid
local workers will be pushing with
might and main of soul an enterprise
which upholds sincerity and the ne
cessity of lessening the devil's fools.
Ballington Booth.
A CHA3IPI0X FOR THE DAT.
Before stating what jokes seem to
me timely, and enjc&abJe ior this
S&-
" WIPE DE FLOOB WID niil."
April Fool's day, I cannot resist th
temptation to say that I think the
spirit of the holiday itself hat always
been singularly misunderstocd. The
day is really to be deemed a pause in
time's serious flight, when folly could
with propriety travesty wisdom, and
set the world smiling. As it is, the
first of April has come to be deemed a
nuisance, wheu its observance is not
don away with entirely. April Fool's
day is sadly in need of soue one to
champion it and xestoi e it to its right
ful place in the calendar. It is not
simply the day on which the boys and
girls may make fools of their elders
with impunity. I suspect that there
was a time when it was regarded
rightly, far away as that time seems
to us now. Then the old people put
aside their serious looks and grew
younger instead of older.
If it takes a wise man to be a fool,
surely April first is the feast day
of the saircs. when thev can act on
Shakcspsare's admonition: "Mingle a
little folly with your wisdom."
As for those jokes which seem to mi
good and appropriate to the dav it
should always be understood that the
element of surprise is the essential
thing. Novelty is wit. Jokes must not
bo cruel pranks, otherwise the day
would ba given up to a general hazing
of everybody. The most successful of
April Fool jokes would be to surprise
one's friends by a change of character.
What a rare joke it would be for the
confirmed miser to bestow a dowry
upon that niece of his who needs only
a little money to marry the lad of her
choice. If all the cranks would put
rside their hobbies for a day, what fun
it would be for the rest of us.
This kind of joke can be carried out
ad finitum and would never fail to bo
successful. Let the tippler remain
sober to-day just as a joke. The skin
flint employer can have a lark with
his clerk by granting that increase of
salary that has been talked about so
long. Let the clergyman I say it
reverently preach a sermon only an
hour long to-day instead of one of
four hours' duration. I am convinced
that the idea would meet with success.
People too old for jokes on April
Fool's day? Xouscnc. Even the gray
heads can have their joke. The repro
bate roue can go to church this morn
ing and explain that it is all a joke on
his part. Many a man is ashamed to do
a good thing because it is so unusual
with him that it would give him un
pleasant prominence. But he can do
it to-day and escape with the admis
sion that it is his April fool joke. I
am glad the day comes on Sunday this
year. B. Gillax.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024442/1896-03-29/ed-1/seq-17/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>One Would e-neso frnm llilc
description that they were taw-fiMi, that
Is, wise-saw fish, hut they were not. They
were eimpij- hucKeru; yec mey knew It
was April 1'ool'b Day.
On tljat Fame
day a man went
Fooling the Fishes-Bait 3SSa J "J
Without Hooks. sot him down on
the wharf and let
downhisliiicand
bait. The water
was clear and he
could ee the
6uckers blinking
and winking at
each other and
rubbing their
nuouts, against
tlie tempting
bait.
"HeiliinkKhe's
run up against
the highland
suckcr."mid fin
ny No. 1 to. scaly
No. -, and noo
dle No. :t i early
swallowed the
bait at short
range laughing
at the sucker at
the o'lier nil of
the'ne. But he
fWifdrifJitalong
till the fun grew
hot.imd (hen he
Tilled his pipe
and hauled up
his line.
Nov.h-'reisa
moral 'nthisMo
ry. Th'-re was
no jojK in the
merry li'-l.er-m
a n ' s b a i r,
wlui h goes to
show that peo
ple who .ue too
wise to "Lite"
very often get
left. e en as the
fish didn't know
a good Uiing
when it was in
dubitably i n
their line.
And on that
same day in the
same generation,
a spinster lady
declined to ojX'ii
a letter, good
forthisdayonlv,
no rain checks. Is
sued, which letter
con tninoda bona
fide healed pro
IKaltj,.Uheand MieMioukl tarry
togetlier at Jeri
cho, or an j place
elM- where there
was good tarry
ing, swooning
and crooning in
the thick after
noon iK-rfiimeof
lot uracil orange
blos.-om. And
the next da j the
died.
Oil the 1st of
April, la-t, a
joung wieacre,
who lives on
New Ilauipclure
aieuuc. received
a letter ,y f.pe.
cial im-sMMiger.
It wab fcuper
bcribedina plain
round hand, and
in the left-hand
corner were the
words "Pmate;
marked down to
10, former val
ue &o." The
letter was re
turned to the
writer, with the
remark on the
margin. "Don't
need any spring
clothes." The
lot terrnerel j con
tained a part
Iiaynient of $20
on a $30 -debt
or honor" which
accrued from
lost borrowed
chips
So when the
bride of only
two Aprils tcle
Kraphed to her
husband In New
i'ork from
"Washington the
thrilling mc-s-fiage.
"Two ana
all's well," lie re
ceived it, "Two
and all swell."
He replied 'Had
eight. -a j self and
feel much swcll
er." She ws a
little -mrpi-ised,
to be sure, and
whei icy grow
up she will tell
the twins about
the mind reading
capaeu y cf a
handsome clerk
of the Oimis Of
fice. These hlMorl
calcaes are not
ed by way of pre
lude to i he slate
ment rhat April
Fools' Day Is
again with us, or
will be on "Wed
nesday next. Af
ter these i-ad ex
amples of mind
read mg, it will
be only t tie more
perplexing to
discover the dif
ference between
looking the gift
horse !u the
mouth and the
gift horse him
self should lie
gallop up to the
door.
One half of the
world will begin
on "Wednesday to,
play pranks on
Uie other half,
and it is an in
teresting day be
cause we have
only two such
days on Uie cal
endar, the other
being Talentine
Day. Election
day Miotild. per
haps, be added,
buttoallofthem
FaUier A braham
undoubtedly re
ferred when he
got off the fa
mous bit or phi
losophy, "You
can fool all of
the people tome
of Uie time, etc.,
etc. otr. ."
The misfortunes of the day are hke the
premonlUons of fctieezeg. STou know they
are coming, but you can't prevent their
arrival, so It is much better to Miecze
at once, even If your mouth Is full of
turtle soup, than to fight against the in
evitable. It Is better even to take in
the bundle on Uie doorstep than to kick
Ef 55
Vtr
JEm)
Some Old and New Jokes Suggested
The Times for Next Wednesday.
Of Course the Small Boys' WeMried and Proven Schemes Wil
Hold Sway, hut There Is a Chance to Extend Them
into Municipal and National Life
TH SUMS
uoke
by
v d y
f art" and 'Teller." havinsr done -which ha
strode oat of the room. leaviojr the second
fiddle- to play out the score.
It will probably be a bad d7 for king
makers, ho wevcrgooditniay be rorpotitical
fctol makers. In a quiet, coay room In a
Philadelphia hotel there are gathered
together the elect of the Warwlcka
of this day and generation, fore
most among whom are Piatt, Quay and
C I ar krer .
"V.
fffj VfLLET vairR
STRlFHi iu v
rti r SL. . x pA.
.,mn jr.r.
iA the o rryki ittL -T Ak
Some Ancient and Honorable April Fool Jokes.
Uie little stranger Into the street. There
may be millions awaiting the long-lost
heir before jou die.
The compliments of the season are firstly
due to Uie three destinies of "Washington.
Messrs. Koss, Truesdell and Poweil. Tliej
will do a land-office business on April
Fools' I)a . They will be bitting at a Uel
shazzar's feast, and lo' there appears on
Uie wall a strange bcroll in the Kalorama
dialect.
The Attorney for the District and the
interpreter of the clastic law of the local
Medcs and Persians Is called in and he is
promised fine raiment and an amethystine
ring ir he expounds the letters of fire on the
wall. Kefer.'ncc to Uie snap shot of the oc
casion will be found in the margin or tins
page. Of course, tins maj not happen, but
it ought to, which isa much better considera
tion. There is one place in the United States
where eerj thing can happen, proidcd
always it is not something practical even
will enforce the rules and order the gal
leries to be cleared.
Mr. Morrill of Maine Mr. President, I
have lieen llfty jcars in the Senate in the
ambassadorial capacity of a Senator from
Maine, atrl I have ncer jet heard
The Toreign Voice I am a talker my-f-clf.
(Renewed applause from Uie gal
leries.) The President The sergeant-ai-arms will
arrest that obnoxious peiaonage.
The galleries are cleared, and the ser-
whlch to exclude the April Foots Day dis
turbers of the White House peace.
In the mind's ee, without even a warm
application of the Roentgen ray, it is easy
to see the fighters against follv seated at
the table in what the President told the
delegation of Baptist ministers was his
"workshop." Ip a certain sense, tin-, is
true, because It is there lie saws wood. The
President casts aside carefully all tlie
suspected letters and puts all the packagi-v
Iu a tub of water near him on the floor
to kill the microbes and anymcidental dyna
mite. The morning is passed away pleas
antly, and he asks for a cigar.
"What kind, extellenzaZ" queries F. A.
H '!'.. in one-third Spau'sn and two-thirtls
Iiayard.
"A Duke of Veragua," replies excellenza.
and Fie-Tt!oi!sard-DolIars-a-Year in the
future opens a new Ijok. The rest of this
story is done in black and white pictonally
on this Seventeenth Page. In scene the sec
ond the unfortunate bot-opener la on his
tr
, )
iiiiinwifi ll'ir i5j
4m
April 1 at the District Building:.
A Neat Little April Eiiect in the Senate.
a Joke. To guess the name of that place
is not as hard as guessing the number of
five black beans in a transparent jar. It
is the United States Senate,
In the afternoon of "Wednesday next,
after the morning hour, the Cutian olla
podrida will be in full blast. Senator
Lodge will hae spoken on the letter that
never came to Secretary Olney, Senator
Mills will hae taken Cuba "vi et aimls,"
and Senator Hale will have delivered his
accustomed eulogy on the late Don Canovas
de Quixote. The listening Senate ib suddenly
startled by a thin foreign voice, which
says, "I'm something of a talker mjself."
Applause breaks out in the galleries.
The President of the benatc-If these
demonstrations are repeated the President
vtw n
A Joke on the Republican RiBg-sters
geantr.it-arms and Firsts Assistant Stewart
rush up into the peanut' reservation. They
return and report that the miscreant has
escaped.
The Presldent-The Senate "will be In
order.
Mr. Chandler As I was saying, Mr.
President, I
The Torclgn Voice I am something of a
talker mjself.
Nothing could exceed -the commoUon in
the Senate when its courtesy was thus sat
upon and spat upon by this intruder. It
was the eagle eje of Senator Sherman
of "Our Foreign Relations" Committee
that discovered the intruder, winch was
quietly looking askance at the President
out of its white-winged eye, a beautiful
queen red and gold parrot direct from Bar
celona. "It Is a Spanish spy," declared Mr.
Lodge.
"It should be shot at drum head," as
severated the fiery Tennessean.
"Try it from the clock," said Mr. Mills.
"Willi the Presidential gun," added Mr.
Hill of New 1'ork. i
Suggestions, however, do not kill birds
at long range, and. the pages were on the
qui vive of excitement lo be let loose on
the most consistent talker at that moment
In the Senate. They were eager for the
bird to fly down and light on tlie bald head
of some Senator, like the eaglathat alighted
on the head of the husband of Tanaquii.
But the spy did not move, keeping his
sinister eye on the Vice President, and
evidently getting ready to sing his unwel
come song again.
Mr. Lodge Eutcka, lMr. President: Per
scalam ad avem.
The President Gqod; has the scrgeant-at-arms
a ladder about him?
The sergeant-at-arms at -once procured
Uie ladder on which he climbed into office,
placed it up against the lintels of the' east
door, and reached for ithe parrot, which
was seated on the Senatorial clock a la
Poc's raven.
Did the sergeant-at-arms land the bird?
Not on your negative. The bird had a
string tied to him and. he'-was hauled aver
the parapet, and tle small boy at the oUicr,
end of the string simply hauled In the fes-'
the Spaniard, opened a -gallery door and
went down stairiand .filled himself full of
apple pic.
This may not happen.but It ought to. A
son of one or the surviiors of the Ford's
Theater disaster would be tlie logical perpe
trator of this lecfure by the pariot to the
Senate.
Too mucU .sympathy cannot be -wasted be
tween now and "Wcdnesdaj'onthefeeilngs of
the Chief Magistrate "with respect to his
mail and exprc packages on the day -we
celebrate. Thcrofhavc plrendj' been con
ferences between him anci Fldus Achates
Henrlcus Tiberius on taii; beet manner in. I
rjtt&n.
knees ascrvatmg in shattered sentences to
the accusation or the Potentate of the Poto
mac that he smelt treason in the tainted
gale.
"if third term doesn't go, lese mnjeste
doe-." thunders the man of destiny.
"1 know it doe?, Your Majesty, but by
the saber of my father I knov not who is
the nuereant, unless it be some godless
member of the 1. W. X. M. of the Occi
dental provinces."
"And who are they, caitiff?"
l-eonie who Need Missionaries, Ex
cellcnza." "Then, bj- mj- halidom, they shall have
Uiem galore before the ides or April."
And with that His Mijestj-seized bis tab
lets and wrote deep in the wax"'Colorado."
"North Dakota," "Oklahoma," "Stew-
til
r
Somebody's Little Joke en Groyer.
Little Willie's OrieinaJ
Idea.
U (!L
''r
T'&ryS "U
misfortune "vr K7 ""7 JaB
trying to ! J "M
doiitwheth- X Nr"V 1 H
there's a V A V l
-"vvr-' . "rv.-oB
A-N1
sV: ,', V-
J
f
.r
They are not
afraid of any
sword of Da
mocles.orknlfc up the sleeve
of Crofcer. or
any other gift
of the Greeks.
But they didn't
reckon on tie
.'deus ex ma
chiua" of a
Philadelphia
hotel.
With a rattle
of tfti plates
and a creaking
of woolen cord
a g e, down
comes Mr. Mc-Kinlej-.
stuffed
full of the
"looks that
way," and the
reast and fun
go out with the
lights and
that Is noioke.
The tevsons
of April Fool's
Day are many
and valuablelf
studied practl-callj-.
A man
stiouM not let
his hcue burn
down becaus",
wiseinhisown
conceit, I s
neighbor telLs
him that r.ts
house is on fre.
At the farce
tirnr, if all tl e
night caps and
nightdresses in
Paradise allej
are sprinkled
from the hose
of the small
boy on the roof
who has been
paid to sLai.t
"fire," It enly
goes to show
that there is a
certain degree
of
in
fin i
lire in your
own house by
looking out of L.
the window.
The place to ; r.
look is in the . ir3-'
bamcnt, or
any other In-sidepreclnct-Again
the
nan who pas
s wisely bj- a
silver dollar on
the pavement
feels had when
he looks back J JCTI-i' J
and sees that r
another man 4 t
has parted it up
safely. If it's a -
iweketbook the
eae is all t'ic
sadder. Or. If
the man w.'.o
believes that ic
is better t fa'ce
in the baby off
the d. orst p,
takes itardtelL,
hKi wife al.ut
it, maj- r pcu
the bundle to
find in itc ncof
ouroldfriTiis,
the rag labj.
So, agam. the
bnckinthehat
Is inevitable,
but it Is no use
to go home in
that condition.
It. of coarse,
requires a good
deal of forti
tude and saw
teeth to eat a
cotton batting
dumpling, or to
chew, with a
scriptural face
even a small
piece of candy
with a j-anvin-side,
but it is
said that It ha3
been done rath
er than ac
knowledge the
joke, but in "r ' !
nearlv all nf : !""
Uie instances
Uie patients
died as mar
tyrs, like the
Who let: the Z. .! T
foc eat. nut of ' 'wil '
his breadbas
ket rather thnn
be indicted for I f
dealing the
fox. I I
If you find
It yarn or cot
ton, spit n c ut i ?sgss3 &
- iiiuii. i is ' vt -5;,
Reach for all I t?it'i SS
the nunev in
sight, ric up
all the pot'et
books, open all
jour icttcrs,
receive all the
visitors in or
out of myster
ious lirdles,
foronth.s par
ticular da it's
the only way
to i o e t h.e
problemsof the
other fool. It
Is somewhat
strange that a
person wl o be
lies esat it is
theucexrcctcd
that always
happens.scoms
to look behind
him when a
small boj- jay
to him confi
dentially: "Mis
ter, jour lorse
hasdroppedhis
tail." it is
human nature
to look back
when he has
turned the cor
ner. There have
beenverymnny
8age tomes
written about
the origin and n HfTTT f
uses of April ,h; rrh7-
Fool's Day.
Som writers
ascribe to it a
Roman, and
others a Greek
origin, it is
more than likely that It began on the day
when Esau tried to pas himself off for
Isaac with their bliud parent. Abraham.
Atu.ia.tia, i.onutr, dtetovrtl tUat the
kLii.iI okC-r lad hair en hi brain and.
tho t o-n. of Esau was launched for all
the rget. They have had hairs on their
brains cer since.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>APRIL CALLED
OUT ALL ITS
ARMY OF FOOLS
The Jester and Victim
Alike Make Merry.
THE MORGUE'S BUSY DAY
McENERNEY AND HIS COUN
TERFEIT PRESENTMENT.
Sad Tale of the Dentist Apprentice
and the Soubrette Who Could
Not Find the Key to the
Curtain.
April dawned bright and beaming and
kept merry throughout its. first day
blithely warbling between laughs, "Al!
fools look alike to me."
In spite of the fin de siecle pessimist
and his prophecy that All Fool's day was
a landmark of the past, the jester was
out In splendid form and landed gudgeons
galore.
The fun began early and lasted late.
A very few new jokes were perpetrated
and all the old ones revived, while the
usual good humor of both jester and vic
tim prevailed during the entire day. The
email boy was not so much in evidence
;is in previous years. Thoughts of Easter
eggs on the morrow, coupled with the ar
duous duties of trying on new suits and
boots and hats, drove for once all
thoughts of mischief from the mind of
the budding lords of creation. The offi
cials at the Morgue were the first to fall
victims to the merriment- of the day.
When the day was but a half hour old
—at 12:30 a. m.— a telephone call, pre
sumably coming from the Receiving Hos
pital, summoned a Deputy Coroner to take
charge of a body at the Hobson House.
"Hurry-up wagon" and Deputy went
quickly to the place, only to find that
April had dawned and that some one un
known wa? taking liberties with dignified
city officials.
In fact, the Morgue, or. rather, the
Morgue's telephone, was the greatest fcuf
: fen-r during the day. The bell rang un-
| -ceasingly from early morning until mid
i night and all sorts of messages were
voiced- over the line. Heartless wretches
also employes this method of fooling un
suspecting friends.
Tiner-aling-iing.
"Hello! Well—"
"Oh. la that you. Mary? This is Jim.
Say Mr. Wilson wants to speak with you.
Call him up— No. 1947."
•'Hfllo. No. 1947! Ts this Mr. Wilson?"
"No: this is the Morgue."
A bang— that's Mary's . telephone— a
enwe— that is the Morgue.
While people were having fun at the
expense of the city the' city was enjoying
Its own pet little April fool joke—repeat
ing the prank over and over a^aln and
hailing each new victim with shouts of
applause and the shrill tooting of horny.
At the junction of Market. Kearny. and
Third streets at regular intervals a box,
neatly packed and stamped, as though
rc-ady for mailing, would glare the guile
less pedestrian straight in the face. Many
a man, woman and child, representing all
sorts and conditions of society, stooped
to pick up the innocent-appearing box.
None got any farther than the attempt.
The shouts of the crowd, many of them
previous victims, scared the parcel-picker
off, and he hastily lost himself in the
throng and waited in his turn for some
one to laugh at.
It was both a costly and hair-raising
April fool experience that Walter Mosier
had. Mosier. a young man possessed with
an ambition to learn dentistry, is em
ployed by Dr. Perkins, a Sixth-street den
tist. Walter's bogs occasionally allows
him to putter around the molars of his
customers who are out of funds.
One of thes? occasions arose Friday and
Mosier was delegated to perform the
charity service. The, victim was a boy
about 12 years of age. He was suffering
from an ulcerated tooth, and Mosier de
cided that the nerve must be killed, so
forthwith he filled the cavity in the
troublesome tooth with enough arsenic
to kill a horse and sent the unfortunate
youth home happy.
When Dr. Perkins came in Mosier, with
the dignity of a full-fledged dentist, told
his employer of his charity work. Then
Dr. Perkins thought of April fool.
"Say, Mosier." said the dentist, with a
serious look on his features. "I've just
received a telephone message to the ef
fect that the arsenic came out of that
boy's tooth and he swallowed it."
"My God!" exclaimed, the would-be
dentist. lf ls he going to die?"
"Well, the doctors are working on him
now, but they don't think they can save
his life."
"Say. Doc, I'm going to get out of town
before this kid dies. I don't want to get
pinched."
"Well." said Dr. Perkins, with a merry
little twinkle in his eye. "You can suit
yourself about that, but I'd advise you to
stay here. They-can't do any more than
charge you with mupder."
"Murder! Ugh! Don't say that. Dr.
Perkins," retorted Mosier, tearfully. "I
didn't mean to do It. I'll go and take
some arsenic myself."
The crestfallen apprentice spent several
moments of contrition and then he made
up his mind to get out of town. He got
50 cents from Perkins and made haste to
the nearest barber-shop, where he Invest
ed it in a haircut and a Bhave. M osier
gave the tonsorial artist orders to cut
}-is hair to the scalp and Bhave his sprout
ing mustache entirely off, hoping thereby
m disguise himself. The badly frightened
youth then returned to the office to learn
further detnils of his mythical victim's
condition. Dr. Simpson told him th« boy
was worse and Mosfer. started to leave the
office. "Wait a minute." called Perkins.
"Where are you going?'
"God knows where I'll go, but I'll never
go to jail for poisoning- that kid," an
swered the youth.
"You go down to the ferry to-morrow
and if the boy dies I'll telephone to you,"
suggested the doctor.
Mosier slipped out to his mother's
home, borrowed 510 and as early as 1
o'clock yesterday morning he arrived
at the ferry thoroughly disguised to
avoid possible detection. He walked up
and down the cheerless and 'desolate
wharves till morning, and then not hear
ing anything from Dr. Perkins bought a
ticket for Sacramento and stole aboard
the boat like a skulking criminal. On
the train he acted for all the world like
a noted forger crossing the line to Can
ada.
ttosiec confided to a friend before he
left that he would commit BUicide rather
than go to jail, which knowledge tuning
to Dr. Perkins made him decide noi to
cfrty the Josh any further. A message
was sent to the frightened youth, and
he returned to the city. Last night he
set about to drown his troubles in the
flowing bowl.
Garret McEnerney fell a victim to a
deeply laid April Fool plot laid for him
by his "close up" friend Jim O'Brien..
The bulky and brainy man of the law
dropped into O'Briens office, commonly
termed the "Cabinet," yesterday noon to
engage the contractor in a little chat.
"Say. Garret." chipped in O'Brien in
an innocent fashion just when the law
yer was i-xplaining to Jim Nealon the
way to make money, "when did you
stand for that bust over in the Palace?"
"What bust?" queried Mr. McEnerney.
"Why. the file they put in the corridor
of the Palace Hotel this morning," said
O'Brien as seriously as if he was talking
business with a moneyed man who want
ed- to spend a "thou or two" in street
work.
"There must be some mistake?" said
McEnerney. "No sculptor ever chiseled
me."
O'Brien is "close up," and his words
had weight with the man who was so
busy dissolving -the injunction against
Chief Lees that he did not stop to think
of April Fool's day.
"Let's go over, Jim, and take a look at
it," said MeEnernty, and .they both start
ed out tho door. O'Brien had no inten
tion of going over with his friend to seek
What he knew to be a myth, so he con
trived to' be excused In a manner ■ that
would not breed suspicion.
The opportunity presented itself when
Judge Lawlor happened along.
"I'm going to take the Judge on -for a
minute," said O'Brien. "You go over and
look at that yourself and I'll wait for
you."
Off went Mr. McEnerney and his April
Fool went down on the arc.hives of the
"Cabnit" as a decided success. Every.
body who dropped into the Cabinet was
sent over to the Palace Hotel to see what
McEnernev had looked for in vain.
"Pete" Dtinworth. the well-known vo
calist, was- the victim of a ghastly April
Fool josh. One of his friends telephoned
to Dunworth's • house early yesterday
morning and informed him that an inti
mate friend had died the night before
and was to be buried immediately.
"They, want you to be a pallbearer,
Pete," said th-e wily person at the other
end of the line.
"All right." said the popular tenor, af
ter expressing genuine regret over tae
unexpected death of his friend.
Promptly at 1 o'clock Dunworth, ar
rayed in a black cutaway suit and white
gloves, arrived at the .undertaking par
lors from which the supposed dead friend
was to have been buried.
"Is this where Mr. So and So Is to be
buried from." asked Dunworth, giving
the undertaker the friend's name and ad
dress.
"Why, he 1b not dead," said the under
taker, "who knew the man very well. "I
just ?aw him "at the corner of Sixth and
Mission."
At the Alcazar they revived the old the
atrical joke of the "key of the curtain"
with marked success. Mrs. Willie Dun
phy, the latest addition to the company,
ten minute* before curtain raising at thp
matinee, was sent on a hunt for the "key
to the curtain." "We can't open up."
said Stage Manager Bryant. "We have
lost the key to the curtain." Mrs. Dun
phy. who glitters on the bills as Miss
Howard, searched high and low for the
key and was in a condition bordering on
hVfiterics when the last bars of the or
chestra died away and the curtain was
lifted without a key.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Concerning the origin of the name and custom of All fool's day
contributed more to the extermination of
the heathen religion and its priests than
all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
though they were also freely employed.
The continuance of customs— especially
droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
the masses— after the original cause of
them has been removed. Is a very common
occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
firmly believed that "fooling" people on
the Ist of April is simply a perpetuation
of the annual public ridiculing of the old
Druid's and their superstitions.
Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
character, 13 thus claimed for April Fools'
day In a quaint old book of folk-lore
called "Father Time's Flyghtes." pub
lished in London In 1659. "numerous
Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
Fools on the First of April. This is said
to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah
sending ye dove out before ye water had
abated, on ye first day of ye month which
among ye Hebrews answers to our first
of April, and to perpetrate ye memory of
this deliverance it was thought proper
whoever forgot so remarkable a circum
stance to punish them by sending them
upon some fool's errand similar to- the
Ineffectual message upon which ye bird
was sent by ye patriarch."
The French associate with the first of
April precisely the same Ideas as do Enr
llsh speaking nations, but the person Im
posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*.
they style an April Fl3h or Polsson d' -v
ril. In the "Etymology of French pro
verbs," a most curious and delightful
work published In 1356. Billlngton I the
author, gives the following expiation
of the origin of April Fool customs / "The
word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and
length of time has almost totall- defaced
the original intention, which w^ as fol
lows: That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
took place about this time o'the year,
and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
and forward to mock and't->rment him.
1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caia
phas to Pilate, from Pilate -°- Herod and
from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
from thence, by which we send about
from one place to anoO«r such persona
aa we think proper subjects of our ridi
cule."
But It Is not only thrjU&hout Great Brit
ain, France and our/own country that
fools are made on U« nrst day of April.
The custom 1- elabrratfly observed
throughout Sweden, aid In Germany an
April fool la called elnen zam April
shlcken." The same custom haa also been
observed in India frm time immemorial.
Late in March of ach year the Hindoos
hold a great celetratton which they call
the Hull festival, of which the last day
is the greatest aid most general holiday.
During the con.nuance of the Hull, one
of its chief dl^rsions is to send people
on errands ar^ expeditions that are to
end In disapr^ ntment anl raise a lausi
at the expend of the person sent.
But the cistom of making April fools
has-been traced back to an antiquity even
greater t!** n that of the Hull festival of.
the Hind ° 9 - Tne ancient Persians wer»
accustorr«l to celebrate the period of the
vernal rruinox. which may occur as early
as ila-^n 22 or as late as April 23. with
elaborv*? festival tites and diversions; of
the Utter the chief was the making of
fool- precisely as we are accustomed to
mate them on April Fools* day.
jjp a quaint volume of poem.l bearing
tH title, "Verses On Several Occasions."
i,.id published In London. 1752, April Foola'
.ay is thus alluded to:
Now April morn b!*r Folly's throas exalts:
Now Dobb calls Nell and lauebs because ah*
halts.
"While Nel! meets Tom and Bays his tall la
loose,
Then laughs In turn and caJTa poor Thoma
"Goose."
In England, from earliest times, th»
ridiculous errands upon which the victim
of an April fool Joke •- sent have been
called "sleeveless errands." but the origin
and true significance of this term ar»
completely buried in oblivion and no an
tiquary has yet been able to unearth
them. These errands are as numerous as
they are Ingenious. Some of them hava
almost become classics, such, for Instance.
as sending a person to a book store for
the second edition of "Cock Robin" or
the "History of Eve's Mother": . sending
some one to a milk dealer for a pint ot
pigeon's milk and to, a shoemaker for an
ounce of strap oil. which, if the shoe
maker has been Initiated Into the Joke,
the Inquirer receives In the shape of a
severe blow from a strap acros3 the shoul
ders. AMY F. STOCKTON.PERSONAL IMPRESSIONS AND REMINISCENCES OF OOM PAUL KRUGER.
TJ3TE SUNDAY CALL.
dana handkerchief. Ont of cariosity I
entered the same church, anticipating of
course, that I should find It crowded, from
the mere fact that the President went
there. I was judging by what on» would
have looked for in Washington— or Lon
don. The little Pretoria church could not
have held more than a hundred or so.
yet I counted but twenty-four in the con
gregation, and of these the majority were
mothers with babes In their arms. The
President took his seat in an armchair
which had been specially provided for
him beneath the pulpit— this was the only
distinction he enjoyed over the rest of his
fellow worshipers.
The service was very simple — about the
sort of thine I should have found In
most Methodist or Congregational meet
ing-houses In an American villas*. Ther»
was a long prayer, a long: sermon, a hymn
or two. a chapter from the Book «f
4
period of eight days. April 1 Is the
octave of March 25, and the last day
of a festival octavo was always marked
by the greatest abandon and festivity.
At the New Year season especially all
sorts of wild, mirthful pranks were In
dulged In, and of these It is believed that
our April fool usages - were a part.
Origins of a religious nature have been
boldly claimed for April Fools' day by
many writers. An old English antiquary,
writing In 1753. states that the custom of
imposing upon and ridiculing people on
the Ist of April may have an allusion to
the mockery of the Savior of the world
by the Jews. Something like that which
we call making April fools Is practiced
also abroad in Catholic countries on In
nocents' day, on which occasion people
run through all the rooms, making a pre
tended search in and under the beds. In
memory, I believe, of the search made by
Herod for the discovery and the destruc
tion of the child Jesus and of his having
been imposed upon and deceived by the
wise men, who, contrary to his orders
and expectation, "returned to their own
country another way."
When the early Britons were Induced to
forsake' their Druidical priests and Idols
and to embrace Christianity, It was their
custom" for many years after to annually
hold in their churches at the commence
ment of April a great festival, resem
bling the Roman Saturnalia, at which
they indulged in a thousand ridiculous
and indecent ceremonies, gambols and
dancing grotesquely to ludicrous anthems.
These singular observances referred to the
exploded pretensions of the Druids, whom
this ' festival was designed to hold up to
scorn and derision. That there Is no more
effective weapon than ridicule was again
proved In this case, for this feast of fools
""Whence proceeds the custom of making
April fools? Answer: From a memorable
transaction happening between " the
Romans and the Sabine.3, mentioned by
Dionysius. Which was thus: The Romans,
about the Infancy of their city, wanting
wives, and finding they could not obtain
the neighboring women by their peaceable
addresses, resolved to make use of strata
gem, and accordingly Romulus instituted
certain games to be performed in the be
ginning of April (according to the Roman
calendar) in honor of Neptune. Upon no
tice thereof the bordqring Inhabitants,
with their whole families, flocked to Rome
to see this mighty celebration, whereupon
the Romans seized a number of the Sablna
virgins and ravished them, which imposi
tion, we suppose, may be the foundation
of this foolish custom." This most absurd
and wholly unjustifiable account of the
origin of making April fools is thus ridi
culed by a poet of the time:
Ye witty tiparks who makes pretense
To answer questions with good sense.
How cornea.it that your monthly Phoebus .
Is made a fool by Dionysius?
For had the Sablnen, as they -came,
D-partpd with their, vlrirln fame.
The Romans had been Jtyled dull tools,
"And they, poor Rlrls. been April Fools.
Therefore. If this be" n't out of season, -¦•'¦;;
Pray, think and give a better reason.
Some old folk-writers claim that our
April Fool customs are attributable to the
fact that the year formerly began, as to
come purposes and in some respects, on
the 25th of March, which was supposed
?o be the day of Our Lord's incarnation.
At that time' it was customary for all
festivals to continue for an octave, or
(Copyright and nil rights reserved.)
"The first of April lome do say.
TVoa «et apart for All Fools' Day;
But why the people call It «o.
Nor I nor they therr.reUes do know."
Thus an old English poet sings truly,
for It would be a hard matter to find any
one who can give an accurate and correct
account of how the Ist of April came to
be known as All Fools' day and of the ori
gin of the custom pertaining to It of then
_ trying to make fools
W\ of people generally
Sf , „ in every conceivable
tjrfjf V^ WS&JS"'"^ manner. In old
¦ books of folklore al-
most innumerable
r I jo^w statements are made
Bf &a concerning the or-
B y - . igin of • both name
it and custom, all dlf
' • " " ferlng as widely as
the poles and bear
" ; •. - ing not the slightest
Wlatlon to each other.
A learned antiquary, writing in 1599,
claims that our April Fools' day Is but a
continuation of the Qulrinalla, or feast of
fools, bf the ancient Romans. In- "The
British Apollo." a most ingenious work
published !n 17C8. I find the following:</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84028140/1902-04-01/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>April Fool Kept by All
People.
Gigantic Hoax Was a Complete
Success.
"This Is the first of April,
Hunt the gowk another mile."
From time itruneiuorlal thollrstof
April has been celebrated by all sorts of
hoaxes and playing of pranks. Tho
truo origin of April' Fool Is burled lu
tho dust of centuries and our great
est antiquaries seem unable to throw
any light on tho subject. Nearly all
people however, celebrate this day or
its equivalent and the similarity of
the practice and tho coincidence of
dutes establishes without n doubt In
the minds of authorities ihe fact that
It had an early nnd common origin
among mankind.
Nearly all tho peoples on the Conti
nent celebrate April Fool with pranks
and tricks, and even the Hindoos havo
a festival on tho 31st of March, called
Hull, which coincides vjlth our April
Fool.
Ono of the most popular amusements
on April 1, or All Fools day, as it Is
called, Is tho Rending of persons on
fruitless frrands. Unsophisticated
persons are sent to tho bookstores for
a copy of the "History of Eve's Grand,
mother," or to the chemist's shop for
"pigeon's milk," while small boys arc
sometimes sent to the harness shop for
strap oil, when a liberal dose of this
treatment Is usually administered to
the boy.
There Is a story told to the effect
that Francis, Duko of I,oiTaIne, mid
his wife owed their escape from cap
tivity at NanteH to this popular cus
tom. Arrayed as peasants, they were
makiug their way out. of the territory
when they were discovered by a wo
man who knew them. She Immediate
ly hastened to a guard, and told him"
that the Duko was escaping. "April
Fool," said the guard laughingly,
treating the matter as a joke, and
while he laughed the prisoners made
good tlieir escape
Occasionally a gigantic hoax Is per
petrated on tho people as a whole, and
such a one met 'with groat success in
London in I8RO. Some wag distributed
cards, bearing an official looking seal,
which read: "Tower of London Ad
mit the bearer to vlorv the annual core,
raony of the washing of the white lions
on Sunday, Aprij, 1, 1800. It Is par
ticularly requested that no gratuities
be given to wardens or their assistants.
Admitted only nt tho white gate."
This trick was highly successful,
and people swarmed to tho tower to
view tho washing of tho whlto lions.
NO HELP.
Farmhands Are Not to
be Had
And Are Being Imported From
Other States.
Chagrin Falls, April 1.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/seq-1/#words=april+fools+pranks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Tacoma Times.
THE DAY OF ALL FOOLS—WERE YOU ONE OF THEM?
BROKER
PHILL PS
TOJUIT
Patrons of the brokerage busi
ness operated by T. H. Phillips in
the Equitable building were look
ing glum this morning when the
word was passed along the line to
those who had Investments with
the concern that Phillips had quit.
It was circulated that - the as
sets would be small and the lia
bilities about $19,000. At the
office the operator would give no
figures ■; and Mr. Phillips at his
home' allowed his wife to make a
statement to the effect that he was
trying to effect a settlement with
creditors and would turn over to
them - some money and property.
How much she did not . say.
' At the office It was stated that
the business would 'be taken over
by Downing, Hopkins & Co., of
Portland, through whom Mr. Phil
lips has been doing 'business.
At Mr. Phillips' home his wife
said he was quitting business be
cause the legislature had passed a
law stopping it. • When asked
whether the business would con
tinue under the name of Downing,
Hopkins & Co. she admitted there
had been some talk to that effect.
It was said on the streets .this
morning that some Tacoma spec
ulators had been caught for; as
high as a couple of thomsam
apiece, and there was considera
ble concern for awhile over the
situation. . ;■• :
COUNCIL
BLUNDERS
'■■' In the hurry, to get the contract
signed and 4 the new i fire : house
completed . for East M ; street the
council overlooked the city char
ter last night and no v the whole
legislation ■:■. will ' have • to ' be . gone
over again. 1;.;/,-.-*:' -"t . % •- t .'■'■<''■ jg
Bids were received several, days
ago and Contractor Opperman was
given the job. The contract could
not ibe executed, however, for an
ordinance had ' not' been. passed.
1 The | ordinance was '•■ introduced
last night and rushed;to passage.
This S morning | it . was ■ discovered
• the > thing . was illegal ;as lit calls
■ for more money . than: can '. be ; ap
jproprlated■,' by * ordinance except
| when : the ordinance •* is ■ read  on
two separate nights. *t--jr" *
'•' The council will have to do its
legislating over next 1 week \ and it
will  • delay • the •■ fire ; house ; three
weeks. Er^j^^,-^;- w :'. r ; c :.;■*::/■'-■;•
White Girl Weds
Chinaman
(By United Press Leased Wire.)
VANCOUVER, B. C, April I.—
A special from Portage La Prairie,
Manitoba says: «w*"VTf, '^S¥'S!^^
m Chan 1 Sing, a Chinese Testaurant
proprietor, and i Nellie I Elliott, ! a
white girl of Melford, Bask., were
married ; yesterday. : The wedding
was i the close of a long conrtahlp;
The couple met In a hotel, where
they, were .working &In I Englan d
several years ago, and X had \ since
been I lovers. "i Chan !Is \ well ; »up
plled wKh thl» world's goods . and
Mln j Elliott is ; the possessor , of
a good education sad an attrac
tive face and mrt&sstoßga
;..; If paint be strained before using
It will '■'. cover 'more surface and
wear better.
The ? WiscoMte Btate i mintia la
con»llerlng;th« formation of an
aeronautic oo'lC*'fi^^^^^^^ffl|
0 Pure milt, whan frocan, pre
«ni« original :proportlo«,Ba
aWmm£ fof waajka*
TACOMA, WASH., THURSDAY E VENTMG, APRIL 1, I»OO
$3,000 in Gold
to the Pan
(By United Press Leased Wire.)
SEATTLE, April 1. — Three
thousand dollars to the pan on
Nolan creek, which gained fame
a year ago by bringing the atten
tion of the miners to the old
Koyiukuk diggings In Alaska, Is
the news that is brought to this
city by Billy Clarke, a pioneer
barber of Seattle, who reached
here yesterday from Circle City,
where he has been for the past
seven years.
Nolan creek, In the Koyukuk,
was struck by Johnson and Olson
in the winter of 1907-o*B.
ON BOTH BIRTHDAY GENERAL
BOOTH WILL LAUNCH SAL
VATION UNIVERSITY.
GEN, WM, BOOTH.
Drums will beat around the world
on April 10 and prayers go «p.in
50 languages from half a million
men and women in honor of the
eightieth birthday of Gen. win.
Booth, the ■ grand old ; man > who
heads the Salvation Army. .
.. The army, which I has i branches
from Iceland to India and Austra
lia, ia the product of the brain of
this veteran soldier , against . Bin,
whose brain Is as clear and active
today as it was a half century ago.
He has grown with it, and still di
rect Its minutest * operations. ■ %
All around the world the Salva
tionists will celebrate the birth'
day lof their leader. On. that day,
too, the : general .will show I fresh
proof of his virility by launching
the most ambitious ■ project .;» yet
started by the organization.Si-.
J A big University of Salvatls|i-r
--to cost $6,000,000, with branches
in London, New York and Chicago
—this is 4 Ocn. . Booth's latest plan
for advancing , his work. He Will
Issue » the I call^f ; funds, on 's his
birthday. Th« * purpose jtf #tny
school is ■to i train t workers In all
branches of ' Salvation work. I
: , |.
oivi/r «ma un lob*, ■
Bf HiM«J rrtM Lnu Wlw« ."
VICTORIA, j£ C April l«r
ona life w.a» lo«t In th« •arttnnfflte
which ahoofe tha oltle* of Tolrte end
Yokohama lh« day before U»« »t*»iO
«r Kag», Maru called "■ there, »ns
which ' arrived here today. *»«»»i»«
APRIL FOOL HUNTERS ARE
ON THE JOB TODAY
"All Fools' Day."
& Just why the first of April |1§
let apart as an occasion when
very.; wag ■ hoe "j license .to pra'otloa
iewptlon on tils fellow
man and get the laugh «n him no
nne seems ,to know, bat ; the : cus
tom is : gen©r«l and o* loss stand
ln«.* And after all i ttia pranks ol
the "April ; Fool H tinnt«rs s» gen
smlly tharmless.
PW t yoa I are ; not abta Ito ; langa
when |g tfhe laugh Is Yon ni MM
lc««p jrou* wtta WMIM to iflj</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1911-04-02/ed-1/seq-1/#words=april+fools+pranks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The San Francisco
SUNDAY
CALL
¥*ar 9/% v /^L v^ ' B l^W ■ * '■ ' v jl HUB MI vU
Aprill Fool</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>JOKERS ANNIHILATE ARMIES
April-Fool Pranks Play Havoc With
European "War Map.
According io me map wmcu t-roi.
U p Wrench has prepared and kept
I . .. .- -.....- .
In the corridor of the third floor of
Academic Hall, European armies have
made radical changes in their ma
neuvers. The French apparently have
given up the war and have fled to the
western coast of France. The Eng
lish have disappeared entirely. All
the German forces of the western
theater are quartered in Paris. In the
east, the Austrian and German forces
are massed in the lowlands of Prus
sia, surrounded by Russian and Ser
vian troops. A few Servians are left
as garrisons along the frontier. One
lone Austrian army corps has escaped
and is now stationed in the middle of
the North Sea.
The havoc Is attributed to some
April Fool prank.
Another Instance of April Fool
thoughtfulness was shown this morn
ing when a member of the Agricul
tural faculty phoned to the county
jail asking "who had left a call for
him."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88084272/1916-04-01/ed-1/seq-14/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058393/1922-04-01/ed-1/seq-5/#words=april+fools+pranks/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> LPRIL FOOL
JOKES,
Copyright. 1922, by McClure News
paper Syndicate.
"Oh. Uncle Wlggily! What's that
behind yo.U? I hope it isn't the Fuzzy
Ko!" cried Baby Bunty one morning.
The little rabbit girl had come over
to the hollow stump bungalow to
borrow a cup of flour.
"What's that? The Fuzzy Fox in
here?'" exclaimed the rabbit gen -Ionian,
and ho gave such a Jump that
ho nearly slipped over back ward
April fool!" laughed B... Bunty
' "Oh!" exclaimed L'nclo WlggiB, BO
suddenly that his pink nose almost
' stopped twinkling. "Oh. so this is the
, first of April, is it?"
"Yes, and I caught you first ofj
all!" laughed Baby Bunty.
And so she had, for she had come
I over early to the hollow stump bun
galow on purpose to do this.
"Did I really make you think tho
Fuzzy Fox was there, Fncle Wig
glly?" asked Baby Bunty 'is the bun
nf gentleman snt down to his break
fast.
"You surely did for 3 moment." an
swered the bunny with a lui.Kh. "I
had no Idea this was April Fool Dsjy
But no matter. My turn will come,"
and he carried his glass of water to
the sink, spilling it out.
"Why did you do that"?" asked
Baby Bunty In surprise.
"Because," answered Uncle Wig
gily, "I have known it to happen m
times past that my glass of water on
April Fool morning would be full of
salt. As I don't want to drink salt
water now I lust emntiod mv rlaiu
1 11 fill It myself with fresh water."
"Oh there wasn't any salt in your
glasi " suirl Nurse Jane
"No, " added Baby Bunty. "I never
thought of that trick. I wish I had
But maybe Oh. Uncla Wlggily! Look
out!" she suddenly crlrd. "Is that a
pin in your chair?" 1
Uncle Wlggily Jumped up as If a
gun had gone off. Hfe looked In his
chair but there was nothing there.
"April Pool!" laughed Baby Bunly
again.
I'ncle Wlggily said nothing but he
sat down rather harfl and ate his
br. ik fast. And when linby Bunty said
"Oh. look out the window and see
who's coming!"
Undo Wlggily nevor looked up
from his morning paler. But some
one was coming along the, path to the
hollow stump bungaliw. They were
Curly and Floppy Twlltytail. tho plg
gle boys. Floppv had a llttlo bas
ket. "Do you want to look In this and
see what there Is?" asked Floppy, ns
ho and his brother camo In after
nrafl.lln U'lnfnr, II...I. r..l . 1 .
" '"h Ul. l Ull III'!
mat.
"Well. I can pretty nearly gu
what's In tho basket," said the bunny
gentleman It's some sneezing pow
der or a lot of dried leaves' You can't
April Fool me again."
"Oh. really, we wouldn't do such
thing!'1 grunted Ourl
"I'll open the basket!" cried Baby
Bunty. So she did, and inside was .1
lovely piece of cake that Mrs. Twisty
tall had sent to Uncle Wlgplly.
"April Fool!" grunted tho piggie
boys.
"Well, this Is a proper kind of April 1
T
Fool Joke!" said the bunny as he ate
the cako. which was very good. '''It
seems I can't be sure of anything this
morning." he told Nurse Jane when
tho children had run out and the
bunny was finishing his breakfast.
"You must he very careful." said
Miss Fuzzy Wuzzy
"I will," promised Uncle Wlggily,
and he was. But even at that a num
ber of- April Fool Jokes were played
on him nothing very serious though.
Once Jackie Bow Wow barked:
"Oil. is that 11 hlir hnil I n u..n
coat, Incle Wlggily?'' The bunnv
nearly twisted off his pink noso to
look at his back, but there was no
hole in his coat at all. Another time
Kittle Kat offered Uncle Wlggily
some candy, and when he chewed It,
Why It was sour Instead of sweet!
And Kittle mewed: '.pnl Fool."
"Well. I think it's my turnto play
an April Fool joko on some one,"'
said the bunny gentleman after a
while. "I wonder what I can do?
T want to play a real Joke'
He hopped along a llttlo farther
and, all of a sudden, out from be
hind a bush jumped he Bob Cat.
"Oh. ho!" howled the Bob Cat.
"Your ears look very good to me this
morning!"
"Do they"" asked I'ncle Wlggily.
' Well, do you know what dav this
Is?"
"It makes no matter of difference
to me what day this is!" howled the
Bob Cat ' I on!y want "
"Dear me' Look! Look behind
you! Is that a hunter man coming
with his gun?" suddenly asked Uncle
Wlggily, pretending to see something
back of the Bob 'at.
a hunter man with a gun! Oh,
don't tell me that! Don't tell mo
that!" howled the bad animal, and
away he ran as fast as ho could.
"I can't tell you that, for there
Isn't a hunter there!" laughed tho
bunny. "April Fool! April Fool!" And
lo h id played a Joke on the Bob Cat
just In time.
"Ha! Ha!" laughed the bunnv. as
ho hopped safely along. ' April Fool
Jokes aren't so bad after all'" And
If the pussy willow doesn't cry Jn the
night and want to bo rocked to sleep
in the cat's cradle, I'll tell vou next
about Uncle Wlggily and the .nrll
shower.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025182/1911-04-02/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>An April Fool Church Party.
It isn't often that the eve of April
I Fool's day or All Fool's day of
the year, is observed in social pas-
street christian church had a flne
I |, Daughrity's class time Friday night, however, in mak
ing merry and acting "foolish" over
ex- the first, day of the fourth month of
art
Unique attractions such as
arcades and other di-1 the years arrival.
of the I A short program of musical and
recitative numbers were given and
much enjoyment had. Refreshments
of ice cream and cake were served.
Some one has kindly written out the
words of a self-mamifaqtured A|ni
DAILY GATE CITY
si
Warner's Rust
Proof Corsets
"A very long skirt model,''
you say. Yes, but not a bit
too long for current style
It completely encases the
hips, which take on the lat
est figure contour, through
the corset shape The soft por-
tion of the skrt that Is, the
part that extends beyond the
boning—is drawn close to
the form by the SECURITY
Rubber Button Hose Sup-^s
porters, making the corsets^
thoroughly comfortable what-fes,':'
ever the po&ture.
Cor. 8th
and Main St.
We re April Fcol folks in an April Fool
state:
We wear April Fool hats on our
April Fool pate
We do April Fool things in an April
Fool way
I11 this April Fool town we're go.
ing to stay.
the body than the trimming of the hat I Hear ns! Hear us! We April Pools
or garment. Deep cream or yellow sing
tones rather than white, are reckoned I The April Fools holler and make the
most desirable for lace accessories, I town ring
while the use of dyed lace and net to F01'
match other materials continue.
Square meshed Venetian laces lead
and are costly in the real, but not high
in excellent imitation nets and inser
tions. Square meshed Valenciennes is'O! We April Fool Girls with our April
also liked in edgings, insertions and Fool Face
all overs. FANNIE FIELD. Wear April Fool Flowers with April
Chorus:
we're April Fool girls and we're
April Fool boys:
Have April Fool Times, and April
Fool Joys.
Fool grace:
1 And Sing April Fool songs with our
April Fool voice
And the April Fool boys are our own
free choice.
O! The April Fool skies, and the
April Fool days,
Are the April Fool's pride and the
April Fool's praises:
1
Mr. Williams Entertained the Sun-j
beam Girls.
Yesterday afternoon at his parish
residence, the Rev. George C. Wil
am el a a os
of the young ladies of the Sunbeam
Circle of the Congregational church.
The meeting was the regular monthly
one that, is held the first Saturday of'
each month
For the April Fool sun and the April
Fool rain:
Warms the April Fool's blood, and
fills the April Fool's brain.
No April Fool wind, or April Fool
drouth,
Stops our April Fool's heart or
April Fool's mouth:
For April Fool's fun and the
Fool's song,
Are the April Fool's Life in
April Fool's home.
Garters are an integral part of the corset. No corset skirt
can possibly fit well witnout them, and the "Security" Rubbe,
Button are the best. Prise $1.50 and $2.00.
created much men-, ptreot.
ment the other evening and the words
are printed below this morning so
that all may learn them:
The April Fool's Song.
(Tune, Hot Time.)
an 1
Chapel Fund Meeting.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1904-12-25/ed-1/seq-28/#date1=1756&index=14&rows=20&words=April+Fool&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=april+fool&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1909-04-11/ed-1/seq-59/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=April+April-fool+Fool+fool&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=april+fool&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-03-27/ed-1/seq-76/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Signs of Spring, Virginia R. Smith, Santa Barbara
she went to a hotel where sin- knew
a lady wanted two kittens. No, the
lady had not any yet and she took
them gladly, giving Laura the $50. Oh,
how gladly Laura went home with the
money pinned safely under her cloak.
April 1 Laura was up with the sun
and put the money under the over
turned plates, and then skipped back to
bed. 'When grandma and grandpa
turned over their plate* that morning,
what, to their amazement did they
find but the fifty needed dollars. Glad
ly Mr. Foster set off to town with the
money,' driving the old horse that he
had no need of selling now. It was
not until weeks after did they find out
wlu> put the money under their plates
that happy April Fool's day.
FINANCES (ORE,
1836 Wonlman avenue. Kan Diego.
Logan Heights school, 5A grade; 10
years old.
t A LITERAL CUSTOMER
■
Dear Aunt Laurie:
This is not a true story. One day
I woke up and was wishing that It
was the first of April and I wanted to
play Home kind of trick on somebody.
This was easy to do, but 1 did. not
want to get caught at it. 1 went to
my bank and took a penny. I hail no
more In at the present time, but want
ed to buy a book telling about April
fool tricks. It cost 25 cents, but I
wanted to get It with l.cent, and did.
I knew a boy who wanted to get a
quarter's worth of sugar. I told him
to wait while 1 got the chisel and
hammer. I cut the penny Into four
equal parts anil then I went to the
store with the boy. When we got to
the door I stopped him and told him
to give me the quarter and I would
buy the sugar. He did so, and I asked
for the book and 1 gave him the
money, then 1 asked for a quarter's
worth of sugar and laid down a quar
ter of a penny and ran. The man
didn't know where I lived and-couldn't
find out. I gave the boy his sugar and
went home, which .was quite a ways
away. I think It was a me.an trick,
but the grocers were fooled. I don't
think I will ever do anything like
that again, but 1 had to imagine some
- thing.
Your nephew, .-
W II.MAT HA ASK.
2641 Pomeroy avenue; age 12 years;
grade A 6, Cornwell street school.
A LESSON FOR THE JUNIORS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
I am going to tell you about an
•"April fool joke that turned out very,
very sadly. • '■' **
One April Fools day papa's cousin
went to a party. While she was there
one of her friends pulled a chair out
from under her and, of course, she
sat down on the Boor. Her back hurt
her dreadfully all evening, but she
did not say anything about it.
She was a school teacher, and went
to school every day for a month after
'her accident. Her spine kept hurting
her worse and worse, until finally she
went to the doctor's. He told her that
there was something the matter with
her spine that could never he cured.
She went home and went to bed. never
to get up again, but lay on her back
for seven long years, suffering terrible
pain. At the end of seven years she,
died. ■•-,'.- . •
I have a little emerald ring of hers
that I wear every day. livery lime 1
look at it I think of seven Ion? sad
years that Mary suffered from an
April fool's Joke.
SHIRKS K. BILK,
419 North. Bright avenue. Whlttler.
AT grade, Bailey street school.
CAKE IS TAKEN
Dear Aunt Laurie: J^/.v
One April Fool's day when 1 was in
boarding school we girls decided to
give an April fool spread in our room
- that nlcht. Contrary to our usual run
torn, we were not going to have any
Jokes played.
The faculty were everywhere watch-
Ing that no jokes were played, and
every one was very peaceful except us.
We had all the food in our rooms ex
cept the cake, which we wanted to be
fresh. Therefore we had to get it In
while the teachers were watching.
How to do that we had not yet de
cided, until one said that we might
put a small rope out of the window
and fasten it on and haul it up just as
supper was being served.
We had just got it fastened, when
ill- girl that was holding It called
down that tin- teachers were coming
to every door, making the children
come to supper, so she had to run and
• leave it hanging. As it was dark, we
had no fear that any one would dis
turb it until we did.
After supper we went to the window
to get the cake, but imagine our sur
prise when no cake was there. We till
trooped down the hall quietly, but
were sent back.
We knew our cake was stolen, but
wo played a good joke on whoever
took it, for the girl that bought the
cake confessed to having told the bak
er to make it as salty as he could, and
we would not have been able to eat it.
Your niece,
MILDRED KKHiiISOX.
USED EMPTY EGG -
Dear Aunt Laurie: ■ '
On April Pool day we were eating
oranges when a thought came to mo
how to fool my aunt, whom I had been
trying to fool.
I cut a piece off the top of an orange
and scooped out the pulp with a spoon.
Then 1 filled it with orange peelings
and put the top on. Then I went next
door to my aunt, holding the orange
with the top down.
1 asked her if she wanted an orange
and she Bald "yes." I gave it to her
and she said, "Thank you; I am so
fond Of orange*, Then she saw too latn
that it was a Joke. T shouted: "April
fool! April fool) I've got you fooled
this tlmeV Then 1 gave her a good
orange. • — .-.'<
Next morning my uncle, WOO baa
been out the night before, asked my
aunt how the orange filled with rinds
got on the sideboard. He said: "I
picked it up and was going to eat It,
and found it wiw no good." Then my
aunt laughed and told him I gave II to
her ami -April ftoled her with It, ana
the had put it there to fool him. He
had not thought of its -being April
fool, or he would not have said any
thing about It. Both got April fooled
by an orange. Tour niece,
LELA CAMPBELL.
Ago l", Lankershlm.
PARROTS LEARN TRICK
i tear Aunt Laurie:
One day a party of people went to a
park to have a picnic. They had come
early, prepared to stay all day. it
whs a beautiful day, and the forenoon
they spent in looking at the flowers
-and animals and playing on the
lawns'.
At noon they were ready for lunch,
and after finding a cozy place with
trees and bushes all around they sat
down and ate heartily.
As they were clearing up all the
scraps and papers around they heard
a noise which sounded like some one
calling for help. They all ran to see
what was the matter, but all they
could see were the birds in their cages,
which were near to them. After they
had gone back they heard something
which sounded like 'April fool." They
all laughed at this and afterward
found out that it was the parrots. In
tho morning these birds had heard
some boys play the Joke and they took
it up, as they often do, words which
they hear. Your loving niece,
KATHEHINE MILLERD.
Long Beach (general delivery); Long
Heath high school grade 9Vi-
USED EMPT YEGG
Dear Aunt Laurie;
One time not long ago, when eggs
were scarce, April fool's day eama _
I thought I would play a trick on my
father, who likes eggs very much. I
bought a nice big white egg, I took It
home and blew the yelk out. I put it
In a box and wrapped the box up with
gilded paper, then tied It with a ribbon.
While letting the table for dinner
on April Fool's day l put the egg on
my father'! plate. When he sat down
he exclaimed: "Ha, ha! What have
I here?"
Not caring for ribbon or paper, but
anxious for the contents of the box. he
eagerly opened it. Ha wan surprised
and delighted when he saw the clean,
white egg lying there. He told me to
boil it for him, but I said It was al
ready boiled. I cracked it open for him
and dropped the empty shells on his
plate, i cried at the same time, "April
fool!" •
"You rascal!" he exclaimed. "I will
get mv own egg* after this." Your
niece. DOROTHY PAY.
Logan Height! school, grade A": ace
10 years. 1580 Logan avenue, lan Diego.
GIRL'S BIRTHDAY ON THE FIRST
Dear Aunt Laurie: .-' "j;-".j
The girls at school were talking
about birthdays.
"When is yours?" naked the girls of
Dorothy, who was near by.
"First of April," replied Dorothy. •
"Oh, you are an April fool!" Bald
Mane, who was one of the biggest
girls.
Lila, Blanche, Bella and most of the ,
other girls commenced to tease Doro
thy about being an April fool. Doro
thy felt very Had, it ml when she got
home she told her mother all about It.
"Never mind," said Dorothy's moth
er. "They will be April fools, after
all." So Dorothy's mother told Doro
thy the plan.
Now, It was a few more days before
April 1, so Dorothy and her mother In- .
Vlted ten girls and ten boys.
They got some ferns and flowers and
decorated the room where the party
was to be, held. Dorothy's brother
helped. to do the errands and Dorothy
herself helped to do the cooking.
I First of April came. Dorothy's eyes
beamed with delight. The party was
to lie at 2 o'clock p. in. and and at
.'> p. in.
Soon the children came. They, played
games. Then they went into the room
where tho table was set. There were
twenty-one chairs and plates. Marie
was the oldest, so .she was to cut the '
cake, which was four layers, with
(Continued on I'ugf Nrvrn)
All Juniors who will write to
Alice Warner, 729 Banana
street, Jacksonville, Fla., and
send her self-addressed and
stamped envelopes will re
ceive in return, free, some
seeds of the beautiful Royal
Ponciana. It is a magnificent
plant and has a large red
bloom. She thinks it will grow
for Herald Juniors in Southern
California and wants them to
write her and let her know
what success they have with
the plant. She is not in the
seed business —simply wants
Californians to have the flower.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-04-03/ed-1/seq-64/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AN EMPTY BOX FOOLS BOYS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
one April fools' day 1 w.-is up north
nnd all Of UN girls knew that the boys
were going "' do something.
That night we all gut re-idy and
went to tin- show, As we were coming
home the hoys flipped behind an
orange tree and just before we got
there they put a dummy out In the
path,
I was the fust one to see it and I
drew the other gills' attention to it.
They dared me to go and see what it
was. So I went. Bod JUSt as I was
going to look they pulled the string.
We didn't see it any more. Then they
;dl jumped out and said "April fool."
When we girls got home we made up
our minds to fool them, s ( , we found
a box and fixed it all up nice and went
out where they were playing. We put
it down there and some of the hoys
came and Mid; "Hay, fellows, we
[omul a box of candy or mush."
He started to !>iek it up and we
pulled the string and said "April fool."
Then we all went Immc,
ZELLA WADDELL.
Sawtelle school, sixth grade.
WOMAN PICKS UP PURSE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Jt was close to April fools' day. My
friend and I had 1 been trying to plan
a trick to play on somebody. We soon
decided to go down town and buy a
purse;
We took the purse and filled it with
big buttons and Knoll buttons until it
looked just like money fr >m the out
slde, Then my friend took the purse
and ran up the .street as fast as lie
could. While running be propped the
purse on the sidewalk. Then he ran
"BED TIME"
around the block and tame back and
met me.
We watched the purse for a little
while, when an old woman came down
tba street. She picked the purse up
and looked around. She did not see
anyone and Miked on very fast to the
next block. Here *he went in a hall
and opened the parse. She looked
eagerly ir.to it, but to her surprise she
saw the buttons. She dropped the
purse and walked sulkily away.
Your nephew',
GEORGU CARL CLARK.
1547 Valley avenue, San Diego, Lo
gan Heights school, age 1- years.
A WET JOKE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
When I was asked over to a hnuse
on April fool night they told me to so
in another room. When I wont in they
had two chairs and ■ cloth spread
across them. They told me to sit down.
I sat down on the cloth. Some one
was .sitting on each end of the cloth,
and when I sat down they jumped up.
This let me and the cloth go to the
door; at last I thought I was going
to Urn floor. 1 was looking: for a hard
tail, but on my way to the floor a tub
of water caught me. The water was
not hard, but it was wet.
I got my clothes all wet. T would
rather have hit the floor than the wa
ter, because the water was cold, and
it was cold outside and I had a long
ways to go. 1 did not sit on another
cloth any more. (April fool.)
RAY McCLURE
Sawtelle city school, grade 6.
WINS PRIZE FOR COLLECTION
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Once a man said, "Whoever gets,
tin' most postal cards of different
kinds will get a prize of $10 and can
ride in the races." Another boy and
I said, "Let's try to get it and buy us
a ride apiece."
My brother ■ was in China at the
time, and I took the stamps oft his
letters. : ; . .r ; ' .
When it was time we took them to:
the fair and got the second prize, which
was seven dollars and a half. My
father save me four dollars more, so
1 got a rifle and I have it yet.
HAYMOND OSTERMANN.
Sawtelle school, grade 6.
SON AFFECTS DISGUISE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
"Now Jack." said his mother, "you
can H<> and play, for this is April
fools' day. and you can play a trick
on 'daddy.' "
Jack ran away as fust as hll legs
would cany him. Hi- went to his
papa'a stori Is the market square. He
drened up as ■ tramp and went up to
the counter and asked if he could have
a drink ol' water, which was readily
given him.
He waited until dinner time and ato
with his father who, not knowing his
son, Kindly save him his dinner, Jack
put some salt in tin- coffee and did
a few other iricks at ulnner,
Ho next thought he would play a
trick on the hired man.
He Rot Into B sack and let the man
put him on the scales. He picked up a
board and hit him on the? head. The
man then looked and saw the sack
jumping after him. He was so fright
ened he ran and told Jack's father.
VVAI.TKIt W. TATLOR,
Bawtelle, grade 6.
BOY THINKS PIGEON IS CAUGHT
Dear Aunt Laurie:
One day last year 1 Woke up not
knowing that it was April fool. I had
a trap set lor pigeons. Papa had been
up a lons time and had gone out and
set the trap off. When I came out
from my room he laid:
"I think there are pigeons in the
trap." I looked out and the trap sure
was sot off. After breakfast 1 went
out Pap« came behind me. As soon
as I lifted the trap he said, "April
fool." 1 said to him:
"Is today April fool?"
He said, "Yes." I went over to a
friends house and we played "Duck
on the rock." Lots of times I took
two rocks. I took cement which I
got from a house that was being built.
He could not knock my duck off.
Finally lie came to see what was
the trouble.
"April fool." says T.
LEWIS EDWARDS.
S awtelle'Clty schools, grade 6.
BOYS ARE DISAPPOINTED IN A
BREAKFAST
Dear Aunt Laurie:
About ■ year ago last April fools'
flay v woman thought she would have
some fun with her boys. The boys got
up very late that morning. She never
got breakfast till late. When she got
breakfMt ready she called the boys,
and ;tft.T they had oaten other things
they came to the pancakes. First the
bora took them. Then they began to
eat. for they were very hungry. One
of the boys said they seemed raw, and
his mother said:
"Eat right on and you can see if they
are raw."
The boys said they didn't taste good,
and their mother laughed and said it
was an April fool on them, because
there was cotton inside of them. The
next April fools' day the boys fooled
their mother, but 1 never heard how.
But April is soon coming around again.
RUTH LARSON.
Sawtelle city school, sixth grade.
PLAYS JOKE ON AUNT
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Last April I went to my aunt's farm
to spend a fi>w days with her. April
fools' day was very close at hand
and I wanted to play a good trick on
my aunt. Every day I spent my time
thinking what would be a good trick
to play on her. When April fools' day
came I went into the house and told
her that one of her ponies was dying.
She did not remember that it was
April fools' day, so she left all of her
work and ran to see what was the
matter with her pony. After she got
theie I said "April fool."
When I said that she laughed at her
self.
When my uncle came home I told
him all about it, and he laughed at her,
too. She said that she wouldn't get
fooled again, and she would remember
that it was April fool's day.
GLADYS WATKRBUHY.
Sawtelle city school.
A TRICK FAILS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Once I wanted a wheel. My father
said he would get me one after a while.
When April Fool day came he told
me to go look in the shed. I thought
I had a wheel, sure. I went and
looked, but there was nothing. I came
back and told him there was nothing.
They all gave BM the laugh and said
"April fool.'
At dinner I got the sugnr bowl and
put salt in it, but it didn't work, be
iiiuse it was too coarse for sugar, so
1 was left fooled again.
RAYMOND OBTERMAN,
Sawtelle city school, grade 6.
IN SPITE OF TOMMY
Home study for Tommy had just be
gun and he found it hard to apply
himself to regular hours. At bedtime
on* evening hi.s father said. "Tommy,
I am not at all pleased with the re
port your mother gives me of your
conduit today."
"No, father, 1 lenowed you wouldn't
be, iind I told her so. Hut she went
right ahead an' made th' report. Jest
like a Woman, ain't it?"— Ladies' Horn*
Journal.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84025968/1892-01-07/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-03-27/ed-1/seq-75/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>POLICEMEN HAVE THEIR JOKE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Walter and Mark were two little
boys who had heard of the tricks
played on April fools' day.
The first trick was a very harmless
one. Mark, seeing a countryman buy
some oranges at a stand, went up to
him and said: "Did you drop some
money just now?"
" The man took out his purse, counted
his money, and (aid: "I miss no money.
Have you picked up any?"
"Oh, you April fool!" said Walter,
They now began to grow proud of
their success, and never once noticed
that a policeman with brass buttons
on his coat and a staff In his hand was
watching thorn closely. At this point
the policeman came up, and, seizing
both boys by the arm, said: "Come
with, me to the station."
"To the station?" they cried, In
great fear.
"Yes, to the station. You have been
breaking the law."
"We were only in fun," whimpered
Mark.
"I want to go home to my mother,"
whined Walter. *
Hut the policeman wanted to play
his April fool trick Just as much as
the boys had wanted to play theirs; SO
he took them to the station, to a man
he called "Judge," and told him what
the boys had been doing. '
Prisoners at the bar," cried the Judge,
"what have you to say?"
And then, seeing that they trembled,
and that the tears were In their eyes,
the good-natured Judge took two apples
out of his pocket and, giving one to
each boy, said:
"Here, you little jokers, your sen
tence Is that you . eat these apples.
Kirn home and tall your mammas how'
1 made April fools of you."
CLAUDIUS WILCHOH.
355 Wisteria drive. Itamona school,
grade A 6.
HORNED TOAD KEPT FOR PET
Dear Aunt Laurie:
on.> time I told my friend that had
staid all night with us to come and
look at the little chickens in the yard.
While she was In the house I got
out of doors and got to looking around
to Me what I could find to play a good
April fool trick. At last I came across
a horn toad. They are a kind of toad
"with little horns all over them, but
they can't hurt you. They are a little
smaller than a real toad.'
.While she was looking around to
find the chickens, I came and slipped
this toad down her sleeve.
She had on one of these morning
Japanese dresses.
Well, she began to scream and cry
out that Gladys had put something
down her neck and it felt like a
snake.
At last mamma asked her what was
the matter. and I went up and whis
pered to mamma and told her nil
about It. She said:
"Oh, Elsie, they have played a trick
on you." ,
I got a letter from her the other
day and she said she still had the
horn toad and it's got two babies. It
will be two years since we caught it
mi April Fool day, and she said she
never would forget It.
oudys TURNMirtE.
Sawtelle city school, grade 6, age 12.
CAT IS MISCHIEVOUS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
When I was 6 yean of rge I had a
beautiful white cat by the name, cf
Tabby. Tabby was not a mischievous
cat and it surprised me greatly when
he played me this trick.
On April 1 as I -was dressing for
school Tabby camo purring around mo.
But Instead of petting him I got angry
and hit him and he ran ay.
Soon after ns I was about to put on
my slippers I could not find one' of
them. I hunted all about as did mam
ma, but we couldn't find the n issi'ig
slipper. So I had i? stay home that
day. •
The next morning I nvoke with
something scratching on the bed. I
arose and looked and who should I see
out Tabby with the slipper fast be
tween his teeth. He had hud it all the
day before.
IUJTH GILDEA.
205 North Mathe'.vi street, agj 10.
I have been In 1.,-is Angeles but a
month and am not yet going to school.
WEDDING CAKE FULL OF SALT
Dear Aunt Laurie: "..'
Mrs. Simpson's brother-in-law was
going to be married to a young lady
by the name of Lizzie Plummer.
Mr. Simpson's brother was going to
be married on the evening of the first
of April. A lot of people were invited
to attend the wedding. . '
, Mrs. Simpson was a woman who al
ways liked to play tricks and jokes on
people, so on the morning of the first
Mrs. Simpson made a whole lot of plea
and cakes. < . y
.; She made one a large cake that, she 3
colored pink and white, but v she put
salt in it instead of sugar, and in one
of the pies she put pine wood shavings
instead of sliced apples. v- She was just "
as sober as one, could :be . when she"
passed the pie and j cake. - She could
LOS ANGELES SUNDAY HERALD—JUNIOR SECTION
hardly keep from laughing, but she
: did. Mamma took a piece of the cake
and papa took a piece of pie. and cake.
Mamma first took a bite of her piece
of cake and it taste,] rather salty, but
she thought she had got some of the
salt on it which she had by the side
of her plate. jgh I took another bite,
but it was so salty that she knew then
that It was an April fool joke. Mam
ma sail v\iien she looked up from her
plate everyone was laughing as hard
as they could. I think that was a
good April fool trick.
CHARLES PRITDBN.
Sawteile City schorl, grade 6. .--T,-
JAPANESE USE SNAKES FOR
FOOD
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Did you ever know thai Japs eat
rattlesnakes? Well, they do, I can
tell you, and they,work on Sundays..
There is only one Jap out of the five
that an- pruning our grapes that don't
eat rattlesnakes, and ho is a Catholic.
The Japs killed five rattlesnakes on
Sunday In our grape vineyard. Per
haps you would like to know how to
rook them. They invited Homer and
Bill and me out to the camp to eat
some. Homer and Bill tasted It. but I
didn't. This is how they cooked them.
Tiny skinned them, then they put them
on sticks to dry for two days. Then
they cut them In little pieces and
roasted them over the fire. They then
eat them. How would you like to taste
some? HAROLD BURROWS,
Etlwanda; Etiwanda school, grade
2; age 9 years.
I enjoyed your letter, Harold. I have
heard that the savages used to-use
snakes for food, but X certainly did
not know that more civilized people
did. I Should be glad to hear from
you In the writers' contest also.
BRIGHT DOG STAYS AT HOME
Dear Aunt Laurie:
. We had decided to send Ross (our
dog that we have bad for over four
years) into the country, for we have
lived In the country ever since we got
Ross, and he doesn't like it in town
nearly so well.
We thought It would be better for
him. Papa was out talking with a
Signs of Spring, Milton Bashan, Inglewood school, Inglewood
man one day, and lie spoke about send
ing Hor3 into the country. Ross was
with him and be heard what papa Bald.
Wo kept him chained, and we didn't
think he could got away, but the morn-
Ing Ross was to go papa went into the
bam and he couldn't see anything of
him. All that morning we waited for
him, but he didn't come back.
' The man who was to take Ross had
to go without him, but after it was too
late for him to go Ross came back.
So he didn't go after all. . Your niece,
LUCY LARCOM SPAULDING.
371 Claremont drive, Pasadena.
Washington school, fifth grade.
MOTHER DOES QUEER COOKING
Dear Aunt Laurie:
One April fool about one year ago
my mother was in the house baking.
My cousin ami I were out In the yard.
A plan came into her head. She said
to herself:
"I guess I will put some cotton In
the cookies."
So she put cotton in three of them.
We did not know anything about it.
Then "she asked us, if we wanted a
cookie. We said yes, and she - gave
us each one with cotton In it.
Just like me, I wanted to take a big
bite. -I got in the big bite a bunch of
cotton. 1 did not let my cousin know
about It. He had not come to his cot
ton yet. Hut when ho did come to if
he was so scared he I threw It down.
Mamma was right there to say "April
fool." j
After that. happened my cousin and
I were going around April fooling
everybody that rime along. -X.-S
-. Your nephew.
LOYNAL CHASE.
Logan school, grade A 5; 12 years
old; 4016 M street, San Diego. ■
CRIES "MICE," SCARES AUNT
Dear v Aunt Laurie:
The only April fool trick I remem
ber playing on any one I played on
my'aunt last year. As it was AH
Fools' day I asked my mother If I
could visit my aunt.
I knew my aunt was afraid of mice,
bo after waiting* a little while I told
her there was a mouse behind her.
You should have heard her scream.
She jumped on a chair. 1 said, "April
Fool."
She said she would get even with me.
I didn't think she could, but .she did
before the day was over.
RALPH CLAVELOT.
Sawtelle, Cal. Grade 6.
MOTHER PLAYS GOOD TRICK
Dear Aunt Laurie:
It was April 1. We were standing
behind a fence waiting for someone to
come by, for we had a string tied to
a purse with a piece of fake money
tin it.
Pretty soon a man came by and
•topped i' pick it up. We gave the
string a jerk and the string pulled the
puree through a hole in the fence. We
yelled "April fool" and the man
wont on.
Nobody would pick It up again, so
we decided to do something else. We
got an old hat and put a brick under
it. Pretty soon a man came by and
gave the hat a kick and hopped away
holding his foot in one hand. •
Our mother called us and said that
she had some candy for us. She gave
us a piece and we began to eat it.
Soon we spit it out and ran for the
faucet, for the candy had pepper in it.
Then mamma said:
■April fool."
1 guess the laugh was turned on us,
all right. After that we never ate any
more candy on April 1.
Your nephew,
ASHER HOPEWELL.
1053 Xl Molino street, Berendo street
school, grade 87.
BAKER READY FOR BOYS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
"Tomorrow Is April Fool's day," said
the baker. "I'll have to make some
cotton doughnuts and pepper pies for
the boys."
;;e set to work and made some
doughnut dough. Then he mixed cot
ton with it and made the doughnuts.
They ,were big, fat. fluffy ones, and
looked nice, but I do not know how
they tasted.
"Now," said he, "there are some
peppery mince pies to make." No
sooner said than he began to work.
He made the dough and then the.
mincemeat. He was sure he had dosed
it enough with redhot pepper, for he
had used two-thirds in the can. After
the pies were baked he set them in the
window to cool and went to bed.
The next morning he got up earlier
than the rooster and made some April
foo! cookies and cakes. At 9 o'clock
in the morning the boys came over to
the bakery to see what mischief they
could do there. The baker said he
would give them some pies and dough
nuts and cookies and cakes if they
would go away. The boys took them
and ran away under some trees to eat
them.
The boys came back soon, and the
baker cried. "April fool!"
Your nephew,
FRITZ CRAKJCR.
55.") Julian avenue, San Diego; Logan
Heights school, grade SA; age 10 yuars.
BOY ASKS FOR CANDY
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Once I thought I would play an
April fool trick. I got a boy. to give
me a piece of April fool candy. He
gave it to me In the presence of an
other boy. The boy asked for some
thing good and I gave him a big
bite. He began to sputter anS spit
ami cough and jump arond. The
candy was filled with pepper. He said
he did not like it much.
LESLIE CLARK.
Sawtelle City school. Grade 6.
HOME-MADE CANDY
Dear Aunt Laurie:
On April 1, three years ago, I planned
to play a trick on v, schoolmate of
mine. I was always up to some mis
chief and could never keep out of it.
At home, school or out visiting I was
always up to something. This day I
was over to see my schoolmate, and as
he knew nothing of April 1 1 had a
good chancf to have some fun. The
day before 1 had been very busy mak
ing April candy and putting red hot
pepper" in it. I asked him to try spine
of it, which, of course, he did, not
having the least Idea that he was
being tOOled.
The candy was so good that he put
It all in his mouth at once and Started
to eat it. I tried to keep from laugh
ing, but about in the middle Of it I
gave a loud giggle. My ichoolmata
now seeing the Joke and tatting the
candy that'once looked so good and
which he now fouml to have pepper
in it, took H out and threw it away.
He asked me what I was tooling him
for. and I told him it was April Fool's
nd thai he was the one who was
tooled. A very mean trick, was it not?
CLARENCE BHEPARD.
10 years. 498 Julian avenue, Ban Diego.
POLICEMAN INTERFERES
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Walter and Jim were two small boys,
who had heard of April fool tricks, so
thought they would also play some.
Their first trick was a harmless one.
A .string was attached to a ball and
the ball was pulled along on the side
walk, while Walter and Jim kept out
of sight ai a street corner,
A little fellow named Peter stopped
to pick up the ball, but every time lie
tried to touch it it would move away
from his grasp, and he did not know
what to make of it. At last he dis
covered the trick, and then the boys
cried "April fool,"
Their first trick was such a tine suc
cess I hat they decider! to play another
one. Seeing "a young lady crossing a
muddy street Walter said, "Pardon
me, madam, but just look at your
stocking."
The lady stopped short, looking down
at her ankles, then the boys, cried
"April fool."
The boys wire proud of their success
now and never once thought a jolly
policeman was watching them closely,
Seeing a man buying oranges at a
stall, Jim stopped him and said, "Did
you drop some money just now?" The
man counted his money and suid, "I
miss no money."
"April fool," cried Walter.
At this the policeman stepped up and
said. "Com* with me to the station."
"To the station." cried they in
fear.
"We were only in fun."
"YOU have been breaking the law,"
said the policeman, firmly.
"I want to go home to mother,"
whined Waller, but the policeman
wanted to play his trick as well as
the boys wanted to play theirs. He
.took them up to a man called "Judge"
and told him what the boys had been
doing.
"Prisoners," said the judge. "What
have you to say about this?" Then
seeing how they trembled and the
tears In their eyes, the good-natured
judge gave them each an apple and
said:
"Your sentence is that you eat these
apples, Now run home anil tell your
mammas how. after making fools of
others, you fell in the hands of the
police, who made fools of you."
1 PEARL MAY.
Sawtelle school. Crade J,
"THE CAT CAME BACK"
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Tom was a merry lad who played a
trick every time lie gut a chance,
It was April Fool's day, and Tom
was looking for a chance to play a
trick on somebody. At last he saw a
well dressed man go into a house
across the street.
"I will play a trick on him." thought
Tom, and taking a stout cord from his
pocket, he went across the street and
tied it from one fence to another, so
that it fill directly across the well
dressed man's doorway. He then let
fall the heavy iron knocker and scam
pered a little ways down the street.
Presently the man appeared in the
doorway, and looking down the street
saw Tom making faces at him.
"I'll fix you, you little scamp," said
the man. Hut belore he had taken two
steps he fell sprawling in the gutter.
The man went into the house, swear
ing to beat the band, and Tom scam
pered away.
Alter a while Tom came back with
a cat, and, first looking to see if any
body was near, went into the well
dressed man's yard, climbed up on the
porch and looked into the window.
He wished nothing better. The man
was fast asleep.
Tom raised the window as softly as
he could and put the cat in.
Pretty soon Tom heard an outburst
of swearing: then the window opened
and the cat came out head over heels.
Taking Tom for his enemy, the cat
(lew at him and scratched him on the
face.
Tom scrambled off of the porch M
quickly as he could and ran home, and
never played any more tricks. Your
nephew, JOHN WECKERLY.
Logan Heights school, grade A".; age
11 years. Thirty-third street and
Webster avenue, Ran Diego.
BYSTANDERS FEEL FOOLISH
Dear Aunt Laurie:
One afternoon of April the first, my
mother was out walking. She came to
a group of stores, in the doorway of
one of them a few men were lounging.
They had a untie on their face! and
were watching the pasuraby to see all
the fun which they might afford.
Walking In front of mamma and
engaged in conversation was an elder
ly lady and her son. They had not
noticed the men in the doorway, and
did not see the little object lying on
the sidewalk until they were almost
upon it, and they were evidently not
thinking Of April fools day, lor the
young man stooped to pick it up amid
the laughter from the crowd In the
(Cuutiuutfd no I'dge l-'utir)
3</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063758/1904-03-15/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FOR THE CHILDREN.
Some Nice Tricks Which Might be Played
On the Approaching "April Fool's
Day."
"But how do you fool them?*
asked .\argy.
She was a very little girl-not
six years old--and she looked up to
Edgar. who was twelve, as an ex
tremely wise person.
"You make 'em think things are
different from what they are," said
Edgar. "Only, of course, you d -n't
tell fibs. And when they find otb
they're tricked. you call "April
fool!: It's lots o' fun."
"It must be." said largy, eager
ly. "I mean to try it."
Edgar looked at his sister. Some
war. altho it was -lots o' fun" for
hinm. he did not like to think of
Margy teasing her friends. and
laughing at their disappointlent.
"Oh. you're too little." he said.
\iamma told me one wasn't ever
too 'ittle to help others," Margy
declared. Edgar wAs so puzzled by
this speecn. that he made no further
renark.
When the Wheaton family came
into the dining-room. on the first
of April, 'Mamma was saying: "I
am so tired of that baked apple
every morning, and I con't care
for oragnes any longer. I do wish,
either that it was time for berries,
or that Dr. Mason had not told me
to eat fruit for breakfast."
Margy danced along by her side,
listening and smiling to herself. As
Mrs. Wheaton caught sight of the
table she gave a cry of surprise.
There sat a plate of strawberries
beside her napkin.
"'April fool!" called Margy. "I
bought 'em myself. Mamma, down
to Mr. Snyder's. And you thought
you were going to have baked ap
ples again. April fool!"
The rest-her father and mother,
Jamie and Edgar-looked at each
other over the little girl's innocent
head. "That is a sweet wav-tc
trick one with something nice,"
said Mamma.
"Why, what other way would
there be?" asked Margy. "No
body would do mean things to peo
ple-not on any day in the year."
A merry voice called "April
fool!" after Papa, whose hat and
coat, all neatly brushed, lay upon
the hall-table. And the same cry
followed Edgar's usual search for
-his school books and his finding
them, strapped together. lying be
side his cap. A sprig of geranium
from largy's cherish plant was
pinned upon the lapel of Jamie's
overcoat, and "April fool!" he
heard. as he hurried into it.
Ellen. the second girl, weht out
to the butler's pantry a while later,
and discovered the silver from
breakfast rinsed and dried and laid
in its proper baskets. "April fool !
piped 31argy."
"What are you doing, child?"
inquired1 Miss Wilkinson. opening
her window to question the~ little
girl in the gar(den next (door. Mar
gy looked up brightly:
"'I'm going to April fool the
birds, she said. "with this plate of
crumbs. They don't expect a thling.
you know. They'll be so surpris
Miss Wilkinson gazed down into
the radiant little face:
"You're a good child." she said,
quickly. and shut down the sash.
Margy ran into the house and
told her mother how Miss Wilkin
son had April fooled her: "Because
she never said I was a good child
before."
WVhen the scrubwoman, wvho was
working next door, went home that
night. Miss WVilkinson astonished
.Maria by g'iving' her a basket of
cold pieces : "April fool !" said her
emprloyer. smiling in a grim way.
ani i\! aria smiled to:
yTan e kindiy ier oi'
me." saidl she.
Air. W\heaton had not beenwi
ing lon in his ofnice when an ac
quaimnance ecaei who~ wa:nted o'ne
ioilr forsomecharitabl Y ict
The face (1 his litt&. giri came up
before her father. Het hajm iekh
man nye dollars. and said. ".\ri!
fool'!" and then they both laughed.
Tamie wras one oi the older pu
p)il's in the high school. and a favor
ite and leader among the big hors.
M\Iiss Fo'nan, the timi d. nervous
Latin teacher, always dlreaded that
half-hour she had] to pass with mis
chievous Tamie Wheaton andi the
comrades lhe incited to whispering
and nonsense. Today. those on the
back benches in the Virgil class be
haved as well as the girls upon
whom she could depend. They be
haved so well. in fact. that she stop
ped them on their way out of the
room and thanked them for it.
Jamie looked up into her face witt
twinkling eves: *We April fooled
v-ou, didn'.t we ?" he asked.
Jack Watson. who had quarreled
with Edgar. had played a horrid
trick upon him yesterday. The two
sides of the room led the march
from it. on -alternate days. On the
thirty-first of March Jack had im
i proved the opportunity to drop a
decayed apple into Edgar's over
:oat pocket. Edgar was very an
gry. Today Jack had good reason
to look out for something in return.
To tell the truth. Edgar had actual
Iv brought in box. a dead mouse
tf:rom the trap at home. with the ful:
ntention of tucking it into Jack's
cket a.slhe passed the overcoat on
his war down-stairs.
Nobody would do mean things
to people. Margy had said. Jack
ad been mean to him. Yes: but his
'ittle sister thought him her wise.
good brother. above such revenge;
and spite. Her shining eyes. when
she called "April fool after him, I
as he found his books in the hall.
seemed to look down into h:s heart.
e could -iot deceive their trnst.
At noon he ran down-town.
When Jack, very cautiously and
icaring the worst. peered into his
pocket that night, a flush of shamed
surprise crept over his cheeks. He
saw a handful of chocolate-creams.
and a slip of paper that read "April
fool!"
I've had such a lovely day."
sighed Margy. sleepily, as herl
mother tucked her into bed that!
evening; "I've been busy every
moment-most And I've fooled
lots of folks. Wouldn't it be nice
if they came oftener-April Fool's
and dhristrias Day. I mean. They
se!-m a good deal alike, you know.
-The Independent.
Many husbands are so sentimen
tal that the want their wives to al
ways wear the dresses they had
wh'en they first knew them.
Elberta Peach Trees,
Barred Plymouth Rocks.
Red Raspberry Plants.
Eggs for hatching a specialty. All
inqniries promptly answered. Write
for Circulars.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-03-31/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TWO CENTS THE DAY BOOK TWO CENTS
MEETINGS TODAY, SUNDAY AND MONDAY
SATURDAY
Friendship Circle Y. P. S. L. April
Fool's party at 9th ward Socialist
hall, 8 p. m.
Machinery Molders' Union -No. 233
holds special meeting at 20i S. Hal
sted, at night
SUNDAY
West Side People's Forum, Robey
and Warren av., Jerome Hall Ray
mond speaks on "Russia and the
Overthrow of Autocracy," 7:45 p. m.
Francis Hanchett speaks on "The
Mission of Theosophy," at 116 S.
Michigan av., 3:30 p. m.
Chicago Salon meets at Masonic
Temple, hall 901, 3 p. m. W. F. Mc
Gee speaks on "Criticism of Father
Siedenberg's Opinions on Birth Con
trol." Universalist Church of Redeemer,
Robey and Warren av., Fred A.
Moore, minister, "Holy Week and
Holy Living," 10:45 a. m.
Society of Anthropology meets at
Masonic Temple, Corinthian hall,
2':30 'p. m. "War, What For?" and
"My Life in the European Trenches,"
by Daniel H. Wallace.
Northwest Side Public Speaking
club meets in Woman's clubroom,
West Park No. 1, 2:30 p. nu
Russian revolution celebration at
Schoenhofen's hall, Milwaukee and
Ashland avs., 2 p. m. Speakers in
several languages.
North Side Y. P. S. L. symposium
at Wicker Park halls, North av., Mil
waukee av. and Robey, 2 p. m. Ben
efit of party press and campaign.
Clarence S. Darrow lectures on
"The American Constitution" at
Garrick theater, 2:30 p. m.
"Crime and Criminals," by Chas.
E. Erbstein at Progressive Prepara
tory school, 8 p. m.
4th Ward Socialist Party meeting
at Healy school hall, 30th and Wal
lace, 2:30 p. m. Robt. H. Howe, can
didate for city treasurer, and K P.
Gugis, candidate for alderman,
Welles Park Woman's Choral so
ciety gives concert at Garfield Park
refectory. Mrs. F. J. Kingstey lec
tures on "Municipal Market"
Poale Zion Branch No. 6 (English)
meets at 1208 N. Hoyne av., 7:t0
p. m. M. Dolnick leads discussion on.
"Will Poale-Zionism Solve the Prob
lems of Jewish Workingmen?"
L. Marcy speaks at Union hJI,
1001 W. Madison, 8 p. m. Subject:
"Why We Have War."
Liberty Hall Players present Lady
Gregory's "Rising of the Moon" and
"Hyacinth Halvey" at Hull House
theater, 8:30 p. m. Admission, 25 cts.
MONDAY
Counter and pantry .night workers
of Thompson's, Weeghman's and
Messinger's meet at 115 W. Madison,
8 a. m.
o o
Berlin. German chemists dwoov
er method of making flour substitute
out of linden and beech buds. Call it
as nutritive as barley flour.
FREE VERSE
By Jim Manee
April Fool!
This isn't free verse at all. It cost
you two cents.
P. S. True, tomorrow is ApHf
Fool's day, but we don't publish on'
Sunday, so I had to spring this today.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045499/1938-05-14/ed-1/seq-14/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=APRIL+FOOL&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=april+fool&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
