<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"Life in a Mining company in Montana, All Fools' Day at Canyon Ferry"
At iho Canyon Ferry House). Iiepb by.
our old friend Cnnt. StalTord. is wont lo
meet occasionally tho Jolly bnrhelors of
mo Hujaeeni mines, wuu sot nroumi lltu
bnr.qunfl' their bovorog'cs nnil bewail lliclr
sad and lonoly lives of bachelorhood.
On Saturday evening, April 1st, whllo a
party of thoso dUcousnlato chap wero
engaged In Iho pastime mentioned. above,
a spanking team was drivHti. to tho par
lor door, by I. il. Tyler, ami by his side
sat n blooming and buxom lemule, who
wns politely, handed out of thu vehicle
nnd shown to tho parlor. A buz of nil
miration went up from tho crowd, nml
Mn Tyler wns interviewed ns to tho pn
ternlty and prdlgreo of tho lovely strnn
gor. These Inquiries wero snttuflcd by
thu stntntm nt that Mr. Stafford bail dls-
chnruetl his ittnlo cook, anu tho truly was
nn interesting widow, who lintl consen
ted to superintend tho cuisine affairs of
the household. Tho crowd otilotl v dron
ped olf their cabins, donned their "bllr-d."
shirts, shaved cl nu, nml dropped back
to the hotel, ono after nitothar, each ono
with it pnliiifntlng heart, nnd n quiet
chuckle to lil'tisell that ha- was looking
supremely smooth, and would recelrc
tho first introduction nnd smiles of the
widow. As they entered, Mr. Tyler
led their, one by one nnd presented them
to their fancied Idol, until the room wns
crowded with rivals, Captain Stafford,
wllh his eye on Iho knot-holo, tinted tho
happy countenances of tho baeholors,
nnd Iho witching smiles of tho widow,
whllo Tyler did tho nmlnblc. Tho
Judge of thu district, n happy, Jolly
bachelor, but, unfortunately, very thin
haired, borrowed n wig for tlio occnlon,
nnd appeared befose thv widow, with
his ours pinned back, nnd looking upon
tho minors with tho lofty contempt
which he felt bis position would give
him over bis rivals lo tho lair willow's
eyes. Tho guests having been all Intro
duced, Joo Stnirer, finally summoned
courngo to tako a sent by her sldo nml
engaged her in conversation ; but what
was his horror upon discovering tho
fair female gently raised her whlto skirts
nml shovo her hand Into tho pocket of n
greasy pair of buckskin brcechos, which
wero hidden by flowing garments, and
from which she hauled n plug of tobac
co, and pasFcd It to her admirer with a
winning smile, nnd tho polite invitation
of "Juo tuko n chaw '" Joo fell bnek iu
amazement, nml exclaimed, "Buys, if
this y'ar isn't Jim Fulsom iu pottlconts,
I'm a cnyuso." The April fool sell wns
then seen through, and Tyler had to
bent n hasty retreat, whllo thu supposed
widow niHilo her exit through tho bnek
door nnil hroko for tlic bush lo cscnpo
the wrnth of thu crowd. Tho Jtttlgo
now hicks only thirteen hnlrs of being
halt! headed, owing to the wrathful man
ner iu which hn ran his lingers through
bis thin locks, when ho learned that the
lovely widow was none olhor than Jim
Fulsnm, a smooth-faced miner, rigged
out for tho occasion. Helena Gazette.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>April Fool.
The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
aod as impossible to determine as the birth?
day of the first fool who marred Nature's
original design of intellectual Man. We
trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
its birth ba files research. We are forced to
admit its existence, without being able to
assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer?
tainly carried its memory in all their con?
quests. Its observance was long cherished
among numer?os nations. Abandoned to
the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
refinement, Momus seems to revenge him?
self by selecting the most elevated and dig?
nified objects for bis practical jokes. Nor
man, cor nation, nor things visible, nor
things invisible can elude bis satire. Nature
herself seems convulsed with his sly sport.
Her groans over a fallen race turn into in?
voluntary, hysterical laughter at the bidding
of this giant Harlequin, on whose kingdom
tbe Ban never sets.
The most pathetic scenes provoke the
wildest mirth. We see men of bonor and
repaie taking advantage of National schemes
to secare private emolument; dividends the
only consideration, the divisor of no conse?
quence. April Fool 1 Divisor of scheme,
plus dividends, laughing at his dupes, and,
thanking Heaven he is not like other men,
proving bis integrity by tbe faith of his
fr ?en dB. April Fool !
The rightful Government of Louisiana
using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti?
ling Kellogg platform ; striking the first
blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
sending representatives to the Union at
large, convinced that her distress must be
of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
balance cac not be determined; giving a
gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of j
bowling it down. April Fool !
England's tories and whigs doing their
best to destroy the ablest minister of the
Crown on the question of the Irish Univer?
sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
"cummin" while neglecting the weightier j
matters of tbe law. April Fool !
France with Thiers more iban king, shoot?
ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la R?publique 1
"A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
April Fool !
Ukraine peasants revolting against an
?utocrat who owns half the Continent of
Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
br the mere chance of being discharged at
heir masters' heads. April Fool !
Each nation convinced that "the Par lia
"mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
:ree. April Fool 1
Each sect persuaded that the whole world
viii soon have bat one Faith, and that Faith
ta own especial creed. April Fool 1
Honor, probity, patriotism, troth and
rirtae sb/J! prove'a successful candidate
tgaiost rampaot Vice. April Fool I
All the world surging, restless, doped and
laping, cries: April Fooll
Deep calling onto deep in awfal sport-all
.be waves and waterspouts shoaling in
nocking derision : April Fool I And men in
childish rage and impotent wrath yell to
?ach other and the Universe at large: Toa
ire-April Fool 1</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ON ALL FOOL'S BAT
i
Brainy Men Ten of First of April
Fancies.
Actor, Artist, BatlrUt, Lawyer, Preacher.
Etc, All Have Something to bar
About This, the Fool
Catcher's Day.
COPTBIOHi; 183 L
H E stage is in
Eomo measure
responsible for
All Fool's day.
So the histo.
rians tell us.
They say it
grew out of an
old Easter
miracle play in
Irhich the sending of Christ from An
bas to Caiaphas and from Pilot to
Herod was the basis of the mediaeval
Jramatist's plot. But I don't think
Hie stage has stuck to its offspring.
We actors are a serious lot of people,
particularly the comedians among us,
for paradoxical as it may seem, acting
Is all work and no play, and conse
quently Jack is a dull boy. We would
"MSTEIt, TXEASE GIVE ME A IIFT. JTLI.
TOU?"
T like to April fool our manager, perhaps,
but we don't April fool ourse'ves, be
cause that would be rather cruel.
I have outgrown the frolicsomenes
of April 1, of course; still I always look
carefully after my coat tails on that
day. And I greatly enjoy the motley
of those who are careless about their
parraental caudals during the Feast of
All Fools. The sight makes me feel
quite a boy again, for we youngsters
used to do that sort of thing in Phila
delphia thirty years ago. 0 yes, I did
It, too. I believe that some of the live
lier children of Philadelphia do it yet,
and have vitality and energy enough
left to laugh at the result, as a comio
paragrapher would say.
The most foolhardy of all the tricks
which I can recall in connection with
this carnival of jeering and nonsense
Is one that I have never seen played
Eince I was old enough to require two
digits to express my age. A bag and
two boys were the ingredients of the
trick, and it never failed to 6core a
great success on a quiet side street.
One boy got into the bag and the other
Stood by it waiting for the victim. The
rest of the boys who were "in on the
ground floor" were hiding in hallways
and doors and behind trucks across
the street. An innocent citizen came
W sauntering along. The boy who had
hold of the neck of the bag stopped
him with a "Say, mister, please give
toe a lift, will yer?" The innocent cit
izen usually acquiesced and took hold
of the bag to land it on the youngster's
shoulder. Just as he got it fairly in
his hands the boy in the bag suddenly
kicked and screamed. Innocent vic
tim, thinking it a bagful of wildcats
or hypnas. let go quickly and ran off
with palpitating heart and hair on end.
while all the boys across the street
pursued him with a villainous chorus
of "April fool 1 April fool! Wash
.your face and go to sclioU" or
something to the same effect. It
Talways seemed to me that the joke
was really on the boy in the bag;
he was sometimes dropped hastily
and heavily and was hurtand occa
sionally the April-fooled citizen gave
him a thrashing besides for being too
funny. But it was an effective trick.
and often an old codger lingered in the
shadow on the opposite pavement to
witness and enjoy the sport. You have
seen a man try to kick a plug hat full
of pig iron over into tho next state
Trell, bis discomfiture was no greater
IT MADE AIM SMD.E.
Good Ola reliOK Ali, hoT it warms ri7
bcart to see them playing their littlo inuoccm
tricks on the Brst or Apnlt Used to do It my
self when I was a toy. But ibey caa't fool me,
though I'm too oU a bird lor fiat.
than that of the man whoso blood was
frozen in his heart by the unexpected
scream emitted by the occupant of the
bag. Laugh? It would make a tomb
stone roll over in a fit of hysterics.
Jonx Drew.
fOMETIlIES IT GIVES PLEASURE TO OTHERS.
It doesn't seem right that the firs
flay of a month so full of pretty things
j is April is should be inseparably con
w nectcd in our minds with empty ard
dilapidated pocketbooks with string
in d-small-boy attachments, di&rep
ntable hats with bricks underneath
them, long streamers hanging from
l nnsuspecting coattails, door bells
rung by invisible hands, and all the
other dear old pleasantries that we
know by heart. And we should prob.
ibly have had a society for the pre
rention of Anril fool iokes Ions aso if
It were not for the pleasure that call
aren gel out of them.
When a certain boy of my acquaint-
fcnee on April Grst. before breakfast,
Informs me that somebody is waiting
ft;' see me in the library, not for the
world would I refuse to go downstairs
and pretend extreme surprise at find
ing nobody there. Nor would any
thing induce me to decline the suspicious-looking,
cotton-filled piece of
candy which is shortly after offered
--. . V.T. a fmnll rrirl I know. I bitA
UlUiD .- O "-
.-& End- Hotter SS6? itLISSrularly i
every year, ana Mr. rfat Gooxnvm or
Mr. Francis Wilson would be glad if
he could raise such a shout of laughter
as easily and unfailingly.
Apropos of this train of thought
there is a little picture of mine in Puck,
published some years since, which will
perhaps bear transplanting here, and
which I subjoin.
Fbedeiuck Buitn Oppeb.
"de bazoo" is suggested.
If yer want a good joke on some ot
yer frcn's, give dem de razoo, see?
Dat's de way dey do in Xew York oa
April Fool day.
Yer work it dis way:
Suppose a man owes yer ten dollars
and won't pay yen Go see him and
ask him for it. He ses he ain't got it.
Wipe de floor wid 'him and take all de
cash in his pockets and when he kicks
apologize and se.y yer didn't mean fer
ter hurt him it'b April Tool, see? Den
yer needn't pive him de money back,
'cause he owe s it, yer see? Course yer
don't want ter try de razoo on anyone
not under yer size, see?
Den yer kin pay off all yer old
grudges de same way. Or if yer hun-
gry and ain't got no money walk inter
de restrint, see, and eat all yer kin,
and say it's April Fool, see, and run
out widout payin' nothin'.
Dat's de racket fer April Fool de
razoo. Steve Erodie.
TO LESSEN THE DEVTL'S FOOLS.
I am abked for a sentiment concern
ing April Fool's day and pause in the
whirl and rush of a righteous warfare
to say that in my opinion time is far
too valuable and important a factor
for a moment to be lost in foolish jest
ing or senseless joking. The world,
especially in these days, is in far too
critical and dangerous a position, so
cially and religiously, to allow of a
man with average sense to saj' noth
ing of those who have consecrated
brains to indulge in any other than
profitable and upright intercourse.
It is a personal relief to me to feel
that in our ranks seventeen hundred
officers and sixteen thousand unpaid
local workers will be pushing with
might and main of soul an enterprise
which upholds sincerity and the ne
cessity of lessening the devil's fools.
Ballington Booth.
A CHA3IPI0X FOR THE DAT.
Before stating what jokes seem to
me timely, and enjc&abJe ior this
S&-
" WIPE DE FLOOB WID niil."
April Fool's day, I cannot resist th
temptation to say that I think the
spirit of the holiday itself hat always
been singularly misunderstocd. The
day is really to be deemed a pause in
time's serious flight, when folly could
with propriety travesty wisdom, and
set the world smiling. As it is, the
first of April has come to be deemed a
nuisance, wheu its observance is not
don away with entirely. April Fool's
day is sadly in need of soue one to
champion it and xestoi e it to its right
ful place in the calendar. It is not
simply the day on which the boys and
girls may make fools of their elders
with impunity. I suspect that there
was a time when it was regarded
rightly, far away as that time seems
to us now. Then the old people put
aside their serious looks and grew
younger instead of older.
If it takes a wise man to be a fool,
surely April first is the feast day
of the saircs. when thev can act on
Shakcspsare's admonition: "Mingle a
little folly with your wisdom."
As for those jokes which seem to mi
good and appropriate to the dav it
should always be understood that the
element of surprise is the essential
thing. Novelty is wit. Jokes must not
bo cruel pranks, otherwise the day
would ba given up to a general hazing
of everybody. The most successful of
April Fool jokes would be to surprise
one's friends by a change of character.
What a rare joke it would be for the
confirmed miser to bestow a dowry
upon that niece of his who needs only
a little money to marry the lad of her
choice. If all the cranks would put
rside their hobbies for a day, what fun
it would be for the rest of us.
This kind of joke can be carried out
ad finitum and would never fail to bo
successful. Let the tippler remain
sober to-day just as a joke. The skin
flint employer can have a lark with
his clerk by granting that increase of
salary that has been talked about so
long. Let the clergyman I say it
reverently preach a sermon only an
hour long to-day instead of one of
four hours' duration. I am convinced
that the idea would meet with success.
People too old for jokes on April
Fool's day? Xouscnc. Even the gray
heads can have their joke. The repro
bate roue can go to church this morn
ing and explain that it is all a joke on
his part. Many a man is ashamed to do
a good thing because it is so unusual
with him that it would give him un
pleasant prominence. But he can do
it to-day and escape with the admis
sion that it is his April fool joke. I
am glad the day comes on Sunday this
year. B. Gillax.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024442/1896-03-29/ed-1/seq-17/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>One Would e-neso frnm llilc
description that they were taw-fiMi, that
Is, wise-saw fish, hut they were not. They
were eimpij- hucKeru; yec mey knew It
was April 1'ool'b Day.
On tljat Fame
day a man went
Fooling the Fishes-Bait 3SSa J "J
Without Hooks. sot him down on
the wharf and let
downhisliiicand
bait. The water
was clear and he
could ee the
6uckers blinking
and winking at
each other and
rubbing their
nuouts, against
tlie tempting
bait.
"HeiliinkKhe's
run up against
the highland
suckcr."mid fin
ny No. 1 to. scaly
No. -, and noo
dle No. :t i early
swallowed the
bait at short
range laughing
at the sucker at
the o'lier nil of
the'ne. But he
fWifdrifJitalong
till the fun grew
hot.imd (hen he
Tilled his pipe
and hauled up
his line.
Nov.h-'reisa
moral 'nthisMo
ry. Th'-re was
no jojK in the
merry li'-l.er-m
a n ' s b a i r,
wlui h goes to
show that peo
ple who .ue too
wise to "Lite"
very often get
left. e en as the
fish didn't know
a good Uiing
when it was in
dubitably i n
their line.
And on that
same day in the
same generation,
a spinster lady
declined to ojX'ii
a letter, good
forthisdayonlv,
no rain checks. Is
sued, which letter
con tninoda bona
fide healed pro
IKaltj,.Uheand MieMioukl tarry
togetlier at Jeri
cho, or an j place
elM- where there
was good tarry
ing, swooning
and crooning in
the thick after
noon iK-rfiimeof
lot uracil orange
blos.-om. And
the next da j the
died.
Oil the 1st of
April, la-t, a
joung wieacre,
who lives on
New Ilauipclure
aieuuc. received
a letter ,y f.pe.
cial im-sMMiger.
It wab fcuper
bcribedina plain
round hand, and
in the left-hand
corner were the
words "Pmate;
marked down to
10, former val
ue &o." The
letter was re
turned to the
writer, with the
remark on the
margin. "Don't
need any spring
clothes." The
lot terrnerel j con
tained a part
Iiaynient of $20
on a $30 -debt
or honor" which
accrued from
lost borrowed
chips
So when the
bride of only
two Aprils tcle
Kraphed to her
husband In New
i'ork from
"Washington the
thrilling mc-s-fiage.
"Two ana
all's well," lie re
ceived it, "Two
and all swell."
He replied 'Had
eight. -a j self and
feel much swcll
er." She ws a
little -mrpi-ised,
to be sure, and
whei icy grow
up she will tell
the twins about
the mind reading
capaeu y cf a
handsome clerk
of the Oimis Of
fice. These hlMorl
calcaes are not
ed by way of pre
lude to i he slate
ment rhat April
Fools' Day Is
again with us, or
will be on "Wed
nesday next. Af
ter these i-ad ex
amples of mind
read mg, it will
be only t tie more
perplexing to
discover the dif
ference between
looking the gift
horse !u the
mouth and the
gift horse him
self should lie
gallop up to the
door.
One half of the
world will begin
on "Wednesday to,
play pranks on
Uie other half,
and it is an in
teresting day be
cause we have
only two such
days on Uie cal
endar, the other
being Talentine
Day. Election
day Miotild. per
haps, be added,
buttoallofthem
FaUier A braham
undoubtedly re
ferred when he
got off the fa
mous bit or phi
losophy, "You
can fool all of
the people tome
of Uie time, etc.,
etc. otr. ."
The misfortunes of the day are hke the
premonlUons of fctieezeg. STou know they
are coming, but you can't prevent their
arrival, so It is much better to Miecze
at once, even If your mouth Is full of
turtle soup, than to fight against the in
evitable. It Is better even to take in
the bundle on Uie doorstep than to kick
Ef 55
Vtr
JEm)
Some Old and New Jokes Suggested
The Times for Next Wednesday.
Of Course the Small Boys' WeMried and Proven Schemes Wil
Hold Sway, hut There Is a Chance to Extend Them
into Municipal and National Life
TH SUMS
uoke
by
v d y
f art" and 'Teller." havinsr done -which ha
strode oat of the room. leaviojr the second
fiddle- to play out the score.
It will probably be a bad d7 for king
makers, ho wevcrgooditniay be rorpotitical
fctol makers. In a quiet, coay room In a
Philadelphia hotel there are gathered
together the elect of the Warwlcka
of this day and generation, fore
most among whom are Piatt, Quay and
C I ar krer .
"V.
fffj VfLLET vairR
STRlFHi iu v
rti r SL. . x pA.
.,mn jr.r.
iA the o rryki ittL -T Ak
Some Ancient and Honorable April Fool Jokes.
Uie little stranger Into the street. There
may be millions awaiting the long-lost
heir before jou die.
The compliments of the season are firstly
due to Uie three destinies of "Washington.
Messrs. Koss, Truesdell and Poweil. Tliej
will do a land-office business on April
Fools' I)a . They will be bitting at a Uel
shazzar's feast, and lo' there appears on
Uie wall a strange bcroll in the Kalorama
dialect.
The Attorney for the District and the
interpreter of the clastic law of the local
Medcs and Persians Is called in and he is
promised fine raiment and an amethystine
ring ir he expounds the letters of fire on the
wall. Kefer.'ncc to Uie snap shot of the oc
casion will be found in the margin or tins
page. Of course, tins maj not happen, but
it ought to, which isa much better considera
tion. There is one place in the United States
where eerj thing can happen, proidcd
always it is not something practical even
will enforce the rules and order the gal
leries to be cleared.
Mr. Morrill of Maine Mr. President, I
have lieen llfty jcars in the Senate in the
ambassadorial capacity of a Senator from
Maine, atrl I have ncer jet heard
The Toreign Voice I am a talker my-f-clf.
(Renewed applause from Uie gal
leries.) The President The sergeant-ai-arms will
arrest that obnoxious peiaonage.
The galleries are cleared, and the ser-
whlch to exclude the April Foots Day dis
turbers of the White House peace.
In the mind's ee, without even a warm
application of the Roentgen ray, it is easy
to see the fighters against follv seated at
the table in what the President told the
delegation of Baptist ministers was his
"workshop." Ip a certain sense, tin-, is
true, because It is there lie saws wood. The
President casts aside carefully all tlie
suspected letters and puts all the packagi-v
Iu a tub of water near him on the floor
to kill the microbes and anymcidental dyna
mite. The morning is passed away pleas
antly, and he asks for a cigar.
"What kind, extellenzaZ" queries F. A.
H '!'.. in one-third Spau'sn and two-thirtls
Iiayard.
"A Duke of Veragua," replies excellenza.
and Fie-Tt!oi!sard-DolIars-a-Year in the
future opens a new Ijok. The rest of this
story is done in black and white pictonally
on this Seventeenth Page. In scene the sec
ond the unfortunate bot-opener la on his
tr
, )
iiiiinwifi ll'ir i5j
4m
April 1 at the District Building:.
A Neat Little April Eiiect in the Senate.
a Joke. To guess the name of that place
is not as hard as guessing the number of
five black beans in a transparent jar. It
is the United States Senate,
In the afternoon of "Wednesday next,
after the morning hour, the Cutian olla
podrida will be in full blast. Senator
Lodge will hae spoken on the letter that
never came to Secretary Olney, Senator
Mills will hae taken Cuba "vi et aimls,"
and Senator Hale will have delivered his
accustomed eulogy on the late Don Canovas
de Quixote. The listening Senate ib suddenly
startled by a thin foreign voice, which
says, "I'm something of a talker mjself."
Applause breaks out in the galleries.
The President of the benatc-If these
demonstrations are repeated the President
vtw n
A Joke on the Republican RiBg-sters
geantr.it-arms and Firsts Assistant Stewart
rush up into the peanut' reservation. They
return and report that the miscreant has
escaped.
The Presldent-The Senate "will be In
order.
Mr. Chandler As I was saying, Mr.
President, I
The Torclgn Voice I am something of a
talker mjself.
Nothing could exceed -the commoUon in
the Senate when its courtesy was thus sat
upon and spat upon by this intruder. It
was the eagle eje of Senator Sherman
of "Our Foreign Relations" Committee
that discovered the intruder, winch was
quietly looking askance at the President
out of its white-winged eye, a beautiful
queen red and gold parrot direct from Bar
celona. "It Is a Spanish spy," declared Mr.
Lodge.
"It should be shot at drum head," as
severated the fiery Tennessean.
"Try it from the clock," said Mr. Mills.
"Willi the Presidential gun," added Mr.
Hill of New 1'ork. i
Suggestions, however, do not kill birds
at long range, and. the pages were on the
qui vive of excitement lo be let loose on
the most consistent talker at that moment
In the Senate. They were eager for the
bird to fly down and light on tlie bald head
of some Senator, like the eaglathat alighted
on the head of the husband of Tanaquii.
But the spy did not move, keeping his
sinister eye on the Vice President, and
evidently getting ready to sing his unwel
come song again.
Mr. Lodge Eutcka, lMr. President: Per
scalam ad avem.
The President Gqod; has the scrgeant-at-arms
a ladder about him?
The sergeant-at-arms at -once procured
Uie ladder on which he climbed into office,
placed it up against the lintels of the' east
door, and reached for ithe parrot, which
was seated on the Senatorial clock a la
Poc's raven.
Did the sergeant-at-arms land the bird?
Not on your negative. The bird had a
string tied to him and. he'-was hauled aver
the parapet, and tle small boy at the oUicr,
end of the string simply hauled In the fes-'
the Spaniard, opened a -gallery door and
went down stairiand .filled himself full of
apple pic.
This may not happen.but It ought to. A
son of one or the surviiors of the Ford's
Theater disaster would be tlie logical perpe
trator of this lecfure by the pariot to the
Senate.
Too mucU .sympathy cannot be -wasted be
tween now and "Wcdnesdaj'onthefeeilngs of
the Chief Magistrate "with respect to his
mail and exprc packages on the day -we
celebrate. Thcrofhavc plrendj' been con
ferences between him anci Fldus Achates
Henrlcus Tiberius on taii; beet manner in. I
rjtt&n.
knees ascrvatmg in shattered sentences to
the accusation or the Potentate of the Poto
mac that he smelt treason in the tainted
gale.
"if third term doesn't go, lese mnjeste
doe-." thunders the man of destiny.
"1 know it doe?, Your Majesty, but by
the saber of my father I knov not who is
the nuereant, unless it be some godless
member of the 1. W. X. M. of the Occi
dental provinces."
"And who are they, caitiff?"
l-eonie who Need Missionaries, Ex
cellcnza." "Then, bj- mj- halidom, they shall have
Uiem galore before the ides or April."
And with that His Mijestj-seized bis tab
lets and wrote deep in the wax"'Colorado."
"North Dakota," "Oklahoma," "Stew-
til
r
Somebody's Little Joke en Groyer.
Little Willie's OrieinaJ
Idea.
U (!L
''r
T'&ryS "U
misfortune "vr K7 ""7 JaB
trying to ! J "M
doiitwheth- X Nr"V 1 H
there's a V A V l
-"vvr-' . "rv.-oB
A-N1
sV: ,', V-
J
f
.r
They are not
afraid of any
sword of Da
mocles.orknlfc up the sleeve
of Crofcer. or
any other gift
of the Greeks.
But they didn't
reckon on tie
.'deus ex ma
chiua" of a
Philadelphia
hotel.
With a rattle
of tfti plates
and a creaking
of woolen cord
a g e, down
comes Mr. Mc-Kinlej-.
stuffed
full of the
"looks that
way," and the
reast and fun
go out with the
lights and
that Is noioke.
The tevsons
of April Fool's
Day are many
and valuablelf
studied practl-callj-.
A man
stiouM not let
his hcue burn
down becaus",
wiseinhisown
conceit, I s
neighbor telLs
him that r.ts
house is on fre.
At the farce
tirnr, if all tl e
night caps and
nightdresses in
Paradise allej
are sprinkled
from the hose
of the small
boy on the roof
who has been
paid to sLai.t
"fire," It enly
goes to show
that there is a
certain degree
of
in
fin i
lire in your
own house by
looking out of L.
the window.
The place to ; r.
look is in the . ir3-'
bamcnt, or
any other In-sidepreclnct-Again
the
nan who pas
s wisely bj- a
silver dollar on
the pavement
feels had when
he looks back J JCTI-i' J
and sees that r
another man 4 t
has parted it up
safely. If it's a -
iweketbook the
eae is all t'ic
sadder. Or. If
the man w.'.o
believes that ic
is better t fa'ce
in the baby off
the d. orst p,
takes itardtelL,
hKi wife al.ut
it, maj- r pcu
the bundle to
find in itc ncof
ouroldfriTiis,
the rag labj.
So, agam. the
bnckinthehat
Is inevitable,
but it Is no use
to go home in
that condition.
It. of coarse,
requires a good
deal of forti
tude and saw
teeth to eat a
cotton batting
dumpling, or to
chew, with a
scriptural face
even a small
piece of candy
with a j-anvin-side,
but it is
said that It ha3
been done rath
er than ac
knowledge the
joke, but in "r ' !
nearlv all nf : !""
Uie instances
Uie patients
died as mar
tyrs, like the
Who let: the Z. .! T
foc eat. nut of ' 'wil '
his breadbas
ket rather thnn
be indicted for I f
dealing the
fox. I I
If you find
It yarn or cot
ton, spit n c ut i ?sgss3 &
- iiiuii. i is ' vt -5;,
Reach for all I t?it'i SS
the nunev in
sight, ric up
all the pot'et
books, open all
jour icttcrs,
receive all the
visitors in or
out of myster
ious lirdles,
foronth.s par
ticular da it's
the only way
to i o e t h.e
problemsof the
other fool. It
Is somewhat
strange that a
person wl o be
lies esat it is
theucexrcctcd
that always
happens.scoms
to look behind
him when a
small boj- jay
to him confi
dentially: "Mis
ter, jour lorse
hasdroppedhis
tail." it is
human nature
to look back
when he has
turned the cor
ner. There have
beenverymnny
8age tomes
written about
the origin and n HfTTT f
uses of April ,h; rrh7-
Fool's Day.
Som writers
ascribe to it a
Roman, and
others a Greek
origin, it is
more than likely that It began on the day
when Esau tried to pas himself off for
Isaac with their bliud parent. Abraham.
Atu.ia.tia, i.onutr, dtetovrtl tUat the
kLii.iI okC-r lad hair en hi brain and.
tho t o-n. of Esau was launched for all
the rget. They have had hairs on their
brains cer since.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>APRIL CALLED
OUT ALL ITS
ARMY OF FOOLS
The Jester and Victim
Alike Make Merry.
THE MORGUE'S BUSY DAY
McENERNEY AND HIS COUN
TERFEIT PRESENTMENT.
Sad Tale of the Dentist Apprentice
and the Soubrette Who Could
Not Find the Key to the
Curtain.
April dawned bright and beaming and
kept merry throughout its. first day
blithely warbling between laughs, "Al!
fools look alike to me."
In spite of the fin de siecle pessimist
and his prophecy that All Fool's day was
a landmark of the past, the jester was
out In splendid form and landed gudgeons
galore.
The fun began early and lasted late.
A very few new jokes were perpetrated
and all the old ones revived, while the
usual good humor of both jester and vic
tim prevailed during the entire day. The
email boy was not so much in evidence
;is in previous years. Thoughts of Easter
eggs on the morrow, coupled with the ar
duous duties of trying on new suits and
boots and hats, drove for once all
thoughts of mischief from the mind of
the budding lords of creation. The offi
cials at the Morgue were the first to fall
victims to the merriment- of the day.
When the day was but a half hour old
—at 12:30 a. m.— a telephone call, pre
sumably coming from the Receiving Hos
pital, summoned a Deputy Coroner to take
charge of a body at the Hobson House.
"Hurry-up wagon" and Deputy went
quickly to the place, only to find that
April had dawned and that some one un
known wa? taking liberties with dignified
city officials.
In fact, the Morgue, or. rather, the
Morgue's telephone, was the greatest fcuf
: fen-r during the day. The bell rang un-
| -ceasingly from early morning until mid
i night and all sorts of messages were
voiced- over the line. Heartless wretches
also employes this method of fooling un
suspecting friends.
Tiner-aling-iing.
"Hello! Well—"
"Oh. la that you. Mary? This is Jim.
Say Mr. Wilson wants to speak with you.
Call him up— No. 1947."
•'Hfllo. No. 1947! Ts this Mr. Wilson?"
"No: this is the Morgue."
A bang— that's Mary's . telephone— a
enwe— that is the Morgue.
While people were having fun at the
expense of the city the' city was enjoying
Its own pet little April fool joke—repeat
ing the prank over and over a^aln and
hailing each new victim with shouts of
applause and the shrill tooting of horny.
At the junction of Market. Kearny. and
Third streets at regular intervals a box,
neatly packed and stamped, as though
rc-ady for mailing, would glare the guile
less pedestrian straight in the face. Many
a man, woman and child, representing all
sorts and conditions of society, stooped
to pick up the innocent-appearing box.
None got any farther than the attempt.
The shouts of the crowd, many of them
previous victims, scared the parcel-picker
off, and he hastily lost himself in the
throng and waited in his turn for some
one to laugh at.
It was both a costly and hair-raising
April fool experience that Walter Mosier
had. Mosier. a young man possessed with
an ambition to learn dentistry, is em
ployed by Dr. Perkins, a Sixth-street den
tist. Walter's bogs occasionally allows
him to putter around the molars of his
customers who are out of funds.
One of thes? occasions arose Friday and
Mosier was delegated to perform the
charity service. The, victim was a boy
about 12 years of age. He was suffering
from an ulcerated tooth, and Mosier de
cided that the nerve must be killed, so
forthwith he filled the cavity in the
troublesome tooth with enough arsenic
to kill a horse and sent the unfortunate
youth home happy.
When Dr. Perkins came in Mosier, with
the dignity of a full-fledged dentist, told
his employer of his charity work. Then
Dr. Perkins thought of April fool.
"Say, Mosier." said the dentist, with a
serious look on his features. "I've just
received a telephone message to the ef
fect that the arsenic came out of that
boy's tooth and he swallowed it."
"My God!" exclaimed, the would-be
dentist. lf ls he going to die?"
"Well, the doctors are working on him
now, but they don't think they can save
his life."
"Say. Doc, I'm going to get out of town
before this kid dies. I don't want to get
pinched."
"Well." said Dr. Perkins, with a merry
little twinkle in his eye. "You can suit
yourself about that, but I'd advise you to
stay here. They-can't do any more than
charge you with mupder."
"Murder! Ugh! Don't say that. Dr.
Perkins," retorted Mosier, tearfully. "I
didn't mean to do It. I'll go and take
some arsenic myself."
The crestfallen apprentice spent several
moments of contrition and then he made
up his mind to get out of town. He got
50 cents from Perkins and made haste to
the nearest barber-shop, where he Invest
ed it in a haircut and a Bhave. M osier
gave the tonsorial artist orders to cut
}-is hair to the scalp and Bhave his sprout
ing mustache entirely off, hoping thereby
m disguise himself. The badly frightened
youth then returned to the office to learn
further detnils of his mythical victim's
condition. Dr. Simpson told him th« boy
was worse and Mosfer. started to leave the
office. "Wait a minute." called Perkins.
"Where are you going?'
"God knows where I'll go, but I'll never
go to jail for poisoning- that kid," an
swered the youth.
"You go down to the ferry to-morrow
and if the boy dies I'll telephone to you,"
suggested the doctor.
Mosier slipped out to his mother's
home, borrowed 510 and as early as 1
o'clock yesterday morning he arrived
at the ferry thoroughly disguised to
avoid possible detection. He walked up
and down the cheerless and 'desolate
wharves till morning, and then not hear
ing anything from Dr. Perkins bought a
ticket for Sacramento and stole aboard
the boat like a skulking criminal. On
the train he acted for all the world like
a noted forger crossing the line to Can
ada.
ttosiec confided to a friend before he
left that he would commit BUicide rather
than go to jail, which knowledge tuning
to Dr. Perkins made him decide noi to
cfrty the Josh any further. A message
was sent to the frightened youth, and
he returned to the city. Last night he
set about to drown his troubles in the
flowing bowl.
Garret McEnerney fell a victim to a
deeply laid April Fool plot laid for him
by his "close up" friend Jim O'Brien..
The bulky and brainy man of the law
dropped into O'Briens office, commonly
termed the "Cabinet," yesterday noon to
engage the contractor in a little chat.
"Say. Garret." chipped in O'Brien in
an innocent fashion just when the law
yer was i-xplaining to Jim Nealon the
way to make money, "when did you
stand for that bust over in the Palace?"
"What bust?" queried Mr. McEnerney.
"Why. the file they put in the corridor
of the Palace Hotel this morning," said
O'Brien as seriously as if he was talking
business with a moneyed man who want
ed- to spend a "thou or two" in street
work.
"There must be some mistake?" said
McEnerney. "No sculptor ever chiseled
me."
O'Brien is "close up," and his words
had weight with the man who was so
busy dissolving -the injunction against
Chief Lees that he did not stop to think
of April Fool's day.
"Let's go over, Jim, and take a look at
it," said MeEnernty, and .they both start
ed out tho door. O'Brien had no inten
tion of going over with his friend to seek
What he knew to be a myth, so he con
trived to' be excused In a manner ■ that
would not breed suspicion.
The opportunity presented itself when
Judge Lawlor happened along.
"I'm going to take the Judge on -for a
minute," said O'Brien. "You go over and
look at that yourself and I'll wait for
you."
Off went Mr. McEnerney and his April
Fool went down on the arc.hives of the
"Cabnit" as a decided success. Every.
body who dropped into the Cabinet was
sent over to the Palace Hotel to see what
McEnernev had looked for in vain.
"Pete" Dtinworth. the well-known vo
calist, was- the victim of a ghastly April
Fool josh. One of his friends telephoned
to Dunworth's • house early yesterday
morning and informed him that an inti
mate friend had died the night before
and was to be buried immediately.
"They, want you to be a pallbearer,
Pete," said th-e wily person at the other
end of the line.
"All right." said the popular tenor, af
ter expressing genuine regret over tae
unexpected death of his friend.
Promptly at 1 o'clock Dunworth, ar
rayed in a black cutaway suit and white
gloves, arrived at the .undertaking par
lors from which the supposed dead friend
was to have been buried.
"Is this where Mr. So and So Is to be
buried from." asked Dunworth, giving
the undertaker the friend's name and ad
dress.
"Why, he 1b not dead," said the under
taker, "who knew the man very well. "I
just ?aw him "at the corner of Sixth and
Mission."
At the Alcazar they revived the old the
atrical joke of the "key of the curtain"
with marked success. Mrs. Willie Dun
phy, the latest addition to the company,
ten minute* before curtain raising at thp
matinee, was sent on a hunt for the "key
to the curtain." "We can't open up."
said Stage Manager Bryant. "We have
lost the key to the curtain." Mrs. Dun
phy. who glitters on the bills as Miss
Howard, searched high and low for the
key and was in a condition bordering on
hVfiterics when the last bars of the or
chestra died away and the curtain was
lifted without a key.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Concerning the origin of the name and custom of All fool's day
contributed more to the extermination of
the heathen religion and its priests than
all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
though they were also freely employed.
The continuance of customs— especially
droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
the masses— after the original cause of
them has been removed. Is a very common
occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
firmly believed that "fooling" people on
the Ist of April is simply a perpetuation
of the annual public ridiculing of the old
Druid's and their superstitions.
Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
character, 13 thus claimed for April Fools'
day In a quaint old book of folk-lore
called "Father Time's Flyghtes." pub
lished in London In 1659. "numerous
Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
Fools on the First of April. This is said
to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah
sending ye dove out before ye water had
abated, on ye first day of ye month which
among ye Hebrews answers to our first
of April, and to perpetrate ye memory of
this deliverance it was thought proper
whoever forgot so remarkable a circum
stance to punish them by sending them
upon some fool's errand similar to- the
Ineffectual message upon which ye bird
was sent by ye patriarch."
The French associate with the first of
April precisely the same Ideas as do Enr
llsh speaking nations, but the person Im
posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*.
they style an April Fl3h or Polsson d' -v
ril. In the "Etymology of French pro
verbs," a most curious and delightful
work published In 1356. Billlngton I the
author, gives the following expiation
of the origin of April Fool customs / "The
word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and
length of time has almost totall- defaced
the original intention, which w^ as fol
lows: That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
took place about this time o'the year,
and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
and forward to mock and't->rment him.
1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caia
phas to Pilate, from Pilate -°- Herod and
from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
from thence, by which we send about
from one place to anoO«r such persona
aa we think proper subjects of our ridi
cule."
But It Is not only thrjU&hout Great Brit
ain, France and our/own country that
fools are made on U« nrst day of April.
The custom 1- elabrratfly observed
throughout Sweden, aid In Germany an
April fool la called elnen zam April
shlcken." The same custom haa also been
observed in India frm time immemorial.
Late in March of ach year the Hindoos
hold a great celetratton which they call
the Hull festival, of which the last day
is the greatest aid most general holiday.
During the con.nuance of the Hull, one
of its chief dl^rsions is to send people
on errands ar^ expeditions that are to
end In disapr^ ntment anl raise a lausi
at the expend of the person sent.
But the cistom of making April fools
has-been traced back to an antiquity even
greater t!** n that of the Hull festival of.
the Hind ° 9 - Tne ancient Persians wer»
accustorr«l to celebrate the period of the
vernal rruinox. which may occur as early
as ila-^n 22 or as late as April 23. with
elaborv*? festival tites and diversions; of
the Utter the chief was the making of
fool- precisely as we are accustomed to
mate them on April Fools* day.
jjp a quaint volume of poem.l bearing
tH title, "Verses On Several Occasions."
i,.id published In London. 1752, April Foola'
.ay is thus alluded to:
Now April morn b!*r Folly's throas exalts:
Now Dobb calls Nell and lauebs because ah*
halts.
"While Nel! meets Tom and Bays his tall la
loose,
Then laughs In turn and caJTa poor Thoma
"Goose."
In England, from earliest times, th»
ridiculous errands upon which the victim
of an April fool Joke •- sent have been
called "sleeveless errands." but the origin
and true significance of this term ar»
completely buried in oblivion and no an
tiquary has yet been able to unearth
them. These errands are as numerous as
they are Ingenious. Some of them hava
almost become classics, such, for Instance.
as sending a person to a book store for
the second edition of "Cock Robin" or
the "History of Eve's Mother": . sending
some one to a milk dealer for a pint ot
pigeon's milk and to, a shoemaker for an
ounce of strap oil. which, if the shoe
maker has been Initiated Into the Joke,
the Inquirer receives In the shape of a
severe blow from a strap acros3 the shoul
ders. AMY F. STOCKTON.PERSONAL IMPRESSIONS AND REMINISCENCES OF OOM PAUL KRUGER.
TJ3TE SUNDAY CALL.
dana handkerchief. Ont of cariosity I
entered the same church, anticipating of
course, that I should find It crowded, from
the mere fact that the President went
there. I was judging by what on» would
have looked for in Washington— or Lon
don. The little Pretoria church could not
have held more than a hundred or so.
yet I counted but twenty-four in the con
gregation, and of these the majority were
mothers with babes In their arms. The
President took his seat in an armchair
which had been specially provided for
him beneath the pulpit— this was the only
distinction he enjoyed over the rest of his
fellow worshipers.
The service was very simple — about the
sort of thine I should have found In
most Methodist or Congregational meet
ing-houses In an American villas*. Ther»
was a long prayer, a long: sermon, a hymn
or two. a chapter from the Book «f
4
period of eight days. April 1 Is the
octave of March 25, and the last day
of a festival octavo was always marked
by the greatest abandon and festivity.
At the New Year season especially all
sorts of wild, mirthful pranks were In
dulged In, and of these It is believed that
our April fool usages - were a part.
Origins of a religious nature have been
boldly claimed for April Fools' day by
many writers. An old English antiquary,
writing In 1753. states that the custom of
imposing upon and ridiculing people on
the Ist of April may have an allusion to
the mockery of the Savior of the world
by the Jews. Something like that which
we call making April fools Is practiced
also abroad in Catholic countries on In
nocents' day, on which occasion people
run through all the rooms, making a pre
tended search in and under the beds. In
memory, I believe, of the search made by
Herod for the discovery and the destruc
tion of the child Jesus and of his having
been imposed upon and deceived by the
wise men, who, contrary to his orders
and expectation, "returned to their own
country another way."
When the early Britons were Induced to
forsake' their Druidical priests and Idols
and to embrace Christianity, It was their
custom" for many years after to annually
hold in their churches at the commence
ment of April a great festival, resem
bling the Roman Saturnalia, at which
they indulged in a thousand ridiculous
and indecent ceremonies, gambols and
dancing grotesquely to ludicrous anthems.
These singular observances referred to the
exploded pretensions of the Druids, whom
this ' festival was designed to hold up to
scorn and derision. That there Is no more
effective weapon than ridicule was again
proved In this case, for this feast of fools
""Whence proceeds the custom of making
April fools? Answer: From a memorable
transaction happening between " the
Romans and the Sabine.3, mentioned by
Dionysius. Which was thus: The Romans,
about the Infancy of their city, wanting
wives, and finding they could not obtain
the neighboring women by their peaceable
addresses, resolved to make use of strata
gem, and accordingly Romulus instituted
certain games to be performed in the be
ginning of April (according to the Roman
calendar) in honor of Neptune. Upon no
tice thereof the bordqring Inhabitants,
with their whole families, flocked to Rome
to see this mighty celebration, whereupon
the Romans seized a number of the Sablna
virgins and ravished them, which imposi
tion, we suppose, may be the foundation
of this foolish custom." This most absurd
and wholly unjustifiable account of the
origin of making April fools is thus ridi
culed by a poet of the time:
Ye witty tiparks who makes pretense
To answer questions with good sense.
How cornea.it that your monthly Phoebus .
Is made a fool by Dionysius?
For had the Sablnen, as they -came,
D-partpd with their, vlrirln fame.
The Romans had been Jtyled dull tools,
"And they, poor Rlrls. been April Fools.
Therefore. If this be" n't out of season, -¦•'¦;;
Pray, think and give a better reason.
Some old folk-writers claim that our
April Fool customs are attributable to the
fact that the year formerly began, as to
come purposes and in some respects, on
the 25th of March, which was supposed
?o be the day of Our Lord's incarnation.
At that time' it was customary for all
festivals to continue for an octave, or
(Copyright and nil rights reserved.)
"The first of April lome do say.
TVoa «et apart for All Fools' Day;
But why the people call It «o.
Nor I nor they therr.reUes do know."
Thus an old English poet sings truly,
for It would be a hard matter to find any
one who can give an accurate and correct
account of how the Ist of April came to
be known as All Fools' day and of the ori
gin of the custom pertaining to It of then
_ trying to make fools
W\ of people generally
Sf , „ in every conceivable
tjrfjf V^ WS&JS"'"^ manner. In old
¦ books of folklore al-
most innumerable
r I jo^w statements are made
Bf &a concerning the or-
B y - . igin of • both name
it and custom, all dlf
' • " " ferlng as widely as
the poles and bear
" ; •. - ing not the slightest
Wlatlon to each other.
A learned antiquary, writing in 1599,
claims that our April Fools' day Is but a
continuation of the Qulrinalla, or feast of
fools, bf the ancient Romans. In- "The
British Apollo." a most ingenious work
published !n 17C8. I find the following:</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84028140/1902-04-01/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>April Fool Kept by All
People.
Gigantic Hoax Was a Complete
Success.
"This Is the first of April,
Hunt the gowk another mile."
From time itruneiuorlal thollrstof
April has been celebrated by all sorts of
hoaxes and playing of pranks. Tho
truo origin of April' Fool Is burled lu
tho dust of centuries and our great
est antiquaries seem unable to throw
any light on tho subject. Nearly all
people however, celebrate this day or
its equivalent and the similarity of
the practice and tho coincidence of
dutes establishes without n doubt In
the minds of authorities ihe fact that
It had an early nnd common origin
among mankind.
Nearly all tho peoples on the Conti
nent celebrate April Fool with pranks
and tricks, and even the Hindoos havo
a festival on tho 31st of March, called
Hull, which coincides vjlth our April
Fool.
Ono of the most popular amusements
on April 1, or All Fools day, as it Is
called, Is tho Rending of persons on
fruitless frrands. Unsophisticated
persons are sent to tho bookstores for
a copy of the "History of Eve's Grand,
mother," or to the chemist's shop for
"pigeon's milk," while small boys arc
sometimes sent to the harness shop for
strap oil, when a liberal dose of this
treatment Is usually administered to
the boy.
There Is a story told to the effect
that Francis, Duko of I,oiTaIne, mid
his wife owed their escape from cap
tivity at NanteH to this popular cus
tom. Arrayed as peasants, they were
makiug their way out. of the territory
when they were discovered by a wo
man who knew them. She Immediate
ly hastened to a guard, and told him"
that the Duko was escaping. "April
Fool," said the guard laughingly,
treating the matter as a joke, and
while he laughed the prisoners made
good tlieir escape
Occasionally a gigantic hoax Is per
petrated on tho people as a whole, and
such a one met 'with groat success in
London in I8RO. Some wag distributed
cards, bearing an official looking seal,
which read: "Tower of London Ad
mit the bearer to vlorv the annual core,
raony of the washing of the white lions
on Sunday, Aprij, 1, 1800. It Is par
ticularly requested that no gratuities
be given to wardens or their assistants.
Admitted only nt tho white gate."
This trick was highly successful,
and people swarmed to tho tower to
view tho washing of tho whlto lions.
NO HELP.
Farmhands Are Not to
be Had
And Are Being Imported From
Other States.
Chagrin Falls, April 1.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Tacoma Times.
THE DAY OF ALL FOOLS—WERE YOU ONE OF THEM?
BROKER
PHILL PS
TOJUIT
Patrons of the brokerage busi
ness operated by T. H. Phillips in
the Equitable building were look
ing glum this morning when the
word was passed along the line to
those who had Investments with
the concern that Phillips had quit.
It was circulated that - the as
sets would be small and the lia
bilities about $19,000. At the
office the operator would give no
figures ■; and Mr. Phillips at his
home' allowed his wife to make a
statement to the effect that he was
trying to effect a settlement with
creditors and would turn over to
them - some money and property.
How much she did not . say.
' At the office It was stated that
the business would 'be taken over
by Downing, Hopkins & Co., of
Portland, through whom Mr. Phil
lips has been doing 'business.
At Mr. Phillips' home his wife
said he was quitting business be
cause the legislature had passed a
law stopping it. • When asked
whether the business would con
tinue under the name of Downing,
Hopkins & Co. she admitted there
had been some talk to that effect.
It was said on the streets .this
morning that some Tacoma spec
ulators had been caught for; as
high as a couple of thomsam
apiece, and there was considera
ble concern for awhile over the
situation. . ;■• :
COUNCIL
BLUNDERS
'■■' In the hurry, to get the contract
signed and 4 the new i fire : house
completed . for East M ; street the
council overlooked the city char
ter last night and no v the whole
legislation ■:■. will ' have • to ' be . gone
over again. 1;.;/,-.-*:' -"t . % •- t .'■'■<''■ jg
Bids were received several, days
ago and Contractor Opperman was
given the job. The contract could
not ibe executed, however, for an
ordinance had ' not' been. passed.
1 The | ordinance was '•■ introduced
last night and rushed;to passage.
This S morning | it . was ■ discovered
• the > thing . was illegal ;as lit calls
■ for more money . than: can '. be ; ap
jproprlated■,' by * ordinance except
| when : the ordinance •* is ■ read  on
two separate nights. *t--jr" *
'•' The council will have to do its
legislating over next 1 week \ and it
will  • delay • the •■ fire ; house ; three
weeks. Er^j^^,-^;- w :'. r ; c :.;■*::/■'-■;•
White Girl Weds
Chinaman
(By United Press Leased Wire.)
VANCOUVER, B. C, April I.—
A special from Portage La Prairie,
Manitoba says: «w*"VTf, '^S¥'S!^^
m Chan 1 Sing, a Chinese Testaurant
proprietor, and i Nellie I Elliott, ! a
white girl of Melford, Bask., were
married ; yesterday. : The wedding
was i the close of a long conrtahlp;
The couple met In a hotel, where
they, were .working &In I Englan d
several years ago, and X had \ since
been I lovers. "i Chan !Is \ well ; »up
plled wKh thl» world's goods . and
Mln j Elliott is ; the possessor , of
a good education sad an attrac
tive face and mrt&sstoßga
;..; If paint be strained before using
It will '■'. cover 'more surface and
wear better.
The ? WiscoMte Btate i mintia la
con»llerlng;th« formation of an
aeronautic oo'lC*'fi^^^^^^^ffl|
0 Pure milt, whan frocan, pre
«ni« original :proportlo«,Ba
aWmm£ fof waajka*
TACOMA, WASH., THURSDAY E VENTMG, APRIL 1, I»OO
$3,000 in Gold
to the Pan
(By United Press Leased Wire.)
SEATTLE, April 1. — Three
thousand dollars to the pan on
Nolan creek, which gained fame
a year ago by bringing the atten
tion of the miners to the old
Koyiukuk diggings In Alaska, Is
the news that is brought to this
city by Billy Clarke, a pioneer
barber of Seattle, who reached
here yesterday from Circle City,
where he has been for the past
seven years.
Nolan creek, In the Koyukuk,
was struck by Johnson and Olson
in the winter of 1907-o*B.
ON BOTH BIRTHDAY GENERAL
BOOTH WILL LAUNCH SAL
VATION UNIVERSITY.
GEN, WM, BOOTH.
Drums will beat around the world
on April 10 and prayers go «p.in
50 languages from half a million
men and women in honor of the
eightieth birthday of Gen. win.
Booth, the ■ grand old ; man > who
heads the Salvation Army. .
.. The army, which I has i branches
from Iceland to India and Austra
lia, ia the product of the brain of
this veteran soldier , against . Bin,
whose brain Is as clear and active
today as it was a half century ago.
He has grown with it, and still di
rect Its minutest * operations. ■ %
All around the world the Salva
tionists will celebrate the birth'
day lof their leader. On. that day,
too, the : general .will show I fresh
proof of his virility by launching
the most ambitious ■ project .;» yet
started by the organization.Si-.
J A big University of Salvatls|i-r
--to cost $6,000,000, with branches
in London, New York and Chicago
—this is 4 Ocn. . Booth's latest plan
for advancing , his work. He Will
Issue » the I call^f ; funds, on 's his
birthday. Th« * purpose jtf #tny
school is ■to i train t workers In all
branches of ' Salvation work. I
: , |.
oivi/r «ma un lob*, ■
Bf HiM«J rrtM Lnu Wlw« ."
VICTORIA, j£ C April l«r
ona life w.a» lo«t In th« •arttnnfflte
which ahoofe tha oltle* of Tolrte end
Yokohama lh« day before U»« »t*»iO
«r Kag», Maru called "■ there, »ns
which ' arrived here today. *»«»»i»«
APRIL FOOL HUNTERS ARE
ON THE JOB TODAY
"All Fools' Day."
& Just why the first of April |1§
let apart as an occasion when
very.; wag ■ hoe "j license .to pra'otloa
iewptlon on tils fellow
man and get the laugh «n him no
nne seems ,to know, bat ; the : cus
tom is : gen©r«l and o* loss stand
ln«.* And after all i ttia pranks ol
the "April ; Fool H tinnt«rs s» gen
smlly tharmless.
PW t yoa I are ; not abta Ito ; langa
when |g tfhe laugh Is Yon ni MM
lc««p jrou* wtta WMIM to iflj</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1911-04-02/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The San Francisco
SUNDAY
CALL
¥*ar 9/% v /^L v^ ' B l^W ■ * '■ ' v jl HUB MI vU
Aprill Fool</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>JOKERS ANNIHILATE ARMIES
April-Fool Pranks Play Havoc With
European "War Map.
According io me map wmcu t-roi.
U p Wrench has prepared and kept
I . .. .- -.....- .
In the corridor of the third floor of
Academic Hall, European armies have
made radical changes in their ma
neuvers. The French apparently have
given up the war and have fled to the
western coast of France. The Eng
lish have disappeared entirely. All
the German forces of the western
theater are quartered in Paris. In the
east, the Austrian and German forces
are massed in the lowlands of Prus
sia, surrounded by Russian and Ser
vian troops. A few Servians are left
as garrisons along the frontier. One
lone Austrian army corps has escaped
and is now stationed in the middle of
the North Sea.
The havoc Is attributed to some
April Fool prank.
Another Instance of April Fool
thoughtfulness was shown this morn
ing when a member of the Agricul
tural faculty phoned to the county
jail asking "who had left a call for
him."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88084272/1916-04-01/ed-1/seq-14/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058393/1922-04-01/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> LPRIL FOOL
JOKES,
Copyright. 1922, by McClure News
paper Syndicate.
"Oh. Uncle Wlggily! What's that
behind yo.U? I hope it isn't the Fuzzy
Ko!" cried Baby Bunty one morning.
The little rabbit girl had come over
to the hollow stump bungalow to
borrow a cup of flour.
"What's that? The Fuzzy Fox in
here?'" exclaimed the rabbit gen -Ionian,
and ho gave such a Jump that
ho nearly slipped over back ward
April fool!" laughed B... Bunty
' "Oh!" exclaimed L'nclo WlggiB, BO
suddenly that his pink nose almost
' stopped twinkling. "Oh. so this is the
, first of April, is it?"
"Yes, and I caught you first ofj
all!" laughed Baby Bunty.
And so she had, for she had come
I over early to the hollow stump bun
galow on purpose to do this.
"Did I really make you think tho
Fuzzy Fox was there, Fncle Wig
glly?" asked Baby Bunty 'is the bun
nf gentleman snt down to his break
fast.
"You surely did for 3 moment." an
swered the bunny with a lui.Kh. "I
had no Idea this was April Fool Dsjy
But no matter. My turn will come,"
and he carried his glass of water to
the sink, spilling it out.
"Why did you do that"?" asked
Baby Bunty In surprise.
"Because," answered Uncle Wig
gily, "I have known it to happen m
times past that my glass of water on
April Fool morning would be full of
salt. As I don't want to drink salt
water now I lust emntiod mv rlaiu
1 11 fill It myself with fresh water."
"Oh there wasn't any salt in your
glasi " suirl Nurse Jane
"No, " added Baby Bunty. "I never
thought of that trick. I wish I had
But maybe Oh. Uncla Wlggily! Look
out!" she suddenly crlrd. "Is that a
pin in your chair?" 1
Uncle Wlggily Jumped up as If a
gun had gone off. Hfe looked In his
chair but there was nothing there.
"April Pool!" laughed Baby Bunly
again.
I'ncle Wlggily said nothing but he
sat down rather harfl and ate his
br. ik fast. And when linby Bunty said
"Oh. look out the window and see
who's coming!"
Undo Wlggily nevor looked up
from his morning paler. But some
one was coming along the, path to the
hollow stump bungaliw. They were
Curly and Floppy Twlltytail. tho plg
gle boys. Floppv had a llttlo bas
ket. "Do you want to look In this and
see what there Is?" asked Floppy, ns
ho and his brother camo In after
nrafl.lln U'lnfnr, II...I. r..l . 1 .
" '"h Ul. l Ull III'!
mat.
"Well. I can pretty nearly gu
what's In tho basket," said the bunny
gentleman It's some sneezing pow
der or a lot of dried leaves' You can't
April Fool me again."
"Oh. really, we wouldn't do such
thing!'1 grunted Ourl
"I'll open the basket!" cried Baby
Bunty. So she did, and inside was .1
lovely piece of cake that Mrs. Twisty
tall had sent to Uncle Wlgplly.
"April Fool!" grunted tho piggie
boys.
"Well, this Is a proper kind of April 1
T
Fool Joke!" said the bunny as he ate
the cako. which was very good. '''It
seems I can't be sure of anything this
morning." he told Nurse Jane when
tho children had run out and the
bunny was finishing his breakfast.
"You must he very careful." said
Miss Fuzzy Wuzzy
"I will," promised Uncle Wlggily,
and he was. But even at that a num
ber of- April Fool Jokes were played
on him nothing very serious though.
Once Jackie Bow Wow barked:
"Oil. is that 11 hlir hnil I n u..n
coat, Incle Wlggily?'' The bunnv
nearly twisted off his pink noso to
look at his back, but there was no
hole in his coat at all. Another time
Kittle Kat offered Uncle Wlggily
some candy, and when he chewed It,
Why It was sour Instead of sweet!
And Kittle mewed: '.pnl Fool."
"Well. I think it's my turnto play
an April Fool joko on some one,"'
said the bunny gentleman after a
while. "I wonder what I can do?
T want to play a real Joke'
He hopped along a llttlo farther
and, all of a sudden, out from be
hind a bush jumped he Bob Cat.
"Oh. ho!" howled the Bob Cat.
"Your ears look very good to me this
morning!"
"Do they"" asked I'ncle Wlggily.
' Well, do you know what dav this
Is?"
"It makes no matter of difference
to me what day this is!" howled the
Bob Cat ' I on!y want "
"Dear me' Look! Look behind
you! Is that a hunter man coming
with his gun?" suddenly asked Uncle
Wlggily, pretending to see something
back of the Bob 'at.
a hunter man with a gun! Oh,
don't tell me that! Don't tell mo
that!" howled the bad animal, and
away he ran as fast as ho could.
"I can't tell you that, for there
Isn't a hunter there!" laughed tho
bunny. "April Fool! April Fool!" And
lo h id played a Joke on the Bob Cat
just In time.
"Ha! Ha!" laughed the bunnv. as
ho hopped safely along. ' April Fool
Jokes aren't so bad after all'" And
If the pussy willow doesn't cry Jn the
night and want to bo rocked to sleep
in the cat's cradle, I'll tell vou next
about Uncle Wlggily and the .nrll
shower.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025182/1911-04-02/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>An April Fool Church Party.
It isn't often that the eve of April
I Fool's day or All Fool's day of
the year, is observed in social pas-
street christian church had a flne
I |, Daughrity's class time Friday night, however, in mak
ing merry and acting "foolish" over
ex- the first, day of the fourth month of
art
Unique attractions such as
arcades and other di-1 the years arrival.
of the I A short program of musical and
recitative numbers were given and
much enjoyment had. Refreshments
of ice cream and cake were served.
Some one has kindly written out the
words of a self-mamifaqtured A|ni
DAILY GATE CITY
si
Warner's Rust
Proof Corsets
"A very long skirt model,''
you say. Yes, but not a bit
too long for current style
It completely encases the
hips, which take on the lat
est figure contour, through
the corset shape The soft por-
tion of the skrt that Is, the
part that extends beyond the
boning—is drawn close to
the form by the SECURITY
Rubber Button Hose Sup-^s
porters, making the corsets^
thoroughly comfortable what-fes,':'
ever the po&ture.
Cor. 8th
and Main St.
We re April Fcol folks in an April Fool
state:
We wear April Fool hats on our
April Fool pate
We do April Fool things in an April
Fool way
I11 this April Fool town we're go.
ing to stay.
the body than the trimming of the hat I Hear ns! Hear us! We April Pools
or garment. Deep cream or yellow sing
tones rather than white, are reckoned I The April Fools holler and make the
most desirable for lace accessories, I town ring
while the use of dyed lace and net to F01'
match other materials continue.
Square meshed Venetian laces lead
and are costly in the real, but not high
in excellent imitation nets and inser
tions. Square meshed Valenciennes is'O! We April Fool Girls with our April
also liked in edgings, insertions and Fool Face
all overs. FANNIE FIELD. Wear April Fool Flowers with April
Chorus:
we're April Fool girls and we're
April Fool boys:
Have April Fool Times, and April
Fool Joys.
Fool grace:
1 And Sing April Fool songs with our
April Fool voice
And the April Fool boys are our own
free choice.
O! The April Fool skies, and the
April Fool days,
Are the April Fool's pride and the
April Fool's praises:
1
Mr. Williams Entertained the Sun-j
beam Girls.
Yesterday afternoon at his parish
residence, the Rev. George C. Wil
am el a a os
of the young ladies of the Sunbeam
Circle of the Congregational church.
The meeting was the regular monthly
one that, is held the first Saturday of'
each month
For the April Fool sun and the April
Fool rain:
Warms the April Fool's blood, and
fills the April Fool's brain.
No April Fool wind, or April Fool
drouth,
Stops our April Fool's heart or
April Fool's mouth:
For April Fool's fun and the
Fool's song,
Are the April Fool's Life in
April Fool's home.
Garters are an integral part of the corset. No corset skirt
can possibly fit well witnout them, and the "Security" Rubbe,
Button are the best. Prise $1.50 and $2.00.
created much men-, ptreot.
ment the other evening and the words
are printed below this morning so
that all may learn them:
The April Fool's Song.
(Tune, Hot Time.)
an 1
Chapel Fund Meeting.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1904-12-25/ed-1/seq-28/#date1=1756&index=14&rows=20&words=April+Fool&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=april+fool&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1909-04-11/ed-1/seq-59/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=April+April-fool+Fool+fool&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=april+fool&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-03-27/ed-1/seq-76/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Signs of Spring, Virginia R. Smith, Santa Barbara
she went to a hotel where sin- knew
a lady wanted two kittens. No, the
lady had not any yet and she took
them gladly, giving Laura the $50. Oh,
how gladly Laura went home with the
money pinned safely under her cloak.
April 1 Laura was up with the sun
and put the money under the over
turned plates, and then skipped back to
bed. 'When grandma and grandpa
turned over their plate* that morning,
what, to their amazement did they
find but the fifty needed dollars. Glad
ly Mr. Foster set off to town with the
money,' driving the old horse that he
had no need of selling now. It was
not until weeks after did they find out
wlu> put the money under their plates
that happy April Fool's day.
FINANCES (ORE,
1836 Wonlman avenue. Kan Diego.
Logan Heights school, 5A grade; 10
years old.
t A LITERAL CUSTOMER
■
Dear Aunt Laurie:
This is not a true story. One day
I woke up and was wishing that It
was the first of April and I wanted to
play Home kind of trick on somebody.
This was easy to do, but 1 did. not
want to get caught at it. 1 went to
my bank and took a penny. I hail no
more In at the present time, but want
ed to buy a book telling about April
fool tricks. It cost 25 cents, but I
wanted to get It with l.cent, and did.
I knew a boy who wanted to get a
quarter's worth of sugar. I told him
to wait while 1 got the chisel and
hammer. I cut the penny Into four
equal parts anil then I went to the
store with the boy. When we got to
the door I stopped him and told him
to give me the quarter and I would
buy the sugar. He did so, and I asked
for the book and 1 gave him the
money, then 1 asked for a quarter's
worth of sugar and laid down a quar
ter of a penny and ran. The man
didn't know where I lived and-couldn't
find out. I gave the boy his sugar and
went home, which .was quite a ways
away. I think It was a me.an trick,
but the grocers were fooled. I don't
think I will ever do anything like
that again, but 1 had to imagine some
- thing.
Your nephew, .-
W II.MAT HA ASK.
2641 Pomeroy avenue; age 12 years;
grade A 6, Cornwell street school.
A LESSON FOR THE JUNIORS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
I am going to tell you about an
•"April fool joke that turned out very,
very sadly. • '■' **
One April Fools day papa's cousin
went to a party. While she was there
one of her friends pulled a chair out
from under her and, of course, she
sat down on the Boor. Her back hurt
her dreadfully all evening, but she
did not say anything about it.
She was a school teacher, and went
to school every day for a month after
'her accident. Her spine kept hurting
her worse and worse, until finally she
went to the doctor's. He told her that
there was something the matter with
her spine that could never he cured.
She went home and went to bed. never
to get up again, but lay on her back
for seven long years, suffering terrible
pain. At the end of seven years she,
died. ■•-,'.- . •
I have a little emerald ring of hers
that I wear every day. livery lime 1
look at it I think of seven Ion? sad
years that Mary suffered from an
April fool's Joke.
SHIRKS K. BILK,
419 North. Bright avenue. Whlttler.
AT grade, Bailey street school.
CAKE IS TAKEN
Dear Aunt Laurie: J^/.v
One April Fool's day when 1 was in
boarding school we girls decided to
give an April fool spread in our room
- that nlcht. Contrary to our usual run
torn, we were not going to have any
Jokes played.
The faculty were everywhere watch-
Ing that no jokes were played, and
every one was very peaceful except us.
We had all the food in our rooms ex
cept the cake, which we wanted to be
fresh. Therefore we had to get it In
while the teachers were watching.
How to do that we had not yet de
cided, until one said that we might
put a small rope out of the window
and fasten it on and haul it up just as
supper was being served.
We had just got it fastened, when
ill- girl that was holding It called
down that tin- teachers were coming
to every door, making the children
come to supper, so she had to run and
• leave it hanging. As it was dark, we
had no fear that any one would dis
turb it until we did.
After supper we went to the window
to get the cake, but imagine our sur
prise when no cake was there. We till
trooped down the hall quietly, but
were sent back.
We knew our cake was stolen, but
wo played a good joke on whoever
took it, for the girl that bought the
cake confessed to having told the bak
er to make it as salty as he could, and
we would not have been able to eat it.
Your niece,
MILDRED KKHiiISOX.
USED EMPTY EGG -
Dear Aunt Laurie: ■ '
On April Pool day we were eating
oranges when a thought came to mo
how to fool my aunt, whom I had been
trying to fool.
I cut a piece off the top of an orange
and scooped out the pulp with a spoon.
Then 1 filled it with orange peelings
and put the top on. Then I went next
door to my aunt, holding the orange
with the top down.
1 asked her if she wanted an orange
and she Bald "yes." I gave it to her
and she said, "Thank you; I am so
fond Of orange*, Then she saw too latn
that it was a Joke. T shouted: "April
fool! April fool) I've got you fooled
this tlmeV Then 1 gave her a good
orange. • — .-.'<
Next morning my uncle, WOO baa
been out the night before, asked my
aunt how the orange filled with rinds
got on the sideboard. He said: "I
picked it up and was going to eat It,
and found it wiw no good." Then my
aunt laughed and told him I gave II to
her ami -April ftoled her with It, ana
the had put it there to fool him. He
had not thought of its -being April
fool, or he would not have said any
thing about It. Both got April fooled
by an orange. Tour niece,
LELA CAMPBELL.
Ago l", Lankershlm.
PARROTS LEARN TRICK
i tear Aunt Laurie:
One day a party of people went to a
park to have a picnic. They had come
early, prepared to stay all day. it
whs a beautiful day, and the forenoon
they spent in looking at the flowers
-and animals and playing on the
lawns'.
At noon they were ready for lunch,
and after finding a cozy place with
trees and bushes all around they sat
down and ate heartily.
As they were clearing up all the
scraps and papers around they heard
a noise which sounded like some one
calling for help. They all ran to see
what was the matter, but all they
could see were the birds in their cages,
which were near to them. After they
had gone back they heard something
which sounded like 'April fool." They
all laughed at this and afterward
found out that it was the parrots. In
tho morning these birds had heard
some boys play the Joke and they took
it up, as they often do, words which
they hear. Your loving niece,
KATHEHINE MILLERD.
Long Beach (general delivery); Long
Heath high school grade 9Vi-
USED EMPT YEGG
Dear Aunt Laurie;
One time not long ago, when eggs
were scarce, April fool's day eama _
I thought I would play a trick on my
father, who likes eggs very much. I
bought a nice big white egg, I took It
home and blew the yelk out. I put it
In a box and wrapped the box up with
gilded paper, then tied It with a ribbon.
While letting the table for dinner
on April Fool's day l put the egg on
my father'! plate. When he sat down
he exclaimed: "Ha, ha! What have
I here?"
Not caring for ribbon or paper, but
anxious for the contents of the box. he
eagerly opened it. Ha wan surprised
and delighted when he saw the clean,
white egg lying there. He told me to
boil it for him, but I said It was al
ready boiled. I cracked it open for him
and dropped the empty shells on his
plate, i cried at the same time, "April
fool!" •
"You rascal!" he exclaimed. "I will
get mv own egg* after this." Your
niece. DOROTHY PAY.
Logan Height! school, grade A": ace
10 years. 1580 Logan avenue, lan Diego.
GIRL'S BIRTHDAY ON THE FIRST
Dear Aunt Laurie: .-' "j;-".j
The girls at school were talking
about birthdays.
"When is yours?" naked the girls of
Dorothy, who was near by.
"First of April," replied Dorothy. •
"Oh, you are an April fool!" Bald
Mane, who was one of the biggest
girls.
Lila, Blanche, Bella and most of the ,
other girls commenced to tease Doro
thy about being an April fool. Doro
thy felt very Had, it ml when she got
home she told her mother all about It.
"Never mind," said Dorothy's moth
er. "They will be April fools, after
all." So Dorothy's mother told Doro
thy the plan.
Now, It was a few more days before
April 1, so Dorothy and her mother In- .
Vlted ten girls and ten boys.
They got some ferns and flowers and
decorated the room where the party
was to be, held. Dorothy's brother
helped. to do the errands and Dorothy
herself helped to do the cooking.
I First of April came. Dorothy's eyes
beamed with delight. The party was
to lie at 2 o'clock p. in. and and at
.'> p. in.
Soon the children came. They, played
games. Then they went into the room
where tho table was set. There were
twenty-one chairs and plates. Marie
was the oldest, so .she was to cut the '
cake, which was four layers, with
(Continued on I'ugf Nrvrn)
All Juniors who will write to
Alice Warner, 729 Banana
street, Jacksonville, Fla., and
send her self-addressed and
stamped envelopes will re
ceive in return, free, some
seeds of the beautiful Royal
Ponciana. It is a magnificent
plant and has a large red
bloom. She thinks it will grow
for Herald Juniors in Southern
California and wants them to
write her and let her know
what success they have with
the plant. She is not in the
seed business —simply wants
Californians to have the flower.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-04-03/ed-1/seq-64/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AN EMPTY BOX FOOLS BOYS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
one April fools' day 1 w.-is up north
nnd all Of UN girls knew that the boys
were going "' do something.
That night we all gut re-idy and
went to tin- show, As we were coming
home the hoys flipped behind an
orange tree and just before we got
there they put a dummy out In the
path,
I was the fust one to see it and I
drew the other gills' attention to it.
They dared me to go and see what it
was. So I went. Bod JUSt as I was
going to look they pulled the string.
We didn't see it any more. Then they
;dl jumped out and said "April fool."
When we girls got home we made up
our minds to fool them, s ( , we found
a box and fixed it all up nice and went
out where they were playing. We put
it down there and some of the hoys
came and Mid; "Hay, fellows, we
[omul a box of candy or mush."
He started to !>iek it up and we
pulled the string and said "April fool."
Then we all went Immc,
ZELLA WADDELL.
Sawtelle school, sixth grade.
WOMAN PICKS UP PURSE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Jt was close to April fools' day. My
friend and I had 1 been trying to plan
a trick to play on somebody. We soon
decided to go down town and buy a
purse;
We took the purse and filled it with
big buttons and Knoll buttons until it
looked just like money fr >m the out
slde, Then my friend took the purse
and ran up the .street as fast as lie
could. While running be propped the
purse on the sidewalk. Then he ran
"BED TIME"
around the block and tame back and
met me.
We watched the purse for a little
while, when an old woman came down
tba street. She picked the purse up
and looked around. She did not see
anyone and Miked on very fast to the
next block. Here *he went in a hall
and opened the parse. She looked
eagerly ir.to it, but to her surprise she
saw the buttons. She dropped the
purse and walked sulkily away.
Your nephew',
GEORGU CARL CLARK.
1547 Valley avenue, San Diego, Lo
gan Heights school, age 1- years.
A WET JOKE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
When I was asked over to a hnuse
on April fool night they told me to so
in another room. When I wont in they
had two chairs and ■ cloth spread
across them. They told me to sit down.
I sat down on the cloth. Some one
was .sitting on each end of the cloth,
and when I sat down they jumped up.
This let me and the cloth go to the
door; at last I thought I was going
to Urn floor. 1 was looking: for a hard
tail, but on my way to the floor a tub
of water caught me. The water was
not hard, but it was wet.
I got my clothes all wet. T would
rather have hit the floor than the wa
ter, because the water was cold, and
it was cold outside and I had a long
ways to go. 1 did not sit on another
cloth any more. (April fool.)
RAY McCLURE
Sawtelle city school, grade 6.
WINS PRIZE FOR COLLECTION
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Once a man said, "Whoever gets,
tin' most postal cards of different
kinds will get a prize of $10 and can
ride in the races." Another boy and
I said, "Let's try to get it and buy us
a ride apiece."
My brother ■ was in China at the
time, and I took the stamps oft his
letters. : ; . .r ; ' .
When it was time we took them to:
the fair and got the second prize, which
was seven dollars and a half. My
father save me four dollars more, so
1 got a rifle and I have it yet.
HAYMOND OSTERMANN.
Sawtelle school, grade 6.
SON AFFECTS DISGUISE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
"Now Jack." said his mother, "you
can H<> and play, for this is April
fools' day. and you can play a trick
on 'daddy.' "
Jack ran away as fust as hll legs
would cany him. Hi- went to his
papa'a stori Is the market square. He
drened up as ■ tramp and went up to
the counter and asked if he could have
a drink ol' water, which was readily
given him.
He waited until dinner time and ato
with his father who, not knowing his
son, Kindly save him his dinner, Jack
put some salt in tin- coffee and did
a few other iricks at ulnner,
Ho next thought he would play a
trick on the hired man.
He Rot Into B sack and let the man
put him on the scales. He picked up a
board and hit him on the? head. The
man then looked and saw the sack
jumping after him. He was so fright
ened he ran and told Jack's father.
VVAI.TKIt W. TATLOR,
Bawtelle, grade 6.
BOY THINKS PIGEON IS CAUGHT
Dear Aunt Laurie:
One day last year 1 Woke up not
knowing that it was April fool. I had
a trap set lor pigeons. Papa had been
up a lons time and had gone out and
set the trap off. When I came out
from my room he laid:
"I think there are pigeons in the
trap." I looked out and the trap sure
was sot off. After breakfast 1 went
out Pap« came behind me. As soon
as I lifted the trap he said, "April
fool." 1 said to him:
"Is today April fool?"
He said, "Yes." I went over to a
friends house and we played "Duck
on the rock." Lots of times I took
two rocks. I took cement which I
got from a house that was being built.
He could not knock my duck off.
Finally lie came to see what was
the trouble.
"April fool." says T.
LEWIS EDWARDS.
S awtelle'Clty schools, grade 6.
BOYS ARE DISAPPOINTED IN A
BREAKFAST
Dear Aunt Laurie:
About ■ year ago last April fools'
flay v woman thought she would have
some fun with her boys. The boys got
up very late that morning. She never
got breakfast till late. When she got
breakfMt ready she called the boys,
and ;tft.T they had oaten other things
they came to the pancakes. First the
bora took them. Then they began to
eat. for they were very hungry. One
of the boys said they seemed raw, and
his mother said:
"Eat right on and you can see if they
are raw."
The boys said they didn't taste good,
and their mother laughed and said it
was an April fool on them, because
there was cotton inside of them. The
next April fools' day the boys fooled
their mother, but 1 never heard how.
But April is soon coming around again.
RUTH LARSON.
Sawtelle city school, sixth grade.
PLAYS JOKE ON AUNT
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Last April I went to my aunt's farm
to spend a fi>w days with her. April
fools' day was very close at hand
and I wanted to play a good trick on
my aunt. Every day I spent my time
thinking what would be a good trick
to play on her. When April fools' day
came I went into the house and told
her that one of her ponies was dying.
She did not remember that it was
April fools' day, so she left all of her
work and ran to see what was the
matter with her pony. After she got
theie I said "April fool."
When I said that she laughed at her
self.
When my uncle came home I told
him all about it, and he laughed at her,
too. She said that she wouldn't get
fooled again, and she would remember
that it was April fool's day.
GLADYS WATKRBUHY.
Sawtelle city school.
A TRICK FAILS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Once I wanted a wheel. My father
said he would get me one after a while.
When April Fool day came he told
me to go look in the shed. I thought
I had a wheel, sure. I went and
looked, but there was nothing. I came
back and told him there was nothing.
They all gave BM the laugh and said
"April fool.'
At dinner I got the sugnr bowl and
put salt in it, but it didn't work, be
iiiuse it was too coarse for sugar, so
1 was left fooled again.
RAYMOND OBTERMAN,
Sawtelle city school, grade 6.
IN SPITE OF TOMMY
Home study for Tommy had just be
gun and he found it hard to apply
himself to regular hours. At bedtime
on* evening hi.s father said. "Tommy,
I am not at all pleased with the re
port your mother gives me of your
conduit today."
"No, father, 1 lenowed you wouldn't
be, iind I told her so. Hut she went
right ahead an' made th' report. Jest
like a Woman, ain't it?"— Ladies' Horn*
Journal.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84025968/1892-01-07/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-03-27/ed-1/seq-75/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>POLICEMEN HAVE THEIR JOKE
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Walter and Mark were two little
boys who had heard of the tricks
played on April fools' day.
The first trick was a very harmless
one. Mark, seeing a countryman buy
some oranges at a stand, went up to
him and said: "Did you drop some
money just now?"
" The man took out his purse, counted
his money, and (aid: "I miss no money.
Have you picked up any?"
"Oh, you April fool!" said Walter,
They now began to grow proud of
their success, and never once noticed
that a policeman with brass buttons
on his coat and a staff In his hand was
watching thorn closely. At this point
the policeman came up, and, seizing
both boys by the arm, said: "Come
with, me to the station."
"To the station?" they cried, In
great fear.
"Yes, to the station. You have been
breaking the law."
"We were only in fun," whimpered
Mark.
"I want to go home to my mother,"
whined Walter. *
Hut the policeman wanted to play
his April fool trick Just as much as
the boys had wanted to play theirs; SO
he took them to the station, to a man
he called "Judge," and told him what
the boys had been doing. '
Prisoners at the bar," cried the Judge,
"what have you to say?"
And then, seeing that they trembled,
and that the tears were In their eyes,
the good-natured Judge took two apples
out of his pocket and, giving one to
each boy, said:
"Here, you little jokers, your sen
tence Is that you . eat these apples.
Kirn home and tall your mammas how'
1 made April fools of you."
CLAUDIUS WILCHOH.
355 Wisteria drive. Itamona school,
grade A 6.
HORNED TOAD KEPT FOR PET
Dear Aunt Laurie:
on.> time I told my friend that had
staid all night with us to come and
look at the little chickens in the yard.
While she was In the house I got
out of doors and got to looking around
to Me what I could find to play a good
April fool trick. At last I came across
a horn toad. They are a kind of toad
"with little horns all over them, but
they can't hurt you. They are a little
smaller than a real toad.'
.While she was looking around to
find the chickens, I came and slipped
this toad down her sleeve.
She had on one of these morning
Japanese dresses.
Well, she began to scream and cry
out that Gladys had put something
down her neck and it felt like a
snake.
At last mamma asked her what was
the matter. and I went up and whis
pered to mamma and told her nil
about It. She said:
"Oh, Elsie, they have played a trick
on you." ,
I got a letter from her the other
day and she said she still had the
horn toad and it's got two babies. It
will be two years since we caught it
mi April Fool day, and she said she
never would forget It.
oudys TURNMirtE.
Sawtelle city school, grade 6, age 12.
CAT IS MISCHIEVOUS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
When I was 6 yean of rge I had a
beautiful white cat by the name, cf
Tabby. Tabby was not a mischievous
cat and it surprised me greatly when
he played me this trick.
On April 1 as I -was dressing for
school Tabby camo purring around mo.
But Instead of petting him I got angry
and hit him and he ran ay.
Soon after ns I was about to put on
my slippers I could not find one' of
them. I hunted all about as did mam
ma, but we couldn't find the n issi'ig
slipper. So I had i? stay home that
day. •
The next morning I nvoke with
something scratching on the bed. I
arose and looked and who should I see
out Tabby with the slipper fast be
tween his teeth. He had hud it all the
day before.
IUJTH GILDEA.
205 North Mathe'.vi street, agj 10.
I have been In 1.,-is Angeles but a
month and am not yet going to school.
WEDDING CAKE FULL OF SALT
Dear Aunt Laurie: "..'
Mrs. Simpson's brother-in-law was
going to be married to a young lady
by the name of Lizzie Plummer.
Mr. Simpson's brother was going to
be married on the evening of the first
of April. A lot of people were invited
to attend the wedding. . '
, Mrs. Simpson was a woman who al
ways liked to play tricks and jokes on
people, so on the morning of the first
Mrs. Simpson made a whole lot of plea
and cakes. < . y
.; She made one a large cake that, she 3
colored pink and white, but v she put
salt in it instead of sugar, and in one
of the pies she put pine wood shavings
instead of sliced apples. v- She was just "
as sober as one, could :be . when she"
passed the pie and j cake. - She could
LOS ANGELES SUNDAY HERALD—JUNIOR SECTION
hardly keep from laughing, but she
: did. Mamma took a piece of the cake
and papa took a piece of pie. and cake.
Mamma first took a bite of her piece
of cake and it taste,] rather salty, but
she thought she had got some of the
salt on it which she had by the side
of her plate. jgh I took another bite,
but it was so salty that she knew then
that It was an April fool joke. Mam
ma sail v\iien she looked up from her
plate everyone was laughing as hard
as they could. I think that was a
good April fool trick.
CHARLES PRITDBN.
Sawteile City schorl, grade 6. .--T,-
JAPANESE USE SNAKES FOR
FOOD
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Did you ever know thai Japs eat
rattlesnakes? Well, they do, I can
tell you, and they,work on Sundays..
There is only one Jap out of the five
that an- pruning our grapes that don't
eat rattlesnakes, and ho is a Catholic.
The Japs killed five rattlesnakes on
Sunday In our grape vineyard. Per
haps you would like to know how to
rook them. They invited Homer and
Bill and me out to the camp to eat
some. Homer and Bill tasted It. but I
didn't. This is how they cooked them.
Tiny skinned them, then they put them
on sticks to dry for two days. Then
they cut them In little pieces and
roasted them over the fire. They then
eat them. How would you like to taste
some? HAROLD BURROWS,
Etlwanda; Etiwanda school, grade
2; age 9 years.
I enjoyed your letter, Harold. I have
heard that the savages used to-use
snakes for food, but X certainly did
not know that more civilized people
did. I Should be glad to hear from
you In the writers' contest also.
BRIGHT DOG STAYS AT HOME
Dear Aunt Laurie:
. We had decided to send Ross (our
dog that we have bad for over four
years) into the country, for we have
lived In the country ever since we got
Ross, and he doesn't like it in town
nearly so well.
We thought It would be better for
him. Papa was out talking with a
Signs of Spring, Milton Bashan, Inglewood school, Inglewood
man one day, and lie spoke about send
ing Hor3 into the country. Ross was
with him and be heard what papa Bald.
Wo kept him chained, and we didn't
think he could got away, but the morn-
Ing Ross was to go papa went into the
bam and he couldn't see anything of
him. All that morning we waited for
him, but he didn't come back.
' The man who was to take Ross had
to go without him, but after it was too
late for him to go Ross came back.
So he didn't go after all. . Your niece,
LUCY LARCOM SPAULDING.
371 Claremont drive, Pasadena.
Washington school, fifth grade.
MOTHER DOES QUEER COOKING
Dear Aunt Laurie:
One April fool about one year ago
my mother was in the house baking.
My cousin ami I were out In the yard.
A plan came into her head. She said
to herself:
"I guess I will put some cotton In
the cookies."
So she put cotton in three of them.
We did not know anything about it.
Then "she asked us, if we wanted a
cookie. We said yes, and she - gave
us each one with cotton In it.
Just like me, I wanted to take a big
bite. -I got in the big bite a bunch of
cotton. 1 did not let my cousin know
about It. He had not come to his cot
ton yet. Hut when ho did come to if
he was so scared he I threw It down.
Mamma was right there to say "April
fool." j
After that. happened my cousin and
I were going around April fooling
everybody that rime along. -X.-S
-. Your nephew.
LOYNAL CHASE.
Logan school, grade A 5; 12 years
old; 4016 M street, San Diego. ■
CRIES "MICE," SCARES AUNT
Dear v Aunt Laurie:
The only April fool trick I remem
ber playing on any one I played on
my'aunt last year. As it was AH
Fools' day I asked my mother If I
could visit my aunt.
I knew my aunt was afraid of mice,
bo after waiting* a little while I told
her there was a mouse behind her.
You should have heard her scream.
She jumped on a chair. 1 said, "April
Fool."
She said she would get even with me.
I didn't think she could, but .she did
before the day was over.
RALPH CLAVELOT.
Sawtelle, Cal. Grade 6.
MOTHER PLAYS GOOD TRICK
Dear Aunt Laurie:
It was April 1. We were standing
behind a fence waiting for someone to
come by, for we had a string tied to
a purse with a piece of fake money
tin it.
Pretty soon a man came by and
•topped i' pick it up. We gave the
string a jerk and the string pulled the
puree through a hole in the fence. We
yelled "April fool" and the man
wont on.
Nobody would pick It up again, so
we decided to do something else. We
got an old hat and put a brick under
it. Pretty soon a man came by and
gave the hat a kick and hopped away
holding his foot in one hand. •
Our mother called us and said that
she had some candy for us. She gave
us a piece and we began to eat it.
Soon we spit it out and ran for the
faucet, for the candy had pepper in it.
Then mamma said:
■April fool."
1 guess the laugh was turned on us,
all right. After that we never ate any
more candy on April 1.
Your nephew,
ASHER HOPEWELL.
1053 Xl Molino street, Berendo street
school, grade 87.
BAKER READY FOR BOYS
Dear Aunt Laurie:
"Tomorrow Is April Fool's day," said
the baker. "I'll have to make some
cotton doughnuts and pepper pies for
the boys."
;;e set to work and made some
doughnut dough. Then he mixed cot
ton with it and made the doughnuts.
They ,were big, fat. fluffy ones, and
looked nice, but I do not know how
they tasted.
"Now," said he, "there are some
peppery mince pies to make." No
sooner said than he began to work.
He made the dough and then the.
mincemeat. He was sure he had dosed
it enough with redhot pepper, for he
had used two-thirds in the can. After
the pies were baked he set them in the
window to cool and went to bed.
The next morning he got up earlier
than the rooster and made some April
foo! cookies and cakes. At 9 o'clock
in the morning the boys came over to
the bakery to see what mischief they
could do there. The baker said he
would give them some pies and dough
nuts and cookies and cakes if they
would go away. The boys took them
and ran away under some trees to eat
them.
The boys came back soon, and the
baker cried. "April fool!"
Your nephew,
FRITZ CRAKJCR.
55.") Julian avenue, San Diego; Logan
Heights school, grade SA; age 10 yuars.
BOY ASKS FOR CANDY
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Once I thought I would play an
April fool trick. I got a boy. to give
me a piece of April fool candy. He
gave it to me In the presence of an
other boy. The boy asked for some
thing good and I gave him a big
bite. He began to sputter anS spit
ami cough and jump arond. The
candy was filled with pepper. He said
he did not like it much.
LESLIE CLARK.
Sawtelle City school. Grade 6.
HOME-MADE CANDY
Dear Aunt Laurie:
On April 1, three years ago, I planned
to play a trick on v, schoolmate of
mine. I was always up to some mis
chief and could never keep out of it.
At home, school or out visiting I was
always up to something. This day I
was over to see my schoolmate, and as
he knew nothing of April 1 1 had a
good chancf to have some fun. The
day before 1 had been very busy mak
ing April candy and putting red hot
pepper" in it. I asked him to try spine
of it, which, of course, he did, not
having the least Idea that he was
being tOOled.
The candy was so good that he put
It all in his mouth at once and Started
to eat it. I tried to keep from laugh
ing, but about in the middle Of it I
gave a loud giggle. My ichoolmata
now seeing the Joke and tatting the
candy that'once looked so good and
which he now fouml to have pepper
in it, took H out and threw it away.
He asked me what I was tooling him
for. and I told him it was April Fool's
nd thai he was the one who was
tooled. A very mean trick, was it not?
CLARENCE BHEPARD.
10 years. 498 Julian avenue, Ban Diego.
POLICEMAN INTERFERES
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Walter and Jim were two small boys,
who had heard of April fool tricks, so
thought they would also play some.
Their first trick was a harmless one.
A .string was attached to a ball and
the ball was pulled along on the side
walk, while Walter and Jim kept out
of sight ai a street corner,
A little fellow named Peter stopped
to pick up the ball, but every time lie
tried to touch it it would move away
from his grasp, and he did not know
what to make of it. At last he dis
covered the trick, and then the boys
cried "April fool,"
Their first trick was such a tine suc
cess I hat they decider! to play another
one. Seeing "a young lady crossing a
muddy street Walter said, "Pardon
me, madam, but just look at your
stocking."
The lady stopped short, looking down
at her ankles, then the boys, cried
"April fool."
The boys wire proud of their success
now and never once thought a jolly
policeman was watching them closely,
Seeing a man buying oranges at a
stall, Jim stopped him and said, "Did
you drop some money just now?" The
man counted his money and suid, "I
miss no money."
"April fool," cried Walter.
At this the policeman stepped up and
said. "Com* with me to the station."
"To the station." cried they in
fear.
"We were only in fun."
"YOU have been breaking the law,"
said the policeman, firmly.
"I want to go home to mother,"
whined Waller, but the policeman
wanted to play his trick as well as
the boys wanted to play theirs. He
.took them up to a man called "Judge"
and told him what the boys had been
doing.
"Prisoners," said the judge. "What
have you to say about this?" Then
seeing how they trembled and the
tears In their eyes, the good-natured
judge gave them each an apple and
said:
"Your sentence is that you eat these
apples, Now run home anil tell your
mammas how. after making fools of
others, you fell in the hands of the
police, who made fools of you."
1 PEARL MAY.
Sawtelle school. Crade J,
"THE CAT CAME BACK"
Dear Aunt Laurie:
Tom was a merry lad who played a
trick every time lie gut a chance,
It was April Fool's day, and Tom
was looking for a chance to play a
trick on somebody. At last he saw a
well dressed man go into a house
across the street.
"I will play a trick on him." thought
Tom, and taking a stout cord from his
pocket, he went across the street and
tied it from one fence to another, so
that it fill directly across the well
dressed man's doorway. He then let
fall the heavy iron knocker and scam
pered a little ways down the street.
Presently the man appeared in the
doorway, and looking down the street
saw Tom making faces at him.
"I'll fix you, you little scamp," said
the man. Hut belore he had taken two
steps he fell sprawling in the gutter.
The man went into the house, swear
ing to beat the band, and Tom scam
pered away.
Alter a while Tom came back with
a cat, and, first looking to see if any
body was near, went into the well
dressed man's yard, climbed up on the
porch and looked into the window.
He wished nothing better. The man
was fast asleep.
Tom raised the window as softly as
he could and put the cat in.
Pretty soon Tom heard an outburst
of swearing: then the window opened
and the cat came out head over heels.
Taking Tom for his enemy, the cat
(lew at him and scratched him on the
face.
Tom scrambled off of the porch M
quickly as he could and ran home, and
never played any more tricks. Your
nephew, JOHN WECKERLY.
Logan Heights school, grade A".; age
11 years. Thirty-third street and
Webster avenue, Ran Diego.
BYSTANDERS FEEL FOOLISH
Dear Aunt Laurie:
One afternoon of April the first, my
mother was out walking. She came to
a group of stores, in the doorway of
one of them a few men were lounging.
They had a untie on their face! and
were watching the pasuraby to see all
the fun which they might afford.
Walking In front of mamma and
engaged in conversation was an elder
ly lady and her son. They had not
noticed the men in the doorway, and
did not see the little object lying on
the sidewalk until they were almost
upon it, and they were evidently not
thinking Of April fools day, lor the
young man stooped to pick it up amid
the laughter from the crowd In the
(Cuutiuutfd no I'dge l-'utir)
3</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063758/1904-03-15/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FOR THE CHILDREN.
Some Nice Tricks Which Might be Played
On the Approaching "April Fool's
Day."
"But how do you fool them?*
asked .\argy.
She was a very little girl-not
six years old--and she looked up to
Edgar. who was twelve, as an ex
tremely wise person.
"You make 'em think things are
different from what they are," said
Edgar. "Only, of course, you d -n't
tell fibs. And when they find otb
they're tricked. you call "April
fool!: It's lots o' fun."
"It must be." said largy, eager
ly. "I mean to try it."
Edgar looked at his sister. Some
war. altho it was -lots o' fun" for
hinm. he did not like to think of
Margy teasing her friends. and
laughing at their disappointlent.
"Oh. you're too little." he said.
\iamma told me one wasn't ever
too 'ittle to help others," Margy
declared. Edgar wAs so puzzled by
this speecn. that he made no further
renark.
When the Wheaton family came
into the dining-room. on the first
of April, 'Mamma was saying: "I
am so tired of that baked apple
every morning, and I con't care
for oragnes any longer. I do wish,
either that it was time for berries,
or that Dr. Mason had not told me
to eat fruit for breakfast."
Margy danced along by her side,
listening and smiling to herself. As
Mrs. Wheaton caught sight of the
table she gave a cry of surprise.
There sat a plate of strawberries
beside her napkin.
"'April fool!" called Margy. "I
bought 'em myself. Mamma, down
to Mr. Snyder's. And you thought
you were going to have baked ap
ples again. April fool!"
The rest-her father and mother,
Jamie and Edgar-looked at each
other over the little girl's innocent
head. "That is a sweet wav-tc
trick one with something nice,"
said Mamma.
"Why, what other way would
there be?" asked Margy. "No
body would do mean things to peo
ple-not on any day in the year."
A merry voice called "April
fool!" after Papa, whose hat and
coat, all neatly brushed, lay upon
the hall-table. And the same cry
followed Edgar's usual search for
-his school books and his finding
them, strapped together. lying be
side his cap. A sprig of geranium
from largy's cherish plant was
pinned upon the lapel of Jamie's
overcoat, and "April fool!" he
heard. as he hurried into it.
Ellen. the second girl, weht out
to the butler's pantry a while later,
and discovered the silver from
breakfast rinsed and dried and laid
in its proper baskets. "April fool !
piped 31argy."
"What are you doing, child?"
inquired1 Miss Wilkinson. opening
her window to question the~ little
girl in the gar(den next (door. Mar
gy looked up brightly:
"'I'm going to April fool the
birds, she said. "with this plate of
crumbs. They don't expect a thling.
you know. They'll be so surpris
Miss Wilkinson gazed down into
the radiant little face:
"You're a good child." she said,
quickly. and shut down the sash.
Margy ran into the house and
told her mother how Miss Wilkin
son had April fooled her: "Because
she never said I was a good child
before."
WVhen the scrubwoman, wvho was
working next door, went home that
night. Miss WVilkinson astonished
.Maria by g'iving' her a basket of
cold pieces : "April fool !" said her
emprloyer. smiling in a grim way.
ani i\! aria smiled to:
yTan e kindiy ier oi'
me." saidl she.
Air. W\heaton had not beenwi
ing lon in his ofnice when an ac
quaimnance ecaei who~ wa:nted o'ne
ioilr forsomecharitabl Y ict
The face (1 his litt&. giri came up
before her father. Het hajm iekh
man nye dollars. and said. ".\ri!
fool'!" and then they both laughed.
Tamie wras one oi the older pu
p)il's in the high school. and a favor
ite and leader among the big hors.
M\Iiss Fo'nan, the timi d. nervous
Latin teacher, always dlreaded that
half-hour she had] to pass with mis
chievous Tamie Wheaton andi the
comrades lhe incited to whispering
and nonsense. Today. those on the
back benches in the Virgil class be
haved as well as the girls upon
whom she could depend. They be
haved so well. in fact. that she stop
ped them on their way out of the
room and thanked them for it.
Jamie looked up into her face witt
twinkling eves: *We April fooled
v-ou, didn'.t we ?" he asked.
Jack Watson. who had quarreled
with Edgar. had played a horrid
trick upon him yesterday. The two
sides of the room led the march
from it. on -alternate days. On the
thirty-first of March Jack had im
i proved the opportunity to drop a
decayed apple into Edgar's over
:oat pocket. Edgar was very an
gry. Today Jack had good reason
to look out for something in return.
To tell the truth. Edgar had actual
Iv brought in box. a dead mouse
tf:rom the trap at home. with the ful:
ntention of tucking it into Jack's
cket a.slhe passed the overcoat on
his war down-stairs.
Nobody would do mean things
to people. Margy had said. Jack
ad been mean to him. Yes: but his
'ittle sister thought him her wise.
good brother. above such revenge;
and spite. Her shining eyes. when
she called "April fool after him, I
as he found his books in the hall.
seemed to look down into h:s heart.
e could -iot deceive their trnst.
At noon he ran down-town.
When Jack, very cautiously and
icaring the worst. peered into his
pocket that night, a flush of shamed
surprise crept over his cheeks. He
saw a handful of chocolate-creams.
and a slip of paper that read "April
fool!"
I've had such a lovely day."
sighed Margy. sleepily, as herl
mother tucked her into bed that!
evening; "I've been busy every
moment-most And I've fooled
lots of folks. Wouldn't it be nice
if they came oftener-April Fool's
and dhristrias Day. I mean. They
se!-m a good deal alike, you know.
-The Independent.
Many husbands are so sentimen
tal that the want their wives to al
ways wear the dresses they had
wh'en they first knew them.
Elberta Peach Trees,
Barred Plymouth Rocks.
Red Raspberry Plants.
Eggs for hatching a specialty. All
inqniries promptly answered. Write
for Circulars.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-03-31/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TWO CENTS THE DAY BOOK TWO CENTS
MEETINGS TODAY, SUNDAY AND MONDAY
SATURDAY
Friendship Circle Y. P. S. L. April
Fool's party at 9th ward Socialist
hall, 8 p. m.
Machinery Molders' Union -No. 233
holds special meeting at 20i S. Hal
sted, at night
SUNDAY
West Side People's Forum, Robey
and Warren av., Jerome Hall Ray
mond speaks on "Russia and the
Overthrow of Autocracy," 7:45 p. m.
Francis Hanchett speaks on "The
Mission of Theosophy," at 116 S.
Michigan av., 3:30 p. m.
Chicago Salon meets at Masonic
Temple, hall 901, 3 p. m. W. F. Mc
Gee speaks on "Criticism of Father
Siedenberg's Opinions on Birth Con
trol." Universalist Church of Redeemer,
Robey and Warren av., Fred A.
Moore, minister, "Holy Week and
Holy Living," 10:45 a. m.
Society of Anthropology meets at
Masonic Temple, Corinthian hall,
2':30 'p. m. "War, What For?" and
"My Life in the European Trenches,"
by Daniel H. Wallace.
Northwest Side Public Speaking
club meets in Woman's clubroom,
West Park No. 1, 2:30 p. nu
Russian revolution celebration at
Schoenhofen's hall, Milwaukee and
Ashland avs., 2 p. m. Speakers in
several languages.
North Side Y. P. S. L. symposium
at Wicker Park halls, North av., Mil
waukee av. and Robey, 2 p. m. Ben
efit of party press and campaign.
Clarence S. Darrow lectures on
"The American Constitution" at
Garrick theater, 2:30 p. m.
"Crime and Criminals," by Chas.
E. Erbstein at Progressive Prepara
tory school, 8 p. m.
4th Ward Socialist Party meeting
at Healy school hall, 30th and Wal
lace, 2:30 p. m. Robt. H. Howe, can
didate for city treasurer, and K P.
Gugis, candidate for alderman,
Welles Park Woman's Choral so
ciety gives concert at Garfield Park
refectory. Mrs. F. J. Kingstey lec
tures on "Municipal Market"
Poale Zion Branch No. 6 (English)
meets at 1208 N. Hoyne av., 7:t0
p. m. M. Dolnick leads discussion on.
"Will Poale-Zionism Solve the Prob
lems of Jewish Workingmen?"
L. Marcy speaks at Union hJI,
1001 W. Madison, 8 p. m. Subject:
"Why We Have War."
Liberty Hall Players present Lady
Gregory's "Rising of the Moon" and
"Hyacinth Halvey" at Hull House
theater, 8:30 p. m. Admission, 25 cts.
MONDAY
Counter and pantry .night workers
of Thompson's, Weeghman's and
Messinger's meet at 115 W. Madison,
8 a. m.
o o
Berlin. German chemists dwoov
er method of making flour substitute
out of linden and beech buds. Call it
as nutritive as barley flour.
FREE VERSE
By Jim Manee
April Fool!
This isn't free verse at all. It cost
you two cents.
P. S. True, tomorrow is ApHf
Fool's day, but we don't publish on'
Sunday, so I had to spring this today.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045499/1938-05-14/ed-1/seq-14/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=APRIL+FOOL&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=april+fool&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-charlie-chaplin</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-11-04/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PASTORS CANT COMPETE WITH
CHARLEY CHAPLIN
Milwaukee, Nov. 4. "Charlie
Chaplin" sermons were called "im
possible" by the Rev. Samuel H.
Woodrow of St Louis in speaking be
fore the Woman's Board of Missions
of the Interior, which closed here to
day. "There has been much talk about
making sermons interesting," said
the speaker. "We never can make
sermons as interesting as melo
dramas or prayer meetings as amus
ing as Charlie Chaplin. They never
were meant to be so.
"If a heathen dropped into New
York and saw a church with a seating
capacity of 1,500, attended by about
200 on Sunday and dark six days a
week, he would never go back with
the impression that the United States
was a Christian nation."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085187/1916-03-10/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>RIVALRY BETWEEN MOVIE MEN
Charlie Chaplin, highest paid
actor in the world, is appearing
at the Melbourne and Liberty to
day in the same picture, "His
First Vacation.'' Never before
has the same actor appeared in
the same picture at two Tacoma
movies at the same time.
It is an evidence of the keen
rivalry between movie men. The
Melbourne had signed the film
for next week. The Liberty, how
ever, obtained the same picture
for the latter half of this week.
Manager Sumni**rville of the Mel
bourne telegraphed a hurry-up
order for his film yesterday when
he heard of the Libertys' move,
and obtained his copy of tlie film
by express yesterday. He put it
on his bill at 4 p. ni. without an-
Tlie picture remains at both
houses until tomorrow night.
CHAPLIN AT
LIBERTY
The old favrolte — Charlie
Chaplin—who has returned to
the IJberty.
Movie fans who see Charlie
Chaplin this week at the Liberty
will not only see the world's
greatest comedian in action, after
a long vacation, but will witness
the work of a man who gets
$670,000 a year for being foolish.
Chaplin recently signed with Mu
tual at this price. His Liberty
film, "His First Vacation," is
added to the regular bill of "The
Innocence of Ruth,' a clever
;crook drama.
BABY FILMS
AT COLONIAL
In view of tlie fact that Ta
coma Is, at the present time, in
terested in better babies and an
observance is being held here for
three days beginning today, it
is an opportune time to mention
the excellent and instructive film
shown at the Colonial theater
every week on better babies. The
films are ln the form of a series
! WHERE TACOMA IS
| AMUSING ITSELF
Theaters
; .TACOKIA
[ Next Sunday and Monday—
; "Peg o' My HeHrt," with Flor-;
' ence Martin nn "I'eg."
KMl'ltliSS
! "The Girl In the Taxi," by
l Wilkes players. Matinee But
; nrday, next welt, "Inside the
; Lines."
PANTAGES
Ward's five piano girls, nnd
> good vaudeville acta.
Movies
APOLLO
"The Eternal City," Froh
; man feature photoplay, with
t Pauline Frederick.
COLONIAL
"Tennessee's Pardner," with
I Fanny Ward, \
M KLHOUHNE !
"Via Wlreles," with Galli
1 Kane and Bruce MrKae, and J
: "Hlii First Vacation," with r
■ Charlie Chaplin. \
LIIIRHTY [
"The Imnocence of Itut!i."<
with Viola Dana, and "Hi-
Flmt VacaUon," with Chafici
Friday. March 10,1916,,
Charlie Chaplin lias tlie honor
of appearing at two bin Pacific
avenue photoplay houses today
and tomorrow in the MUM pic
ture—a feat never before accom
plished in Tacoma by any motion
picture actor.
and fully show the best care that
can be given to infants. Tha
methods shown have been en
dorsed by the best known physi
cians of the country. The bath
ing, dressing, feeding snd .gener
al care are illustrated with tha
statistics given on the screen.
These pictures are shown every
Sunday, Monday and Tuesday.
The "better babies" number com
ing Sunday is an unusually inter
esting one and every mother in
terested should see It.
Mystic Thrill
In Big Play
Something of the mystic spirit
that attaches to papal Rome la
carried to tlie audiences that see
"The Kternal City," which li
proving one of the biggest attrac
tions tlie Apollo has had in a
long time. One feels the "eterni
alness," so to speak, of the great
religious power centered In the
Holy Father. The reverence ha
comands and the very spirit that
lives in his as it shines forth In
the impersonation by Fuller Mell
ish have much to do in building
up the climax of the play.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87093407/1916-04-22/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>300 BOYS MARCH
IN NOON PARADE
Charlie Chaplin* Give Down
town Seattle Lunch
time Laugh
THEY'RE LED BY BAND
The downtown aection of
Seattle waa all messed up with
Charlla Chapllna Saturday
noon.
About 300 boys, all coatum
ad Ilka Charlie and Imitating
I th* ecrean comedian'a famous
walk, participated In Tha
Star*a Charlie Chaplin parada.
Tom North, Northweat minuir
of tfc* film led '*•
profession la his automobile Then
nm» Cavana'itha band, and then
the rarortlnn Chaplin*
Other automohllrs brouaht up
the rear, one of them rirrylii* the
Judaea
Th»re were Chaplin* of all a»e*
and aires, from boya of 5 rlear up
the line.
f'rlrea were awarded at Iton
March* park, at the conclusion of
the parade
N'orman Hsrkett. leidln* man
i for Wlike* player* at th«> Metro
! iolHan. Mavor'a Secretary Jlmmv
I 'rehan. li. S Tolila*. of the North
ern Pacific, Tom North and John
liamrli'k were Judaea
Klrat prlite *'»* $25 In ca*h.
given by INmrlck. who I* man
ager of the It**. where Chaplin'*
burleaque on "Carman" I* now br
ine shown Second prl»e wa* a
125 watch. glv»n by Tom North
Third prlte wan a 125 *ult of
clothe*. given by Channcey Wright.
Other prlaea of Rei pa**ea were
given
Ttio i!»t of prlre winner* will b*
anrmnn'ln Monday'* Star
The only red-beaded Charlie
Chaplin In the world *i» dlacov
ered In thr parade
ll« had clipped a wlap of hi*
own brick-colored tre**e* and paet
ed them on hla upper lip.
During the performance at the
Hon Marehe park, one future
oon a year comedian lost hla baggy
trouaera while doing the Charlie
Chaplin walk
The kla went In drove*
They *w*tted eali other ov«r
the hrada and made face* nt the
truffle cop*
One cnterprl*itig Charlie crawled
on the back of n pn*alng anto and
Rwatted an elderly occupant over
the "dome" with hi* cane
Daylight bomb* containing tlck
eta to the Metropolitan theatre
were explodod In the »lr before
the parade.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014682/1917-10-15/ed-2/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"The Fireman"
An uproariously funny comedy
one of Charlie's best. Come
early for gcod seats.
Tonight
7:40
T
"An Innocent Magdalene"
SUscMcf wrought by sondalons tongce3 and aa irfflo
csst girl x?ho suffers from them znaks thij bcantif ul
story well written and acted.
PICTURE SCHEDULE
The System 7:40
The Fireman 7:53
Innocent Magdalene. 8:20
SIDNEY DREW in
"THE SYSTEM"
(Metro Comedy)
i
NOTICE Coming October 28th: "The Slacker0
TO DARKEN HAIR . !r.
HaveYbii Ever Considered
that your eyes may be the cause of your ailment. Consult
Dr. John7t Mundorff of the ;
AMERICA
lH8.Fort Street
Honolulu, T. H.
Blaisdell Bldg.
32
STAR-BULLETIN 75 CENTS PER FdOMTH
; It's Grandmother's Recipe to
Brinq Back Color and
luster to Hair
You can turn gray, faded hair beau
tifully dark and lustrous almost over
niirhi if vou 11 cet a ou-cent Douie 01
-Wveth'a Sas;e and Sulphur Com
nnnnd" at. anv drue store. Millions of
bottles of this, old famous Sage Tea
Recipe, improved by the addition of
other ingredients, are sold annually,
says a well-known druggist here, be
cause it darkens the hair so naturally
and evenly that no one can tell it has
teen applied.
Those whose hair is turning gray or
becoming faded have a surprise await
ing them, because after one or two ap
plications the gray hair vanishes and
your locks become luxuriantly dark
and beautiful.
. This is the age of youth. Gray
haired unattractive folks aren't want
ed around, so get busy with Wyeth's
Sage and Sulphur Compound tonight
and you'll be delighted with 'your
dark, handsome hair and your youth
ful appearance within a few days.
This preparation is a toilet requisite
and is not intended for the cure, mttl
gaticn or prevention of disease. Adv.
MEETING NOTICE.
E
malamaia ana. he halawai o na
hoahanau o ka Ekalesia o Ktvraiahao
ma ka po Poakahi, Okatoba 15, 1917,
hora 7:30, ma ka luakini o Kawaiahao,
no ka noonoo ana i kahu hou no ka
ekalesia.
A meeting of the members of Ka
waiahao Church will be held at 7:30
o'clock next Monday evening, Octo
ber 15, in the church.. The meeting is
for the purpose of considering the
calling of a new pastor for the church.
JOHN K. KAMANOULU,
Ifoahanau.
Honolulu. Okatofca 13, 1917.
Tax R
ILANCHE SWEET
IS AT LIBERTY
Blanche Sweet, idol of millions of
followers of the silent drama, is al
ways assured a warm welcome at the
liberty theater the -Home of Para
mount Pitcures," and. of necessity the
stopping off place of Blanche Sweet
while in Honolulu. Twice welcome
is thi3 star when in the east is an
other star also a favorite of Ions
standing with the select Liberty au
diences. Thomas Mcighan appears in
the current feature at this theater,
"The Silent Partner." as co-star with
Blanche Sweet and the combination is
one that it would be hard to beat.
"The Silent Partner" is one of those
kind of dramas that always appear to
have teen especially written for Miss
Sweet. It affords her an opportunity
to turn from tears to sunshine as she
alone knowns how. It is a powerful
drama with business loyalty as its
foundation and tells of a faithful steno
grapher and her successful efforts to
save her employer from financial destruction.
r WW
SEEN A I HAWAII
cor.ir.iEucirjG
PAUAttt C HOT St STA.
N T RAN&tJ.
eturns
The Henry Waterhouse Trust Co., Ltd., has opened
a department for the assistance of its clients in making
out ' "
51 Federal Income Tax Returns and other documents re
quired under the new Federal Revenue Laws. ,
. 51 The new law assesses all incomes over One Thousand
Dollars for bachelors ; Two Thousand for married men.
; 51 This department will be under the able direction of
; MR. PHILIP F- LEE, head of our bonding department.
Mr. Lee has had a wide experience in work of this
character through his former association with mainland
financial institutions.
Henry Watkouse Trust Co., Ltd.
Corner Fort and Merchant Sts.
Phone 5701
Charlie Chaplin the real one may
remain in Honolulu for a short time,
but Charlie Chaplin the reel one is
almost a permanent fixture. Provided
the management of the Hawaii thea
ter can s'o arrange, C. C. will be a
perpetual attraction.
There is little difference with C. C.
as to the title of his attractions. Just
so long as the leading comedian of
the screen is in the billing Honolulu
and every other city in the world will
turn out almost en masse. i ne cur
rent Chaplin attraction at the Hawaii
happens to be entitled "The foreman,"
and the title is a good one as it is
an excuse for Chaplin himself to ap- j
near for a couple of reels of laugh J
production. As is customary with
Chaplin's films there is nothing to it -
but laughter, although that commo
dity is more plentiful than at any time
at the Hawaii since, the last appear
ance of the same star. '
Lillian GIsh also appears as a .Ha
waii star in. "An Innocent MagdeleneV.
a strong rnangie-r me ah imiuic
This Is one of the Hawaii favorites. ;
g
fti nuA An QHn
nuuiinf iniwut vMiwwi
CHARLIE CHAPLIN, AND
SAILS AWAY FOR HIL0
Boyishly beaming with satisfaction
at the great crowd present, Charlie
Chaplin reeled up the gangway or the
Mauna Kea Saturday afternoon before
departing for his visit to the volcano.
Minus his makeup, "moustache.
i ,
cane ana massive snoes, some ui
the many children present could not
be convinced that their screen idol
had really come to life in Honolulu
until the comedian twisted his ears,
wrinkled his face and let his feet per
form. Then there was a chorus of
childish voices shouting, "bee Char
Hot"
lib
Cliarlie had scarcely boarded the
steamer until lfe and Demosthenes
Lycurgus had established an entente
and posed with arms locked for a
squad of amateur photographers. Due
to "Monty's" plentiful proiwrtions
there was grave danger of the Vol
cano hotel manager "hogging the
camera," until Charlie was placed on
the weather, or camera, side.
As the Mauna Kea pulled into thqi
stream, the screen comedian waved
a red bouquet, tiped his white flan
nel hat, shuffled three dance step3,
did a" donkey" with his cars, smiled
his Roosevelt smile, teeth and all,
and shouted "Aloha kakou."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058246/1917-11-15/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHARLIE CHAPLIN
IN HAWAII
HONOLULU, Nov. 12. Tho fam
ous Charllo Chaplin arrived in Hon
olulu, October 10, and whllo ho in
tended to como for a rest betweon
custard pio throwing contests, ho
waa'kept cxtromely busy sightseeing.
Photographers camped on his trail
and snapped him riding tho sivf
boards on tho Beach at Wnlkl, eat
ing two fingered pol, dancing with
tho hula girls and even flirting with
Polo, tho Goddess of Fire, on the
odgo of tho Volcano at Kllauoa.
It Is expected that ns soon as his
contracts permit ho will bring over
a company and bo filmod with an
Hawaiian setting which will bo uni
que. Ho was accompanied by Itobort
Wagner, tho well known writer and
they returned to tho mainland, Oc
tober 17, tired, but happy.
Charlie Chaplin, movlo king, small
boys loud his praises sing. Ho will
bo back with us today from a trip
to Hllo bay hero ho went to visit
Pelo and to see tho lnva Jolly. Char
llo likes Hawaii's stylo and ho fain
would stay awhllo, loafing on tho
sun kissed sand, eating pol with
cither hand; Hstonlng to tho ukuolo
played by Walkikl, 13111 Dalloy; oat
Ing.dog in guiso of pig; practising
thb hula Jig. Dut no's got to get
back home and with us may" no
moro roam back to make a nation
smile In raro Charlie Chaplin's way.
When his pictures come this way
as they will on some flno day, wo
shall watch for something new In
the moving scenic vlow. Wo shall
hope His Nibs to see In tho surf at
Walkikl, look to see him gaily prance
in tho featlvo hula dance, and find
Joy without alloy, in tho palo elus
ivo pol, Charlie Chaplin's back to
day. Hip hurray! Banzai! Hurray!
We shall seo him, I've a hunch at
the merry Ad Club's lunch, where
ho'll pick a friendly bone and make
Jokes to help tho Loan.
Now, togethor, small boys all old
boys, bold boys, short or tall, when
the boat pulls out tomorrow show
your very earnest sorrow that C Q.
has got to go, that .,tho parting is
a blow, by parading to tho boat there
to take a final gloat at tho moving
picture king; hark, the herald angels
sing!</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-05-12/ed-1/seq-37/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AT WAU.ORF-ABTORIA HOTEL,
on Saturday Evil*. May isth, at S o'clock.
Capturing Charlie Chaplin
By Harriette Underhill
Once upon a time we did not love
Charlie Chaplin. It was not so long
ago, either?not more than two years?
and it was when all movie houses re?
leasing his pictures had those horrible
wooden effigies of him in the lobby.
This may have helped to prejudice us.
At any rate, we used to glory in the
story of the nice old lady who went tim?
idly up to the box office and said: "Ex?
cuse me, "but is Charlie Chaplin's pict?
ure showing here?" "Yes, ?madam," re?
plied the box office man. "Going on at
2 o'clock." "Thank you," replies the
n. o. 1. "Then I won't go in." We al?
ways quoted that nice old lady and
never felt that we were really under?
stood unless we could find some one to
talk to who didn't like Charlie, either.
This was not so difficult at first, but
we felt that we were rapidly losing our
very best supporters, and hardly a day
passed but some one of them went over
to the pro-Charlies. Then along came
Heywood Broun, "our favorite dramatic
critic," saying that Charlie Chaplin was
screamingly funny and an artist. We
began to weaken.
First we went to see a Chaplin pict?
ure with an unbiassed mind. Then we
went to see another one voluntarily,
and then we fell to wondering how long
we must wait for the next to be re?
leased.
Four days ago we saw Charlie Chap?
lin talking to a man in front of Clar
idge'8, and we became incoherent with
excitement. It was the first time we
ever had seen him off the screen, and
we were immediately stricken with in
terviewitis. Stage and screen persons
have come to be merely subjects. They
are good, bad or indifferent?mostly in?
different?but Charlie was a prize not
to bo ignored.
The fact that he was avoiding pub?
licity and had refused to see all inter?
viewers made the thing so much more
interesting. The most he could do
would be to deny his identity and say:
"Madam, how daro you! I am not that
sort of person." But fortunately his
countenance was not as inscrutable as
that of the hotel clerk up at the Ritz,
where Charlie has his modest little
three rooms and five baths. But more
of that hotel clerk later.
At any rate, we decided to sacrifice
everything on the altar of duty, so we
went straight up to the great and only
Charles and just as we were about to
pluck him by the sleeve and say, "Ex?
cuse me, Mr. Chaplin, I'm the person
who has been writing such nice things
about you," we discovered ?hat the
man he. was talking to was the man
who writes the second best movie re?
views in town.
Of course, even with a proper intro?
duction it was a bit disconcerting ?to
meet your screen idol so suddenly,
without his shoes or his cane or his
hat, and yet we knew him immediately.
Wo apologized for the interruption,
mentally deciding that wild horses
couldn't drag us away until we had had
a chance to find out just how Charlie
Chaplin talked, how he thought, how
he dressed and how he looked.
He talks humorously, he thinks se?
riously, he dresses quietly and he
looks handsome. He has the whitest
teeth we ever saw, the bluest eyes and
the blackest eyelashes. "How did you
know me?" inquired Mr. Chaplin
naively. "Why, you look just like your
pictures," wo answered truthfully.
"Not my pictures on the screen, I
hope?" said Charlie. "Oh, no," said
we. "But, you know, occasionally one
does see a photograph of you in a
magazine." "Oh, I see," said Charlie.
"Such is fame." And then we said
pleadingly, "Won't you please let us
interview you?" To which he replied:
"You know, I haven't seen a person
nor talked to any one, but if you'll
promise not to say anything about my
work for the government, why?all
right."
He looked terribly suspicious. Just
as though we were not taking more of
a chance than he was. Hadn't we seen
him drop ice cream down a lady's neck
and get her involved in a revolving
door and trip her up with his cane?
And how could we tell what moment
he might pull a dog out of his. trousers
pocket or drop an egg out of his hat on
our new suit?
But he told us that he never again
would pull a dog out of his trousers
pocket, because Mutt, who co-starred
with his master in "A Dog's Life," is
dead, and no other ever shall take his
place. When Charlie came East he
left Mutt behind, and to, being only a
dog, Mutt refused to forget his beloved
friend. He starved himself to death
and was buried on the 29th of April.
"Every one told Mutt that I would
Burely return, but perhaps he didn't
understand, or perhaps he didr?'t be?
lieve them. At any rate, he never would
] eat after the last time I fed him, and
the inscription on his tombston^ reads:
'Mutt, died April 29?a broken heart.'"
We talked to Mr. Chaplin for an
hour, and then he suddenly remem?
bered that he had to go out and make
a speech on the subject which we
promised not to mention. And he told
us about how much better he likes the
West than he does the East, and ad?
mitted that he could play the 'cello
and the violin and the piano, and thst
he had worked for two-and-six a week
in London, and that he didn't know
why people laughed at him, and how
he first walked his famous walk. The
other things which we learned about
Chaplin are probably known to every
one who knows Charlie.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1918-11-12/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Charlie Chaplin Married;
Bride a Movie Star of 17
i" 1 i
4 V
MILDRED
WARRIS U-
CHAPUN tfc".'.,
WITHHOLDING AERO CLUB
PRIZE REPORT DENIED
Awaiting Official. Notice of Winner
In Statue of Liberty Flight, Says
Officer of Organization.
Th 9 report, published In one New
York paper, that tho Aero Club of
America had held' up prises Which It
offered for tho winner of the race from
Helmont Park around tho Statue of
Liberty on the ground that It would
r.ft be lecmljr to present the guerdons
to a non-commissioned officer Is dented
by Alan It, Hawley, rrctldcnt of tho
club,
"The story Is made out of whole
cloth," ald Hawley to-day. "The Aero
Club Is waiting only for (ho proper of
ficial notincntlon os to who Is the win
ner. It la generally understood that
Beret Clnrcnco Coombs won the race
In record time, but tho club has re
ceived no omclat report to that effect.
We bare not the slightest trace of feel
ing against Eergt. Coombsv On the
Contrary, we have as a club entertained
him, and stand ( ready to deliver the
priio to him as soon as he Is officially
declared the winner.
TUGBOAT MEN AT WORK.
nesntne Job After Olbrtlort Fol
lorrlnK Knd of Strike.
Striking lighter and tugboat men who
called oft their strike yesterday but
postponed going back to work until
after they had celebrated aermanya
surrender were on the Job to-day.
Danger of a freight embargo probably
has been averted. It was stated at the
office of W. 1J. Pollock, Federal Director
of ruilroai Marino freight In New
York.
SAGE TEA TURNS
GRAY HAIR DARK
Wedded in Los Angeles Oct.
33 Official Carelessly
Reveals Secret.
"When I wanted to marry I didn't
have tho money. Now thut I havo
tb.3 money, I don't care to marry."
Theffo wcrt) once Charles Spencer
Chaplin's sentiments, but elnco ho
mado that remark tho same Mr.
Chaplin, who Is Charilo .Chaplin,
Charlie of tho films, tho llttlo fellow
who lias made millions laugh at Ills
queer shoes and ridiculous mustache,
and, Incidentally, has mado millions
of. dollars for himself, lias been in
ducted Into the ranks of tho bene
dicts by charming Miss Mildred J
Harris, another screen star, of Loa
Angeles.
Tho woolnff under a bunch of
"Coopers" Instead of a moon was
all kept very secret, and his most
intimate friends were as surprised
as any one else when tho news was
mado public recently that Charlie
and Mildred had slipped quietly away
to th houso of R. S. Sparks, head
of tho Loa Angeles County Llcensa
Bureau, and had been married by
the Rev. James L Meyers,,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1920-08-29/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Charlie Chaplin in a Care-Free, Gay S
having Just the Way He Did Not,
Says, So Far as She Was Conce
NO recent case of broken romance and
once fond hearts estranged has created
such Interest as the suit for
y divorce by Mrs. Charlie Chaplin against
her husband, the world famous funny man
of the motion pictures. The charges
i brought by Mrs. Chaplin are "mental cruelty"
and failure of her husband to provide
for her. /
Among the millions whom Charlie Chaplin
has made laugh there l'"ve probably
been msnv. wl'o hove thou?V*. how carefree
and amusing the lot of the woman
vas his wire. No wcma'.i, It would
could ever have the toluss or be
'ig but cheerful with so m.rthi~
a companion. Yet strangely
rre are no sadder, more posai'?
than the professional humorni
to use up all their store of
* n ;r output. And, according to
"u. Charlie Chnnlln w.13 no exI?
?. ?ho t?lls What she alleges
1 it di1' story of her life with the
.! 11 on earth?so far as the
< r >uo?rncd.
1 ir.ilin has denied all that Mrs.
^ charges in her suit, and has ex
d bhn elf as being much surprised
r d c'slon to force the Issue. He will,
i jai,:, bring counter suit against her on
j _vanccr of his own, and Incidentally al)
ges that, despite her charge of penury,-"
lie spent over 160,000 In about eighteen
months in housekeeping expenses, although
during that time Mrs. Chaplin herself
was earning $1,000 a week.
By Mr*. Charlie Chaplin
(In an interview) <
I AM quite ready to admit that my marriage
to Charlie Chaplin was a mistake.
It was a mistake on his part, because
he is a genius, and geniuses should not
I knarry. He would better be free and remain
free, for he will make any 'woman he
marries miserable, I know. J
I We have been married for three years.
Tor two of those years we lived under the1
! same roof, more or less. That Is, if greeting
a husband after long disappearances
might be said to be living under t^e same
L [roof with him.
I If lying awake, weeping and wondering
where your husband is, until 4 or 6 o'clock
in the morning can really be called living.
1 If wrangling over every bill that comes
i in can be called Mving.
If living on the scale of an income of
$250 a week, when your husban<\ earns
$13,000 a week, can be called living.
If having your wardrobe censored and a
standard of two or three dresses and one
hat established may be considered an existence.
If being told to Keep your head down
to that no man will'see your face is living. .
Tf hearing that meat and potatoes and
i 'rtdlng are enough for a meal and that
i ?? cream and salads are silly and useless
iiMlv stands for proper living.
V being constantly accused of flirting by
n i'*n who Is causelessly Jealous Is living.
*!', this and more I endured?and for
; v? vn months. That Is the reason I hesit?te
?o .'ay that we lived under the same
, f. Tt wasn't living. It was perdition
f- ?.
U lias been said that a comedian Is only
! i ,iy in public, I believe It. In fact, 1
,< .W It. Chsrlle Chaplin, who has made
ruil'lons laugh, only caused me tears.
So It was better that we should separate,
'letter that there be a divorce. 1 have
KPsn htm since my suit for divorce began.
We met in the office of my lawyer in L-os
When we parted he said: "Mildred, you
are right I should never have married.
I know It now. Yon probably will marry
soon. If rou do I hope you will be happy.
I shall never marry again " And we
looked at each other sadly?a funny man
and his wife.
That the public may not be misled by
strange, false rumors I will tell for once
nnrt finally, unless I tell It In court, the
strty of th? fttnny man who cou,d y
ma is hU wife cry.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1920-12-19/ed-1/seq-36/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Charlie Chaplin in CI
I T was n odd match when the news
leaked out that Charlie Chaplin, fun
niest comedian in the motion picture
world, had married Mildred llarris whose
film specialty is tears, "sob stuff." And
the news of the marriage 'was soon follow
ed by whispers that the funny man bride
groom was not getting on very well with
the tearful bride.
Nobody seemed to know jti~t what was
the matter but in due time Mrs. Chaplin
admitted that she and her husband had
separated. Then followed several state
ments from Mrs. C'haplin but no comments
came ifom Mr. Chaplin.
At last the 'matrimonial troubles drifted
into the Los Angeles courts. Mrs. (Chap
Iun brought suit for divorce. And here on
this page is the sworn testimony given by
Mildred liarris Chaplin in support of her
plea for a divorce. Mr. Chaplin did, not
tak9 the trouble to appear at the trial and
Ch lie (Chaplin's version of the matter is
not on record.
W~hen the case was called recently be
fore Judge York Mrs. Chaplin took the
..uness stand in her own behalf. Ii.
tt
IoyMod
boy efMouscoedan
DIRECT EXAMINATION.
QUESTION BY LAWYER GILBERT.
State your namd in full, please.
ANSWER BlY MRS. MILDRED HARRIS
CHIAPLN-Mildred Harris Chaplin.
QU'ESTION.-How old are you, Mrs.
Chaplin?
ANSWER-Nineteen.
Q.-How long have you been living in
California?
A.---Since I wgs seven years old.
Q.-When were you married?
A.-October 23, 1918.
Q.--When did you and Mr. Chaplin be
come separated, finally?
,A.-A year ago this comigg February.
Q.-Were there any children by this
marriage?
A-One boy.
Q.-ls it living or dead?'
A.-Dfead.
(Q -You say you were married when you
j ,.. s.eneen years of ae?
fred Harris's Si
that time
A.-My other
Q.-idsh kep oucostatl4ude
her cre?
A. - hed .
Q-twstecureo odc
whc ormte urudtwr o n
had a teahe for me
Q.-Wht ha bente gnraod
tio ofyu.hat veic, hte
wasdnot ver srong whenI wS marr
Q.--u mn byChaplouhaenee
A.-Yes.
Q.-tutimrs teamn twr
A.-Mey moteetadr ey.oey
Q.-How ohd keep yo. Cnhapnt uthe
tihe arr d ou
Q.-You aege ourse coanuta
whicthe yourstero pfurse toard yofter
yoawre argryand yarraeduatkep
an mterst. A twhoae kugetinnastht
A-Mor. Chadawanen'mst
Q.-Dliad hated io ny meason fiur.
whn accoun twlv proesoldrao and te
her areacohe for nom areo.el e
Q.-Yout aeen your comgena ad
fiour ofks you heaheve sie. whithspl
ofv lnever bnter riblypr stron. aut el
thae hadr abu fe thelaotl. esbt ee
veryserous foutridek, of perhaet fever.le
was, notery wetwrn mared I was arre.
Q.-Dyou go? ythtyuhaebe
A.-Yes.
Q.-Yuu t hern ,te mrrag became
A -Veryseta.vr oey
irprising Stor3
e Famous Fihn
R4
LMOST
flattered
wife of
could sle hope i
pects--such a ric
fagnous husband
And such fun i
dian around the'
half a dollar or :
for half an hou
his fun making,
have him all to I
Think of it!
To be the bri
man in the worlk
ing till night, to
his stunts in her
Would he hoo
ankle with that
squash pie in hei
the door on h
friends wondere
to-be was sure I
the rough stuff
little wife. Of c
id
Charlie.
Q.--Now. after the marriage becam4
public. Mrs. Chaplin, just tell the court ii
~nur own way about the course of treat.
ment Mr. Chaplin adopted toward yoi
after that time?
A.--Well, after I was taken out of thi
hospital I had to stay in bed until Christ
mas, Christmas Eve, and the doctor sent
a nurse home with me, and Msr. Chaplli
got us a home up in 4,aughlin Park, and
lad (po stay in bed until Christmas Eve
and that was the first tim9 I was dowil
after I got out of the hospital. .And
(Christmas afternoon-! mean the day be
fore Christmas, Mr. Chaplin told me that
he would be home and have dinner with
me and help me trim the Christmnas tree,
and I had had mother get all the Christ.
man presents. I was not able to get ui
and I had always thought a great deal of
Chirstmas, and- that evening. I dressed and
went downstairs and waited for him, and
hIe did( not come home. And I waited until
11 o'clock. and he did not come, so I trim.
med the tree and mother helped me and
then I went to bed and stayed awake unti
about two or tlpree, and Mr.' Chaplin came
hiome about three o'clock.
Q.--What occurred?
A --And when he came home he came
utpstairs and was very angry at me for
b'uyirig so many Christmasapresents and
making~ such a time lover Christmas.
Q.-Then what occurred?
A-Then the next day was C'hristmam
D~ay, and he would '?ot get up all Christmna'
morning, and I went downstairs and took
him uip his presents and he was very angry
at me for making so much over Christmas.
Q.-What would he say? What did hi
bay?
A.--Well, he said it was very foolish
and that he did not believe in such thing'
and that I should not be so silly over
C'hristmas and over having presents and
liking such things.
Q.-Now, then, you allege that after that
Christmas evening he began a course of
conduct toward you of absenting himmell
frum home. Tell the court about that.
A-In February the doctor said I had to
go up to Mt. I owe for my health. I kepi
of Her Domes
Comedian WI
scent Divorce
iford from Mr.
on His Side of
ny young woman would be Harris a
to be invited to become the Last Oct
Charlie Chaplin. Where twenty-i
o find more attractive pros- The a
;h, amiable, entertaining and Judge 7
as he was certain to be? story of
to have this inimitable come- part of I
house! If it was well wortl; divorce.
nore to sit in a tleatre chair lin woul,
-and watch "photographs of. of a br
what would it be worth to after th
terself all the time? What a
Charlie
de of the merriest, funniest Christn
1! All day long, from morn- Some zi
have Charlie Chaplin doing And i
6wn home. -but th
k her around the neck or her ed that
busy cane of his, or land a own woi
face at dinner time, or slam testimo
er fingers? Miss Harris's low on I
d about that, biut the bride. s Unfer
he comedian would cut out was not
at home and with his own made hil
ourse he would I So Mildred it to the
getting wors And worse and I couldn't
eat, so the doctor sent me up to' Mt. Lowe.
Q.-Ygu were in bad shape physically at
that time, as I understand,it?
A.-Yes, sir.
Q.-9go ahead.
A-l went to Mt. Lowe and Mr. Chaplin
ould not ith =' e said he had to
g aw I*= aWd 11d to be away from
me, for a while. I beWd him to go with
me, ,but he would not go, so he went to
Coronado.
Q.-With whom?
A.- th 18 secretary, and stayed down
there a fiew "ye.
Q-Abo three weeks, you say?
A.-Ae stayed a few days, and then he
came back to his house. I could not stand
it say longer. so I went down to the city
to ask hib if he would come up with me
to Mt. Lowe for one day, and he said he
would not came.
, Q.-Ne said he would not come?
A.-Tes. So I took quite ill and threat
mend to do everything In the world If he
would not come up with me one day, so
he went up with me for one day and said
he had to go right down; that he could
just stay that day.
Q.-He got up there at what time in the
morning?
A.-He went up in the evening and he
went down the next morning.
Q.-Then how long before you saw him
the next time?
A.-Then he went back to Coronado.
Q.-Well, how long did he remain there?
A-He stayed a couple of weeks.
Q.-Were you Ill all the time you were
at Mt. Lowe?
A.-Yes.
Q.-Who was with you?
A.-Mother was with me.
Q.-Now, on this Qhristmas evening you
have told about, the first Christmas even
Ing after your marriage In October, you
had invited your friends there to the
house, had you?
A.-No, I had not; Mr. Chaplin bad all
his own friend.; he did not want me to
have mine.
,Q.-Then, you allege, that he came home
about what time on Christmas morning?
A-It was about two-thirty or three.
Q.-Two-thirty or three. Then nal
Christmas morning what occurred?
A-He stayed in bed all day until four
o'clock; he wouldn't go down stairs with
me to pee the tree. I took him his
presents.
Q.-Did he abuse you?
A-He was very angry at me for mak
ing so much over Christmas
Q.-What did he say?
A-He said It was very foolish an,1
wasn't right to make so much or for me
to like presents and foolish thing.; that
it was not his idea to have Christmas or
celebrate Christmas; he had never done It.
Q.-You allege in your complaint that
you had always had girl friends of ap
proximately your own age as companions?
A-Yes, sir.
Q.-What condition existed after you
were parried with reference to whether
or no~ he would permit your tiends to
come and visit you?
A-He did not like them: he didn't
think that I should see them; he thought
I should like hi. frend. and be more
studious.
Q.-What did he say or do with refer'
once to your friends V he should find them
in his house or the house, what was his
conduct toward them?
A-He was uot nice to them; he
wouldn't come home if I bad them.
Q.-When you had your frends he would
refuse to come to the house if he found It
out?
A.-Ya., air.
tic Life.
ich Won Her
but Not a
0
Chpin
It AU
-ried him. If was two years. ago
s. She was seveuseen, he was
nas.
ther day, in a Los Angeles court,
rk listened to Mrs. Chaplin's sworn
how the great comedlian.played the
sband-and gave Mrs. Chaplin her
It was expected that Charlie Chap
I be a very original and unusual sort
degrom. He was. Two months
ey were married Christmas came.
Drt of frolic would you imaginl
Chaplin would think up for hig
a celebration with his young bride?
we1y, some surprise of course.
was an entirely unexpected surpried
s unique way the comedian celebrat
Christmas is told in Mrs. Chaplin's
1 as given in the transcript of the
y at her divorce trial printed be.
his page.
sately, Charlie Chaplin himself
present in court to explain what
n play the part as his wife described
judge.
Q.-Haw oftea did that occur, Mrs.
Chaplin?
A.-All the time; he would never tell me
when he would be home; he said he had to
be free to live his own life and do as he
plealed.
Q.-Now, on that Christmas did he give
you any present or token of any kind?
A.-No.
Q.-Was he earning money in consider
able amount at that time?
A.-Yes, sir.
Q.-He made you no present whatever?
A.-No, sir.
Q.-What was your condition at that
time of your trip to Mt. Lowe?
A.-I was expecting to be a mother.
Q.-And he knew that?
A.-Yes, sir.
Q.-At that time did you have a contract
with the Universal Film pompany for your
services?
A.-I did.
Q.-Tell the court about that with refer
cnce to his insisting on your working when
you were unable to work?
A.-Well, when we %rere married Mr.
Chaplin told me he wanted me to break
the contract with the Pniversal, because
he did not want me iorking with them.
So, when I was in the hbspital, after I was
first taken ill, I sent a written notice that
I would not be with them any more and I
was under age. My lawyer told me we
could break the contract. Then, in Feb
ruary. when I came back from Mt. Lowe.
they had been sendjag me my check each
-:eek, and I had been sending them back
and they would return them again, but I
had not cashed any. In February a friend
of mine, Miss Bweet, asked me to go to
New York with her when I came back
from Mt. Lowe, and Mr. Chaplin had been
away so long, and when he came back he
said it would do me good to go to New
York, so I wentt with her. But he wouldn't
give me but $150.'and when I got East r
bought a lot of baby clothes ad some baby
furniture and a few other things, and I did
not have enough money and I wired for
more money. But he would not send me
any more, so I wired mother to please
ash one of my checks.
Q.--That 'was the check that would re
a-dirm your contract irith the Universal
-eople, which he advised you to break?
A-Yes, sir.
Q.-Did you advise him with reference
to your circumstances?
A-Yes.
Q.-DId you advise him that you expect
ed to purchase some furniture for the ex
pected child?
A-Yes, sir.
Q.-And he declined to send you any
money at all?
A.-Yes.
Q.-And he was making apozimately
16,000 or I7,000 a month at that time?
A.-More than that.
Q.-You mentioned the furniture. You
say there was an arrangement made about
snme turniture for the baby's room?
A.-BDefore I went East Mr. Chaplin said
Icould get a set of furniture for my room
un in our home, because it was very dark.
Q.-That was the room in which you
were to be confined?
A.-Yes, sir; my own roem. So. ?
hoght it at Beriker Crothers, end when !
got back from he . York the room was all
=urnished in thE aew furniture, ad he
took me up to see it, and I was very happy
about it aid he seemed to be quite pleased.
but when the bfll came he refused to pay
it. He said it was too expeasive and tat
Ishould send it back.
Q--Did you send It back?
A.-No, sir.
Q.-What did you de?
(Oontinseed on Neat Pugf)</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1921-08-31/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Charlie Chaplin Proclaims
In the Matrimonial Market Again
In 3-Minute Hot Weather Interview
HQ' l:LXvs Irf '5
Comedian Strategically Shy on
Most Questions, but Vents
Some Positive Opinions
Doesn't Know What Sort of
Woman He Likes Best and
Would .Rather Read Hamlet
Than Play It.
By Mar giteriteMooersMar shall
Charlie Chaplin, tho playboy of the
movies, Charlie of the funny feet, the
trained mustache, the Incredible head
gear, handles ,a three-minute Inter
view with all the care he does NOT
bestow on oustard pics and cops.
Charlie is ever so polite about it, mit
nevertheless he acts as It he thought
The Evening World's hot weather
test In mental speed were a bomb of
some sort that might go off in his
hands.
When I saw the brown-eyed, debo
nair, soft-voiced little comedian in the
theatre lobby Just after the rehearsal
of the next release of his friend Mary
Pickford and Just before the showing
of the newest picture of his friend
Douglas Fairbanks, he leaned against
the wall for support, wiggled his fin-
gers nervously and took his full three tatlon. although you'd think him quail
minutes to nnswer the fifteen qucs- fled to answer this one) Make them
Hons I had prepared.
.
viwot TiTirrTP
rjiioj juinvj u,
Gains on Schedule, but Parries Most
Thrusts.
It was exactly 17 minutes past 1
when I asked:
Q. No. 1 What Is It that makes you
so funny?
Charlie Chaplin (grinning bashfully.
60 that he showed most of his very
hlto and even teeth, and looking orr
into space, somewhere over my left
shoulder) I don't know ask tho kids.
Q. No. 2 Ought movie salaries to
go down?
Charlie Chaplin (straightening his
drooping shoulders, an Indignant In
flection In the soft voice) Certainly
not!
Q. No 3 Is the Rolshevlk Govern
ment going to last In Russia?
Charlie Chaplin I do not know.
Q. No. 4 Why don't you want to
marry again?
Charlie Chaplin (who was recently
quoted as saying that he didn't, but
who seoms to have changed his mind
girls, here's your chance!) Who
says that I don't? Quoting me to that
effect was a ralBtafce. I certainly do
want to marry again very much!
Q. No. 5 What sort of woman do
you like best?
Charlie Chaplin (again grinning em.
barrasscdly and tying his fingers Into
bowknots) Now, that's hard to an
swer; I really couldn't say; I couldn't
even tell whether she's blond or bru
nette; I couldn't answer that.
Q. No. 6 Are you In favor of an
Irish republic?
Charlie Chaplin (determinedly play
ing safe) I prefer to be discreet and
not commltmyself.
The first minute was gone and we
were one answer ahead of the avcrago
called for by the tlmo schedule.
SECOND MINUTE.
Slows Down His Ansuers, but UoUls
to Schedule.
Q. No. 7 Should women smoke
cigarettes?
Charlie Chaplin (hesitating, Hps
moving nervously, then smiling dlplo-
vicw to obtaining an Increase In
fares. Nathan Kushncr, No. 1057
Simpson Street, former Interborough
guard, said that while there was no
official union statement showing that
the company was back of the strike.
It was freely passed from one em
ployee to another that tho company
was going bankrupt and that the
only chance for employees to get a
pay increase was to help tho company
obtain a ten-cont fare which tho
company would share.
Commissioner Hirsuficld said that
the Interborough receivership move
In designed to got an Increased fare.
Tho Transit Commission, ho said,
fears to gTant an Incrcaso for political
reasons. If tho company gots a
"friendly receiver, ns in tho cose of
the D. It. T.," ho predicted, "It will
separate its elevated and subway
systoms, doing away wlln transfers,
and thus getting the equivalent of a
I fare increase,"
MAKEi VOU FUNHV ?
SHOULD
i AUAt?l C.S GO DOWN r"
i-v-"rwe. QqusHcvik govt.
WHV DONT YOU 'wAKl-r
WOMH bQVQU
LI KB. OE5T ?
DO YOITC.VOR.
WOMEN SfrvlOKC
oovoo itsm-icvi;
wm,t qovoo
DOWITW YOUR
MOM JCV ?
OOV T HEtPTHC
ON EMPI.OVCD?
wi-wr isthc
EVSICtTr WAV
"TO MAKE PEODLE
IAU&H ? it'YOO
JVCRENOT, A. MCVIC
SfAtfc WHAT WOULD
Vvuix-r i - w-.. r: .
THE VOISTKAOIAW,
PIES HAVf
VOU WUINtD IN -YOOCL
CAREER -p
matloully) That depends
woman!
Q. No. 8 Do you believe In national
censorship of the movies? m
Charlie Chaplin (repeating the
question to gain tlmo and thinking
hard) Do I believe In national cen
sorship? Yesif It's intelligent.
Q. No. 9 Whit do you do with all
your money?
Charlie Chaplin (tho hundred candle-power
grin again turned on) Pay
my taxes and spend some now and
then.
Q. No. 10 What should the Govern
ment do to help the unemployed?
Charlie Chaplin (who takes a de
cidedly sorious, non-facellous Interest
in labor and social problems) They
should do a great dcal-so much that
I couldn't begin to cover the subject
een if I todk the whole time you
allow for tho Interview.
Tho second minute was up, and we
had lost our one-answer lead owing
to the comedian's habit of stopping to
think before he spoke.
THIRD MINUTE.
Finishes Exactly on Time and Seems
Glad It's Ocer.
Q. No. 11 What is the easiest way
to make people laugh?
Charlie Chaplin (with modest hesl-
nappy. I guess uui someutxiy eiso
could answer that question a good
de-'11 better than 1.
Q. No. 12 If you weie not a movie
star, what would you like to be?
Charlie Chaplin (with a quiet
chuckle) Night watchman.
Q. No. 13 Hqw many custard pies
have you ruined since tho beginning
of your career a million?
Charlie Chaplin Oh, not as many
as that. Say a. thousand!
Q. No. 14 What is your
opinion of the Volstead act?
Charlie Chaplin (the laugh
candid
In
ins
eyes, as well as on his lips, and look
ing me straight In the face for almost
' the first time during the Interview)
Of the Volstead act? You must ex
cuse me I don't use such language!
Q. No. 15 When ate you going to
play Hamlet?
Charlie Chaplin 'although this role
is said to bo his dearest ambition)
I'd rather read It. What I really want
in my future work is to do as I please
to follow my own whim!
The interview and the three minutes
were over. Charlie seemed glad the
bomb had not exploded!</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024827/1921-10-02/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHARLIE CHAPLIN WRITES HIS IMPRESSIONS ' OF AMERICA
V'
" '4
i
1
' t
J
W "'T K V
L
T
Famous Movie Comedian says
London He Knew as Boy
Does Not Exist Now
BY CHARLIE CHAPLIN
LONDON, Oct. 1. I always figure
America under the symbol of youth
vigorous, aggressive, full of hope and
pen. courageous, and with the sun
light of the morning shining in its
eyes.
I find England more like a serene
old age mellowed by time, softened
ly suffering, wise from long experi
ence and with the. afterglow of the
westering sun in its eyes.
America, like all youth, has a core
of hardness in its heart.
England, like all mellowed old age
has a core of tenderness in its heart.
I should say America for work,
England for thoughtful contempla
tion and dreams. ,
Of course, I know England is one of
the mightiest nations in the world;
that its hardy sons rule an empire;
that they sail all seas and traffic In
all markets. But I am merely trying
to give my own impressions, to tell
how the two countries 'affect me.
I don't think I could do much work
in England. Everything Is so finish
ed, so settled, so restful that it would
simply absorb' me.
America Is Restless
nut there Is in America a feeling of
the unfinished, of restlessness that
ius. makes one want to get up and do
thjngs. That is why I am going back
In a few weeks.
It's all very nice to say that Chap
lin brings laughter to men, but the
truth is that Chaplin is working for
his bread and cheese just like the
rest of you. There is not much fun
jn loafing too long.
' I have been rediscovering England
for myself aiyl contrasting my Im
pressions of America and also with
my memeories of the England I knew
as a boy.
' I came to America when I was 18
und In the past 14 years have only
been back home once. .
My best experience has been to ram
ble around the streets in the poor
sections of London that I 'used
know. I found in the mean streets
something very lovely, something spir
itunl. I nian as regards the people.
There they were, living in misera
ble ( tenements, their faces thin and
pinehed from poor food, and yet there
w something very beautiful in their
eye.
I. have never seen anything sweeter
than the expression in the face of a
girl out walking with her coster Tcrer.
I began to understand how these
poor people had suffered during the
long years of the war and how thev
had found the pluck to do it. and 1
saw the mak rit had left on them. It
was saddening as well as beautiful to
get these -revelations.
Had "Emotional Jag"
Then I had an emotional jag. I
prowled these poor streets in search
or a wistful little bov I used to know
a little, ill-dressed, rather fright
ened Charlie Chaplin.
Somehow. I couldn't quite catch up
with him. The streets all seemed nar
rower to me than they did to that
little chap, and the crowds not quite
so big and bustling, and the policemen
not quite so terrifying.
1
N
I
. it I
-3- Vy :
i
, ' "ft:
4 V;
CHARLIE CHAPLIN . ,
But I did see something we haven't
got in America. eaw the mark Iof
class distinction. The population In
England Is really subdivided into real
classes and castes. And being a very
I old civilization and a very crowded
country, it is hard for a man to get
ou of his class.
We have none of that in America.
The workman of today still has the
chance to be the captain of, industry
of tomorrow. Why, the poor editor of
yesterday is the president of today!
America" is still in thd construction
stage. She is not finished. That i
why the builders, who are at work on
the structure today, should be so very
careful.
It seems to me, looking back
across the waters and across time,
that America Is in a very critical pe
riod. 1
Finance is once, more in danger of
falling into the 1 bands of the few we
always call "Wall Street."
And finance is adapting a taa Intol
erant attitude toward labor. Labor
should not be -asked to do all the giv
ing un. Finance should give up a lit
tle, also."
There is a danger that if there is
too much clash, a class feeling will
develon which would be entirely un
American. Too Much Organization
I think "another danger to America
is the number 'of organizations which
are growing up which are anti-some-bodyq,
anti-some religion or race or
creed or free expression of thought.
America can learn a lesson in this
regard from old England. There is
far greater personal liberty and far
greater iibertv of speech in England
than in America. .
Since havle been over here I have
seen it stated that I am a deep reader
and that I am a Socialist. I would
like to deny both statements. I am
not a highbrow. I don't pretend to
be. My only pretension is to be an
rtist. I don't mix in, politics. And
I am nol immersed in economic litera
tu. " . " .. i
I am neither, a Socialist 'nor a par
lor Bolshevik. But I believe with all
mv heart in social reform. I believe
very strongly in municipal ownership
of public utilities. I believe in the
nationalization of the railways and
probably of coai mines. ,
In 20 years one. million,. eight hun
dred and eighty-three thousand homes
have been broken up in the United
States by divorce courts. '
I (V
Mm IWii ,
B8!d Witesa Frodk? '
A "Betty Wales" label means so" much !
It's the unconditional guarantee that the style
is correct, fabric of the finer quality, workman
ship unfailingly perfect.
Mingled in the ultra gathering at tea hour
or, perhaps, strolling along Main Street,
you'll see women - wearing "Betty Wales"
Frocks. Each model is different wonderfully
smart and chic, . ,
Look for the "Betty Wales" in our window
There is one "made for you."
50
Douglas</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1922-04-16/ed-1/seq-61/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Charlie Chaplin; the Man
By Everett Dean Martin
Social Psychologist, Director Cooper Union Forum of the People's
Institute, and d of "The Behavior of Crowd$."
_ ??Te \pro.\p r\y Charlie Chaplin.
>ffv ?,;;,,. b Harper * Bret %
' \ i THINK ove: te Chaplin
,% en, it strikes
^Ja that the essential ele
X -* ment in them is not the
thrown m the dice or the clown
tics. I dent believe that these
is? Ivea would have
Charlie his almost universal
"^ai In hi? autobiographical book.
;8,t published, "My Trip Abroad." there
rj revealed another quality which, on
?-.l'.ysis is the thing that constitutes
?pea! on the screen. There's a
human Sympathy coupled with a
umor, and this humor
. after ? :. ?". psychological compensa
?on for something which lies much
?fcpt
1 . yov.-, here is the thing - Charlie
lim ' ,n uniforT,l!y aPP??r? on the
;? .e? as a vagabond adventurer. He's
Byway? on the outside looking in. n
? ?eotly figure, undignified, ridiculous,
;3 a world rires?=cd tin and formal. This
garla is presented partly as a joke on
hm, ar.d in the end the situation is
reversed and the joke is on the eonsti- j
tated order of things. In every one of
i .5 there is this hidden scamp hero with
whom Chaplin identifies himself and
with whom the world of respectabilities
??nd conventionalities is in conflict.
Chaplin expresses for us an imaginary
escape from this conflict and he does
it by resolving it into a joke.
? ? a
rpHERE are people who are suffering !
asid lonely and defeated who save ?
their ?elf-feel ng with just this sort of
homer directed at themselves. The
profotindtst humor in this world al?
ways has a touch of the pathos of a
man^i struggle with his r:te. The es
tablir-hod ord - of things forced on
us all rcmaii tact. Chaplin doesn't
ap?it ? order of things,
? f ; idiculous he> ?g
aSi? at tief- same time to preserve thai
Mtablisl and kei p alive that
in hin -? ??; v hicli is in con
Sict with '?'?? by making it, aiso. ridicu
[oqI. B that kind is what
psych i ? ' ?'? fi nee mechan
iim. It show! that with all our obeli
ID? md conformit/1 to established
imething in us which
is in this world but not of it. Chaplin
bowl this secret and reveals it in
Iiiis hook.
Gar!...' Chaplin's book is from the
psychological angle a remarkable hu?
man document, greatly because of this
revelation. It explains the appeal of
this poor little feeble creature on the
outglde of the great big world. To the
reade?r unversed in psychology the
outstanding features of the book are
likely to be the triumphant return of
Charlie Chaplin to the land of his birth
his meetings with the great in poli?
tics and letters his sympathy for the
unfortunate his intimate confessions
of his likes and dislikes. However, the
real revelation lies in Charlie's visits
to the haunts of his childhood.
Trio whole tone of the book is that
of a half lonely ?'dventurer visiting the
scene:; of his early 1 i fr. reacting with
genuine sympathy to every situation.
We learn of Chaplin's early experi?
ence as a little ragged urchin. On top
of that, experience has been imposed
this magical thing- for his succ?s?? has
been like an Arabian Nights fantasy?
and 1 doubt if he has ever quite real?
ized tha' ?t vvas he who has had it.
This little ragged urchin has stayed
v.ith Chaplin all his life and is the
main reason for his tremendous hu?
man appeal.
? ? ?
OUR or five years ago ?ome neigh?
bor child came rushing to me, all
out of breath. She was all excited, for
she was going to the Hippodrome to see
"Charlie Chaplin himself.'' ?
At thar time "Charlie Chaplin him-'
self didn't mean any more to me than !
Charlie in the, movies. But after read?
ing his book T feel that I do know
Charlie Chaplin himself. In another
age. where he would have had to ap
pear directly in person before his
audiences, the chances are that the
personal side of his art would have
been more evident to the people, who
are rather inclined to look down on
the movies, anyhow, and who have re?
garded Charlie Chaplin merely as a
comedian who makes lots of money.
The motion picture ,is a medium of
expression is a syndicate sort of thing.
It takes a tremendous amount of per?
sonality to overcame the?" difficulties.
] !. ? crowds who have bce'n rooting for
Chaplin have been psychologically cor?
rect. 'While he has an enormous popu?
larity, he doesn't make an appeal to
the crowd mind, but rather a secret
h -?stance to civilization which is in us
nil. and he does it because at heart he
is really the littlo ragged ur?jhin?the
vagabond adventurer.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024827/1922-09-17/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WHO WILL BE NEXT BRIDE OF
CHARLIE CHAPLIN? RUMOR SAYS
LILA LEE TO WED COMEDIAN
EM
- " -
- ' -
TO
FULFILLTREATV,
DECLARES
Air Over Orient Is Rapidly
Clearing, Says Secretary
of Navy on Return
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 1C. How
do the Oriental political skies seem
to the eyes of the secretary of the
navy?
Edwin Denby, back from a wide sur
vey made unofficially but neverthe
less thoroughly, says he "is convinced
that the Japanese will sincerely ful
fill all obligations of the four power
treaty." He talked freely and frankly
"And naval disarmament there?"
he was asked?"
"Japan has not yet scrapped a
ship," replied the secretary. "But
neither have we. There is nothing
threatening about that. It is not to
be expected that any guns will b
spiked until the treaty has been rat
ified all around. Our navy will not
(Continned on Page Two)
LILA LEE (CENTER), PEGGY JOYCE (LOWER LEFT) AND CHAR
LIE CHAPLIN- '
LOS ANGELES, Sept. 16. Will
Lila Le be the next Mrs. Charlie
Chaplin?
This . question is frequent 'in
Hollywood following announce
ment by Mildred Harris, former
wife of the world famous film
comedidh. that such was the ru
mor amongst those "in the know"
in filmland.
Among those who have nothing
to say about the rumors are
Charlie and Lila Lee.
The former Mrs. Chaplin, in
telling of the Lila Lee-Charlie
Chaplin reports, took occasion to
announce that Peggy .Joyce, for
merly speculated upon as the fut
ure Mrs. Chaplin, was no longer
considered as a possible bride for
Charlie." ' ' ' r
About this Charlie also says
nothing so you can do your own
guessing.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-08-05/ed-1/seq-20/ocr/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHARLIE CANT GO NEAR THE WATER
Mabel Normand and Charlie Chaplin in a little off-stage comedy stuff
Charlie thought he would take a dip; Mabe! thought he wouldn't that's
ali. Until recently those two were team-mates in the Keystone comedies.
Now Chaplin is working with the Essanay company and the laugh-provoking
antics Of these two will no longer shake tne sides of those who watcl
for Keystone releases,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1923-02-25/ed-1/seq-61/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PolaN^ri'sliusbandto Duelwith
Count Dombski Insists That djjfiL Charlie BJL
Pola Is Still His Wife and ’ ZV f _«..
He Will Hold Charlie • 'UXQIdIIR• '
to Account on the'- .
Field of Honor -
J. . S<\ ‘ •
Nevaire shall Charlie Chaplin marry Pola Negri—«
she is my wife. A divorce? I know nothing of it and
I do not recognize such a document if it exists.
I will see for myself what is in all this talk from
America. And if I find that Charlie Chaplin would
marry my wife—ha! Then will I speak to- him as a
man of honor speaks on such affairs; through the
mouth of my second, as you call them in your country.
A duel it shall be. The man who takes my wife shall
answer to me with the sword!— Says Count Dombski,
who insists that he is the husband of Pola Negri,
V
Im *1
IBPgy- I
ii vhHb
iNB ' '
11
■F w..
I ■ ■
j ■■
■K> 1
*J
r ? BbKI
V/ ' -"' >*
~ ■!'■<*
The Inimitable Charlie Chaplin and His
Very Handy Cane.
V* “ <n 1 ml
<==s3 ,<=>
■Mb " ’WMMjIL
B- » Kh 1
■ /fc L I fl BbL m Br Ilb
Bk 1 '
H fl f o BB \
fl ni fl ... e* s
>< ■BrfW r
fl I lW fl
EjftmKß BRB BBsk«—
**l repeat,
*1 am free, free
£o marry the man
of my choice/ M
Cried Pola Negri in Tragic Earnestness.
SCARCELY two years since Charlie Chaplin
was divorced from Mildred Harris, is
wife, and now his new romance wi
German-Pole film star, Pola Negri, is clou e
with trouble.
The Polish nobleman, Count Dombski, has
heard the news where he happens now to be in
England and has announced that Pola Negri is
still his wife and that Charlie Chaplin must face
him in a duel if he dares to marry Pola Negri.
It would be a strange sight if the motion
picture audiences could see the fiery Count
Dombski rush forward, sword in hand, to make
the great film comedian answer to him on the
field of honor. But the threatened duel is hardly
likely to happen where the movie cameras can photograph it.
x Charlie Chaplin is very handy with that cane of his. Is it
possible that Mr. Chaplin would take a humorous view of the
wild-eyed Polish Count and would give him a lesson in fencing
with his cane? z ~
The film audiences have seen Mr. Chaplin wiggle away from
all sorts of threatening situations and,-again and again, that
handy cane has tripped up policemen and detectives and big
bullies. But that was on the screen. What would Charlie do
rn a real life encounter with Count Dombski and his sharp-edged
S "°ln the recent news from the interesting lovers Pola Negri
has sebmed to be rather more demonstrative than Mr. Chaplin.
The expressions that have come from the comedian have seemed
to be rather conservative, as if, perhaps, he had some anxieties
or misgivings in the back of his nead. Has Charlie Chaplin re
ceived a warning that he will be held to account on the field of
honor if he takes Pola Negri as a bride?
Pola Negri is a very attractive woman, and it is not surpris
ing that a man who was lucky enough to once possess her would
fight valiantly not to lose her. Very little has been revealed as
to the exact facts of Pola Negri’s marriage to Count Dombski, or
just when, where, and under what circumstances the divorce
was secured which Pola Negri relies upon to make it possible
for her to marry Charlie Chaplin.
But the interview quoted above with Count, Dombski was
secured by a British newspaper, and if Count Dombski makeg
good his threat to come to America and require an accounting
at the hands of Charlie Chaplin, a very interesting situation
will develop.
Whether Count Dombski is now cn his way to America to
settle things with the film comedian and his runaway wife has
not been announced. It is possible that Count Dombski may
be arranging his affairs in a leisurely manner and may not
arrive until after the marriage takes place.
Whatever Count Dombski may be planning to do, there is
.... 1... * <<»..» 1.. t
BmOBNB W' w Srw
I" ' *
The Languishing Eyes of the German-Pole Film Star, Pola
Negri, Who Insists She Is Free to Marry Charlie
Chaplin, Although Count Dombski Asserts
That She Is Still His Wife.
little doubt that the Polish nobleman is a man of vigorous per
sonality and violent manner. He is an excellent swordsman and
a very good shot with the pistol.
Pola Negri herself, in telling of her romance and carriage
to Count Dombski, explains that he was so violently opposed to
having his wife continue working in the studios that he forbade
her to go on with her contracts with the Berlin movie producers.
“The parting of the ways came one night a few months
.after we were married,” she said, “when I was making one of
my periodic stays at Count Dombski’s castle at Sassnowiece, in
Poland. A telegram arrived about midnight, calling me back to
the Berlin studio, and when I showed it to my husband he flew
into a violent rage.
“Drawing his revolver, he told me that if I left for Berlin
it would be over his dead body. Knowing how he felt about the
matter, I recalled that the climax had been reached and that he
might do something desperate. So I told him 1 would remain.
“But that night, after he had gone to sleep, I got up and
dressed and, taking only such clothes as I could carry in my
arms, I left the castle, never to return.
“How I reached the railway station at Sassnowiece after my
escape is still a mystery to me. I must have walked and run
miles in the darkness. But my mind was made up—my career
came first, cost what it may. And, as luck would have it, there
was a train for Berlin almost ready to depart when I arrived
at the station —the spot where our romance had begun nearly
a year before.” ...
The lady who says she is no longer Countess Dombski, and is
eager to be Mrs. Charles Chaplin, is most emphatic on the
points at issue between her and the Count. “I deny that I
am the wife of the Count, and I challenge him to try to assert
his supposed rights in any court in the world. I have the
proper decree dissolving the marriage,” she insists.
“I am told that it is in proper form in all respects, and
that there is nothing to bind me to the Count. I am as free
as ever I,was, and he cannot stop me marrying the man of
Great Britain Bights Uesrrved.
jHL j@ jfl
m mi_ A fflulOw IfflO i wlft Ml
Bl
wwWiWy . ;V WBflL f .x.
»
It Would Bo a Strange Sight If the Motion Picture Audiences Could
See the Fiery Count Domhslri Rush Forward, Sword in Hand, to Make
the Great Film Comedian Answer to Him On the Field of Honor. But .
Charlie Chaplin Is Very Handy With That Cane of His. Perhaps Mr.
Chaplin Would Take a Humorous View of the Wild-Eyed Polish
Count and Would Give Him a Lesson in Fencing With His Cane.
my choice. “I repeat. lam free! free I free! to marry th* ftflHl
of my choice.
“Charlie and I love each other. We are made for eatfl
other, and we intend to seek happiness together < until death '
alone parts us. .Charlie sought me out among the artists of tho
world, and helped me to achieve greater fame than 1 enjoyed
up to then. We found that we were not only soul mates, but
that we had the temperament in our art that made tho one
Tthe complement of the other, and we both think that In associa
tion we can achieve our greatest and best work.”
At Los Angeles she appears everywhere Charlie is to bo
seen, and goes around with the triumphant air of the woman
in possession who will not surrender her rights to the film
artist under any circumstances.
“There is no law that can keep us apart,” she says. “Wo
are masters of. our own fate, and we shall not be prevented
from uniting our lives by ahy one. I love only Charlie in tho
world. He is my ting among men, and I will marry him in
spite of everything and everybody who tries to come between
us all.”
Mr. Chaplin is less defiant, and at times has the appearance
of being uncomfortable under the aggressive manner in which
he is claimed as her- affinity by the lady who seems to have
discovered in him the perfect lover immediately after he found
in her the perfect film star.
Mlle. Pola Negri, when questioned regarding the suggestion
that she as a Roman Catholic could hardly claim the right to
remarry after divorce, replied rather vaguely:
“On that there is a good deal of misunderstanding. I can
only tell you that I have taken the best -advice from legal and
spiritual advisers, and there is no real barrier to our marriage
if we decide to go through with it. •
“Fate brought Charlie and' me into contact, and we should
be foolish to run pway from our happiness decreed by fate.
He was on his way back to America when he was shown a
film in which I appeared.
“He said to,the person who showed the film, ‘Why, this is
the artiste I have been looking for since I first went into the
film business.’ I received a telegram soon after asking if I
would meet him.
“I did not know him except by name, and I did not think
I should like him, so I said ‘No.’ But in spite of that he came
and I realized at once that he was altogether different to what
I had expected, for not only was he a great actor but he was
a real man in every sense of the word.
“I found myself won over by his charming manners, and I
felt that I had at last found the man to whose keeping I could
surrender, my heart, my life, and my future happiness without
hesitation. Working with him makes a great deal of difference
to me.
“I feel that I can give a better expression to my heart
under his eyes, and for his sake I try to surpass anything I
have ever done before. I used to think that Charlie was fust
what you call a clown, with no art and no message, but now I
know that behind his clowning there is a real art and a real
message, if only those who see nis films would understand them.
“Charlie seeks to portray the- life of ‘Les of
the great cities and to arouse the comfortable classes to their
duties and responsibilities to the less fortunate.”
The story of the beginning of the Chaplin-Negri romance
is very interesting.
Charlie was shown some, of the films of the lady in London
and again in Paris. He liked them so well that he must needs
rush to Berlin and then to Vienna to see the artiste for himself.
“A veritable queen of the movies, the most perfect acting
features I ever seen, capable of expressing every con
ceivable shade of emotion with the skill and grace of the true
artiste,” he exclaimed.
These were among the eulogies passed by Charlie on the
lady as an artiste, but later he had something to say of her as
a worn in, as a beauty, and as a charmer of hearts. * She has
all the qualities of form and soul that fit a woman to reign
over the heart of a man and to be his greatest inspiration in
whatever he regards as his life work,” he declared. I
And Pola Negri was no less lavish in what She said of
Charlie. “A man that any woman could love, could work with
as life partner, and feel honored in doing so, finding her true
happiness in association with his life.,” she declared.
“He has the true soul of an artiste and is an ideal lover
with the capacity for making even the most capricious woman
happy,” were among the things she said of him, and after
this semi-public love-making, it was only to be expected that
the rapturous crowds of admirers should be eager to lead the
happy pair to the altar in order that their lives might be united
for better or for worse. . . . ,
Will Count Dombski cool off and let things take their course
or will he turn up in America and ask Charlie Chaplin to meet
him on the field of honor? And then what?
3</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89079026/1916-11-09/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NATIONAL APPLE SHOW
At Spokane Nov. 20 to 25 Will Be
One Round of Hilarity
Spokane, Wash.,, Nov. B.—Starting
off with the famous $20,000 movie
scream “Tillie’s Punctured Romance,”
the free moving picture show at the
National Apple show November 20 to
26 will furnish a continuous round
of hilarity. The management of the
show after weeks of mnegotiations,
letter writing and telegraphing has
booked up the choicest bits of Charley
Chaplin fun and frolic that have ever
been thrown upon a screen, but per
haps the greatest of these will be
“Tillie’s Punctured Romance,” which
will be the big feature opening day
November 20.
This film has been made famous
not only by the tens of thousands
who have laughed at it till their sides
ached, but also by the fact that, if
such a thing is possible, it is the
only film wherein Charley Chaplin
has been out starred, and that by a
mere woman. Charley wouldn’t have
been out shown then if it hadn’t been
that Marie Dressler, who plays the
part of Tillie, resorted to the courts
to recover $20,000 damages for injur
ies to various parts of her anatomy
sustained while depicting Tillie.
But Charley Chaplin will reign su
preme in the National Apple Show
movie. TFor five days this clown of
clowns will cut up capers, but on
Thursday he’ll be driven from the
footlights and then it will be Annette
Kellerman in ‘“Neptune’s Daughter,’
probably the most spectacular piece
ever photographed. This is the film
tbat was made in Bermuda, where the
mermwtids sport in the water, with
its wonderful water scenic effects and
marveious underwater pictures. Run
ning companion to Charley Chaplin
for four days will be two reels of
animated cartoons, with two new reels
each day. This moving picture’ show
will be absolutely free with a com
plete change of program every day.
The program ‘for the Apple Show
week follows:
Monday, November 20th: :
Charley Chaplin and Marie Dressler
in “Tillie’s Punctured Romance.”
Tuesday, November 21st:
Charlie Chaplin in “Work.”
Animated Cartoons.
Wednesday, November 22nd:
Charlie Chaplin in “Shanghaied.”
Animated Cartoons.
Thursday, November 23rd:
Annette Kellerman in ‘“Neptune’s
Daughter.”
Friday, November 24th:
Charlie Chaplin in ‘“Police.”
Animated QCartoons.
Saturday, November 25th:
Charley Chaplin in “Woman, Love
ly Woman.”
Animated Cartoons.
‘Wilfred G. Hannam chairman Apple
Pie giver, who is to have charge of
the free apple pie distribution at the
Ninth National Apple show in Spo
kane, November 20 to 25, walked in
to the office of Gordon C. Corbaley,
manager of the Apple Show.
“I'm getting ready for the apple
pies and I'd like to have a little
appropriation,” remarked Hannam.
“Alright, what do you want?”’ ask
ed Corbaley.
“In the first place I want six tons
of the choicest apples we can get.”
“How much?’ asked Corbaley, as
he leaned back in his chair and star
ed at the prodigal Hannam.
“Six tons, and good ones too,” re
peated Hannam.
“Say, are you trying to put the
whole ‘apple crop of the United Sta
tes into apple pies to be given away?”
asked Corbaley.
“You said a pie for every one who
comes to the show, didn’t you, and
as often as they come?”’ asked Han
nam,
“You bet and that goes, too, even to
babies,” replied Corbaley.
“Well here are the figures,” said
Hannam. “Figure it out yourself.”
Corbaley did. He figured it twice,
because he couldn’t believe it the first
time. When he got through he ac
cepted Hannam’s figures for all the
rest.
“You're right,” he said, as he put
his 0. K. to a voucher that read some
thing like this: ‘
Six tons of choice apples. -
Four tons of flour. :
One and one-half tons of lard.
One half tons of sugar.
Two hundred pounds of salt.
“And all that’s going into. apple
pies and they’ll all be given away at
the Apple Show,” remarked Hannam,
with a chuckle as he walked out. “I
guess it’'ll be some apple pie feed
alright.” . v</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-05-13/ed-2/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ONE OF THE BIG GUNS "IN THE MOVIES
cm&Ejj.av&Lm
Chas. Chaplin, as he looks in real
life and as he appears in his comedy,
"The Champion."
Charley Chaplin is one of the most
favorite stars in the- moving picture
game today. Since the Chaplin fun
ny pictures started appearing on the
screen the young man has been a
huge hit He has appeared in a great
many well written and staged come
dies, among them "The Champion,"
"By the Sea" and "The Jitney Elope
ment" His "By the Sea" has especially
been a laugh producer. There are
enough roars in that picture to sink
a fleet of battleships, as a Chaplin
lover puts it.
Chaplin, with his big feet perform
ing their usual mirth provoking per
ambulations, wanders down to the
sea shore. There is some wind blow
ing, so Chaplin anchors his hat to
his head with a young cable. He
meets 'a pedestrian whose hat is sim
ilarly attached.
The two bump, their hats fly off
and they scramble for them. When
hats finally are recovered each has
IPs Bl
j
the wrong one. This causes consid-,
erable embarrassment when the two
cables go taut as the men separate.
Anger soon takes the place o vinbar-1
rassment when the cables i "ome.
j. .gtftf.gJ-</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1916-02-07/ed-1/seq-20/#date1=1756&index=14&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charley&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=charley+chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026089/1915-11-04/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHARLEY CHAPLIN CONTEST ON MONDAY
\o HAS NOW MADE HER PHOTOPLAY DEBUT AND SAYS SHE LOVES IT,
The many New Hope and Lambertville friends of the latter’s Strand
Theatre will be much interested in the announcement that Flemington,
the county seat of Hunterdon, will soon have a handsome theatre to be
named “The Strand,” as soon as a site is selected. Messrs. Hildinger
and Papier, owners of the “The Strands” of Lambertville and Doylestown
and numerous other theatres throughout the state, have been in confer
ence with A. B. Lare of Flemington, and have the choice of two central
locations.
The building when completed will have 800 opera chairs, an elegant
orchestral organ, a gold fibre screen, two Powers fib picture machines
and all the latest equipments that ha%e made the H. and P. theatres so
pronounced successes.
Flemington will no doubt receive the new theatre with considerable
enthusiasm as the need of a modern house has been keenly felt. The
fact that Messrs. Hildinger and Papier consider Flemington a fertile field
for their operations speaks well for the progress of the county seat as a
theatrical centre.
The famous Paramount pictures, which are enjoying a wide popu
larity, will be shown at the Flemington playhouse as well as at the local
theatre.
Many of the Strand patrons from Lahaska, Buckingham and Carvers
ville who formerly came to Lambertville occasionally now make frequent
visits to the Doylestown playhouse. Frequent visitors from Flemington
have voiced the need of a modern and popular movie theatre, and it will
complete a chain with the Coryell’s Ferry Community as a center.
CHARLEY CHAPLIN CONTEST.
The Charley Chaplin contest will be held Monday evening, and the
boys on both sides of the river are anxiously awaiting the moment when
they can show which most resembles him. Prizes will be offered, and a
big time is expected. The full details are given in their ad on the last
page of this paper.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1916-02-05/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charley&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=19&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=charley+chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-09-08/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charley&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=17&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=charley+chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-12-01/ed-1/seq-30/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charley&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=18&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=charley+chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042224/1918-04-13/ed-1/seq-16/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Lion Brand House Paint
$3.00 Per Gallon $1.60 Per
Mr. Washington (as old Bill Thack
eray sarcastically used to call him)
could not speak for the third liberty
Loan in words, being there only in
bronze. But while Charley Chaplin
led the Twenty-second infantry band
with his slllv little cane and While
the affable and athletic Doug Fair
banks bounded lightly as a panther
from nlmost the sidewalk level to
place beside the heroic bronze legs
of General Washington—while the
crowd estimated as low as 50,000 and
as high as 100,000 listened to Doug
and Charley make speeches for the
loan -the general held a right bronze
hand gently outward, palm down, as
if to hep the attention of the appall
ing mass of humanity stretching
south in Broad street as far as the
eye could reach, east in Wall street
until humans merged with the noon
haze, west 1n Wall street until the
rear guard of that wing oi' the crowd
was belnsr Jammed into the entrances
of Old Trinity, far out on Broadway
Also the crowd spilled back into Nas
sau street so many blocKs that the
northern fringe of the Jam could not
so much as see the sub-treasury
building, where George and Doug
and Charley were facing the vast
multitude.
Described in a Ssntanea.
A great reporter on The Sun, the
late Julian Ralph, once described in a
sentence the crowd that had packed
itself in Unter den linden in Berlin
during the coronation ceremonies of
the present Kaiser Wilhelm. Whore
other correspondents took up a
column to impress upon their readers
how great was the crowd on that oc
casion Mr. Ralph said it all without
stopping for breath by remarking*
"A small German boy perched on
the low branch of a tree fell off and
broke his arm on somebody's head,
nd it took the driver of an ambu
lance exactly thirty-two minutes to
work his vehicle three-quarters of a
city block to tho spot whero tha boy
had fallen."
And that was tho kind of croyrd
that turned out yesterday at noon at
Broad and Wall streets to hear, and
especially to look upon. Doug Fair
banks and Charley Chaplin talking
bout the glories of buying Liberty
bonds.
After attending to a girl stenogra
pher who had fainted in the crush
Ambulance Surgeon Phillips of the
Broad street hospital remarked
casually that the girl he had just
revived was the eleventh case of the
kind to which he had given first aid
since taking up his station in front
of the entrance of the J. P. Morgan
& Co. offices less than three-quarters
of an hour earlier. One riian got so
jammed in the crowd that his ribs
snapped. One hundred and fifty
police reserves who tried to keep the
crowd in a semblance of order were
themselves swallowed In the onrush.
And not onlv was the asphalt pav
ed solidly from building line to build
ing line In four directions as far as
the eye could «ee, but also there were
alls of humanity reaching to the
zenith as the windows of the Bank
ers' Trust buiidine and the other
towering buildings flew up. Clerks
and stenographers and office boys,
yes and bosses too, leaned far out of
the windows up near the clouds to
get a glimpse of tho tops of the
heads of George and Charley and
Doug.
Choors From the Skylino.
And although George held his dlgni
fled pose, Doug and Charley found
time amid their speeches and acro
batics to lean far back and look
straight up into Heaven to wave and
ishout acknowledgments of the happy
cheers that came down from snowy
oints far above the timber lino of
ower Manhattan.
And when the erpeechmaking and
mnastics of the open air were fin
ished Treasurer Martin Vogel of tho
sub-treasury took Doug ana Charley
who jointly were losing about 'steen
hundred bucks an hour by working
for the liberty loan instead of for
themselves) into the vaults of tho
sub-treasury, together with John
airbanks, Doug's brother, and a few
friends, to impress them with the
mount of gold and silver coin, bank
not BP and gold bars stored behir
eorge's bronze back. And wht
Martin had piled up before rharli
and DOUBT all the kale he could ft?
King around loose the distressing]
wealthy movie stars, looking straigf
into the features of hundreds of mil
lions of dollars. Just stood there and
laughed and laughed right In the face
of the sub-treasury's millions.
Martin Vogel. Acting Assistant
Treasurer U. S. Grant, who is a
•nephew of the immortal Ulyssea
Assistants Chapman and Twitty and
olher officials of the sub-treasury
tried their derndest to Impress Doug
nd Charley with samples of goods
from the shelves of the sub-treasury
aults. The longer the official force
along the money aisles worked at
pulling their stock off the shelvos
that louder Doug and Charley laugh
ed at the paltry display.
Assistant Twitty. plainly peeved,
opened a little steel door painted a
light battleship gray and tossed a"
We 1" «. .*!o:... _"_t_ v. s. _iUQut ..- because tha 1
of national defense will not allow tho manufacturers to mak
more than SO colors. These 12 colors will be closed out at:
y2
85c Per Gallon
FRES COAT—A kalsomine that can be mixed la cold or warm
watar. Wa have It in
12
tints, at—
10 CENTS POUND
Gallon
i^iiaasoa Drug Co.
10 iROADWAY FARGO, N.
They Visited the Treasury and Held
$100,000,000 "Kidded" President
Wilson, and Talked to Between
50,000 and 100,000 Per
sons In New York
From The New York Sun: Doug
and Charley and George—surnamed
respectively Fairbanks and Chaplin
and Washington-all stood at ease
on a granite pedestal at the sunlit
northeast corner of Broad and Wall
streets during the noon hour yester
day and looked out upon the upturn
ed faces of the most tremendous
crowd that ever had been packed into
the greatest corner of the greatest
financial district in the greatest city
in the goshawfulest greatest country
in the golderned greatest world
THE FARGO FORUM, SATURDAY EVENING, APRIL 13, 1918.
Some slight sign of interest might
now be noted in the eyes of Charley
('haplin and of Doug, as each began
to realize that he was clasping |80,
000.000 to his panting bosom.
Make it $lO0.O00,000 while you're
at it. what?" cried Charley, whereup
on the sub-treasury folks, seeing that
they were beginning at last to make
some sort of dont upon the non
chalance of even Charley Chaplin,
reached toward another, shelf and
took down J40.000.000 more, 120,000,
000 for Charley and another 520,000,
00 for Doug, thus permitting ach to
hold 1100,000,000 for a few minutes.
"Oy!" cried Charlye Chaplin, un
able any' longer 'to preserve his
studied savoir faire. And he bent
his tousled head gentlv. lovingly to
one side and downward and rested
his boyish cheek fondly against the
monneh. "Oy, yol-yoi-yoi!" he croon
ed and he kissed the $100,000,000
fondly before he passed It back to the
United States of North America.
Triok Hat Stays in Vault.
Tho little party came out of tha
vaults then, Charley Chaplin bringing
up the rear. Doug Fairbanks was
the first to notice that Charley car
ried no hat with him as he passed
out of the vault. Doug called Char
ley's attention to the fact that he was
hatless.
"Sure enough!' 'cried Charley, with
every semblance of surprise. "Yea, I
must have left the little old trick hat
back there in the vault room. Doug,
you and Mr. Vogel, and all you
guards go on right up to the maU)
floor and I'll Join you as soon as I've
stepped back in the vault and found
my hat. Go on—all the guards and
everybody don't wait for me—I
couldn't think of detaining you, gen
tlemen."
But they wouldn't let Charley Chap
lin go back into the vaults to get his
hat. at least not unaccompanied. And
despite the fact that Charley's pub
licity bureau issued a screed last
night to the effect that Charley had
left his trick hat back among the
monneh quite by accident, Doug
Fairbanks was authority for the con
tradictory statement that he had seen
Charley deliberately place the trick
hat on top of $85,000,000 in a dark
corner of the vault room when no
one was looking.
Charley and Doug started out from
the Rltz-Carlton early yesterday
morning to preach to ail Manhattan
throughout the day on the text:
"First, second and third liberty
Ixjans, these three and the greatest
of these Is the third." They had Just
come from California, via Washing
ton, In their "Three Star Special,"
which was not a brand of hard liquor,
but a real train. The third of the
stars was our Mary Pickford.
"Greateat Actors in World."
All across the continent Charley
and Doug had piled off at stations
and had mingled with the throngs.
E#£r
li'V '-I
I*
.jfrr:.
Fargo Missed 'Doug' and 'Charley'and
'Our Mary' But Here's What They Did
In New "York and Washington
bundle of bills, each bill having "$10,
000"
engraved on its face, and the
whole packet being about the size
of a brick too short but too thick in
to Charley Chaplin's hand. That lit
tie bundle of bright new yellow
backs was wot-th Just 110,000,000 in
regular gold coin.
Smilss Wouldn't Woar Off.
Charley Chaplin smiled a smile
that very plainly said, "Pooh oh
pooh!" Assistant Chapman tossed i
similar little bundle into Doug Fair
banks" tanned mit. Plainly the teethy
smile of Doug said. "Pooh, and
couple of blooies!" All the treas
urers and assistant treasurers and
deputy assistant treasurers thereupon
plainly got sore. So feverishly they
opened one cubhv hole after another
doubling the sruard around Doug and
•Charley as he did so and in a few
seconds Charley and Doug each were
holding on their palms and crooked
forearms eight of tho "bricks" of
bank notes.
Bcvr..- fly Tune",
Comes PEARL Time
We sell genuine t»5
PEARL Wire Cloth.
YSatisfaction.
OU can have Confidence in anything
you buy from us because we guarantee
We are confident that
/you will be satisfied because we buy what
we sell on a basis of what you need and
want, and then stand
Doug yeTfthg above the roar of shout
ers, who did not know that young
Mr. Fairbanks was standing at theh
elbows. "Fairbanks: Bring Doug
Fairbanks out on the platform. Who'
the greatest actor In tho world? Doug
Fairbanks!"
And from the crowd pressing
around the other end of the observa
tion car the voice of Charley Chaplin
could be heard calling: shrilly, "Chap
lin! Oh, you funny Charley Chaplin
Bring out Charley Chaplin, the great
eat actor in the world!"
Both Doup and Charley were graci
ous enough to intersperse their yells
with cries for "Our Mary! Bring ou
Mary Pickford!" And when Charley
and Doug had gflt his particular
group of standees on the station plat
forms yelling hard enough for Char
ley and Doug each would crawl under
the brake beams of the car and then
sneak back into the car and stnoll out
onto their respective platforms while
the going was good.
In time they got to Washington
where President Wilson received
them last Saturday night. That was
the evening the President delivered
his important speech at Baltimore,
and although the 'Three Star Spec
lal" was an hour late at Washington
the President was gracious enough
to wait an hour overtime at the
White House until Doug and Charley
and Our Mary had got there.
"And what are you going to say in
your speeches about the third Liberty
i-oan'."' the President asked the three
movie stars.
They all thought hard and then
variously they murmured to the
President half intelligible remarks to
the effect that although they could
do fair work for the lillums they
weren't so sure of themselves as ora
tors.
"Mr. President," spoke up Doug
Fairbanks at last, "the only general
scheme I've got for a speech is to
mention your name whenever I get
stuck. That'll get a cheer every time
and while the crowd is making a lot
of noise I'll keep wraving my arms
and working my lips as if I was say
ing something. And when the noise
dies down again I'll shout, 'And, fel
low citizens, this great President
Woodrow Wilson Bingo, they'll
begin to cheer again, and I'll work
my Jaws and pound one palm with
my fist, and keep swinging my arms
until the noise dies down some more.
Then I'll shout Out your name again
—'as long as good,' as we say in the
show business."
All of which the Honorable Wood
row Wilson enjoyed immensely.
But Charley and Doug followed no
such plan once they had battled their
way knee high to the heroic bronze
legs of George Washington at Broad
and Wall streets at noon yesterday.
Charley got the crowd going first by
flipping his trick hat and then lead
ins: the khaki clad bond on the sub
tr.easury steps, and Doug, who arriv
ed a few minutes later, rendered the
office bo contingent of all the tinan
cial district speechless with ecstasy
as he vaulted to the pedestal beside
George, threw off his mustard colored
polo coat, grabbed up a little red
megaphone and led the cheers in col
lege boy fashion.
4
Doug Jiggles Charlay.
Charley Chaplin, when a semblance
of quiet was restored, yelled out over
the human pavement that although
British born he waa "144 per cent
American," and would be In the
trenches if it were not for a physical
disability that makes him impossible
as military material. And Doug
reached for the slim waisted little
Charley and gripped him below the
belt on the East River side while1
Charley was facing the Hudson. Then
the muscular Doug held Charley high
in the air with one hand and jiggled
him above the roaring crowd.
Doug made his speech after that,
megaphoning questions to the crowd
which enabled the roaring thousand*
to yell back resounding affirmatives
which, if the crowd meant what it
said, some day will be heard away
out in the eastern suburbs of Berlin.
And after that Lieutenant Reuterdal,
the illustrator naval officer, made a
brief speech and the movie celebrities
went Indoors to heft real money.
This morning Doug and Charley
will go to Philadelphia, where they
will meet Miss Pickford, who was
speaking in Baltimore yesterday
while the other two-thirds of the
Three Star Special" were talking
here. Then they will separate, each
to go on a separate Liberty Loan</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-dixie-tornado-outbreak</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058130/1908-04-24/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TORNADO HITS NEBRASKA NEBRASKA
Three People Killed Killec1Many Many Injured Injuredand Injuredalid Injuredand
and Several Houses Swept SweptAway SweptAway SweptAway
Away by the WindBaneroft Wind WindBancroft WiiidBancroft
Bancroft Neb April 23 IA A tornado tornadoswept tornadoswept tornadoSwept
swept through Cumlng county and Into
Thurston county at noon today and three threepeople threepeople threepeople
people are known to have been killed a anumber anumber anumber
number Injured and a number of houses
destroyed destroyedThe destroedThe e eThe
The tornado struck the house of John
Mangleson near Pender Neb and then thenswooped thenswooped thenswooped
swooped up into the air taking the thewreckage thewreckage thewreckage
wreckage of the house and both Mr and
Mrs Irs Mangelson Both were killed killedthelr their
bodies being beln carried a mile mileGeorge mileGeorge mileGeorge
George Waacker and family were at atlunch atlunch atlunch
lunch when the twister struck their house
Three of the family were seriously In ¬
jured juredThe JuredTbe juredThe
The dead body of a little baby was waspicked waspicked waspicked
picked up In the public road ten miles milesfrom milesfrom milesfrom
from Bancroft The child hab ha not been beenidentified beenidentified beenidentified
identified but undoubtedly was brought broughtby
by b the tornado from some residencewhlch residencewhlchwas
was wreckedLUMBER wreckedLUMBER wrecked wrecked</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1908-04-24/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DEATH IN TEXAS TORNADO
One Killed, Several Injured and Twenty
seven Buildings Destroyed.
fRy T»>«rrarh to Th* Tribune. 1
Paris Tex.. April 3.— Deport, a. town in Lamar
County twenty miles southeast of Paris, was struck
by a cyclone this afternoon. Twenty-five houses
and two churches were destroyed and considerable
damage was done in the business section. W. R.
Isbell was killed and several others injured.
At Fort Smith. Arkansas, a tornado cloudburst
and hail damaged buildings.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045555/1908-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TWO HUNDRED PEOPLE KILLED
utinis of Tornado That Swept
Over Louisiana Mississippi
And Alabama
HUNDREDS MORE INJURED
f o
lost of Dead Were Negroes
Their Shacks Proving Ver
itable Death Traps
uriii La lcl Some Twclie Hours
Sulking Kirs I Olio Ton n niul
f Then Another
CPW Orleans La April 2iThc iloail
iro than 200 the Injurctl at least MO
5 < were the grim facts which runic
light In I10 early hours today when
utile oC the wreckage or yesterdays
itado in Louisiana Mississippi and
fjabama had boon cleared away Thu
> imdoes lasted altogether uboiit 12
urN striking promiscuously one town
ter the other before daylight on FrI
iy until midafternoon Many noun
11 they struck trains bearing near
200 Injured came crawling cautiously
t of the tornado districts leaving
hind them one town Purvis Miss
lurly demolished five others practl
lly blown uway and 13 little villages
i1 more or less acute stages of ruin
Ith these wounded came the details
one of the worst wind disasters In
history of the gulf states
First of all It became known that
gioea comprised most of the dead
at the picturesque darky cabins not
I for thoir lllmsy happygolucky
instruction had been converted by the
j ind Into wholesale death traps I
18 In the fall of these cabins which
tit down almost without warning
Jbat inost of the negro deaths occurred
skesc always overcrowded cabins also
furnished most of the badly wounded
SYlie Identified white dead early to
Jay numbered 42 In addition It was
llrportcd that four whites hal been
tilled at McOallum Miss which would
iilng the whlto death list up to 4G and
1hr number of negroes killed was be
iopn HO and 175
The towns which suffered the worst
damage In addition to Punls were
Amtlo la McCallum MeLaurln and
Winchester Miss and Albertvllle Ala
TOWNS DAMAGED
Tho following 35 towns were more or
f tiamaged
Klchmond and Iumourle La VII
riti New Augusta Columbus Walls
iraxton Belle Grove Jtejtou Loimun
Iile Ridge Qultmans Landing Falr
hllds Creek and AVahaak In Mlssls
rpl and Bergon Alabama
Most ot those places are merely a
Election of n few stores and dwellings
i that the property losses will not
nch very largo tlgures No estimates
property damage buvo yot been
ddc with the exception or Amltc La
iid Purvis Miss tho two worst suf
rcrs where tho damage which will
wi
over 0 estimated In tho aggregate
is done to timber lands to planta
Ums and to railroad property bcut
1led paThe through I boll about GOO miles
The destruction of Purvis Miss oc
urml nt about 10 minutes after 2
cock Friday afternoon and was all
Iel In a few minutes tlmo Of about
dwelling houses only seven were
ft Htandlng Tho court house the
ily other building In town to with
land tho wind was Immediately packed
ith dead and Injuied and served
< the alI uvalhililo hospital within
Tiny miles C W Cromwell of Juck
IJ Mis In attempting to describe the
orin wild that all ho could realize
in that tho air wan full of Hying tlm
os Those timbers dealt death to
ny persons who sought safety In tho
l >  u alii while the fulling walls were a
llll greater peril to those who re
iUied Indoors
hJI1 child is sid to have been kneel
 Ill prayer her uncle bending over
i In an attempt toshield her but
iplte his care a timber which did not
iHli him killed the little girl
Scarcely one brick uf thu school
HUMS was left</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058130/1908-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GUlf ST STATES A TfS SWEPT SWfPTBY SWEPTBY
BY TERRIBLE TORNADO TORNADOflwo
flwo Two Hundred and TwentyFive Persons Killed Killedand Killedand Killedand
and 490 Injured in Louisiana Ala Alabama Alaba Alabarna ¬
bama ba aand and Mississippi MississippiMost
Most of the Victims Negroes Whole Towns Demolished Demolishedand
and Property Loss Will Be Heavy
I
4 + + + + tt ttNew 3 3New + + 4 + 4M4 + + + + + + HHH HHHNew + + + + + +
+ New Orleans April 24 24About 24About + f fAbout
+ About thirty white persons and andand andand andand +
+ and fifty negroes were killed killedby kIIJedby + t tby
+ by the tornado at Purvis Miss Missf MissThis MissThis +
+ f This raises raaes the total death list listf listto +
f to about 225 225fMH 225tt 4 +
+ fMH + + + + + + + + H + + + + M tt 44AtLanta M + + M MAtlanta + + + + + + + + + tAt1 + + + + +
Atlanta At1 nta Ga April 24 tReports Reports up to tomidnight tomidnight tomidnight
midnight indicate that 150 persons were werekilled werekilled werekilled
killed and about 400 injured in storms stormsof
of great violence which passed over over sec sections sections seetions ¬
tions of Louisiana Mississippi and Ala Alabama Alabama Alatama ¬
bama today Several towns were almost
j 4 totally swept sway and the property propertdamage
damage will run Into large figures figuresMost figures1105t figuresMost
Most of those tho e killed were negroes whose whosecabins wllosecabins whosecabins
cabins were swept away like so much muchpaper muchpaper muchpaper
paper paperNatchez paperNatchez paperNatchez
Natchez Miss reports that of sixty slxt slxtfour
four persons killed In that section only
two were whites whitesLate whitesLate whitesLate
Late reports from Amlte mite a small town townin townin townin
in southeastern Louisiana say that the thetown thetown thetown
town was almost entirely destroyed and andthe andthe andthe
the estimates place the number killed at atbetween atbttwcen atbetween
between twentyfive and fifty while at atleast atleast atleast
least seventyfive were Injured InjuredHarvest injuredHarvest mi tired tiredHarvest
Harvest of Death DeathAt DeathAt DeathAt
At McLnin Miss eight are reported to tohave toIlae tobave
have been killed at Vidalia La one onewhite onliwhite on onwhite
white woman and six negroes are re dead deadat deadAt deadat
at Quitman Landing eleven negroes were werekilled wereldlled werekilled
killed at Purvis Landing Miss 1155 three threewhites threewhites threewhites
whites and nine negroes were victims of ofthe orthe ofthe
the storm and reports of from one to five fivedeaths fivedeaths fivedeaths
deaths come from rUin many towns scattered scatteredNew scatteredotr scatteredOver
Over the stormswept are areNew area areaNew
New Orleans aid Mobile were cut off offIT offrtJom
rtJom I IT from wire communication with the outside outsideworld outsideworld
I world for several hours today and the thetelegraph thetele thete1egmph
telegraph tele ph companies report wires down downIn downIn downIn
In all directions directionsTonight directionsTonight directionsTonight
Tonight the storm is sweeping through throughGeorgia throughGeorsta throughGeorgia
Georgia but beyond torrential rains ac accompanied accompanied accompanled ¬
companied by b high winds and brilliant brirllantelectrical brlHianteleetrlcal brilliantelectrical
electrical displays no serious damage or orloss orloss orloss
loss of life has been reported in the state stateScore stateScore stateScore
Score of Towns Wrecked WreckedIn
In Louisiana It is estimated that a score scoreof score scoreof scoreof
of small towns were cre destroyed or par partially partlally partially ¬
tially wrecked They The include Amite City i
Arcadia ATl adla and Independence Belie Grove GroveVclton GrovVelton GroveVelton
Velton Lorman Pine Ridge Quitman QuitmanLanding QultmnnLanding QuitmanLanding
Landing Falrchilds Creek Purvis and andLumberton andlumberton andlumberton
Lumberton Miss are reported seriously
damaged by b the storm stormIn stormIn stormIn
In Alabama < Dora was the chief Auf nufferer Auffrer srnfferer
ferer This town is also known as Ber Bergen Bercn Betgm ¬
gen gm cn Four or more persons were killed killedmongr killedong i
mongr ong them the wife and daughter of ofSectlonmaster otSectionmaster ofSectlonmaster
Sectlonmaster Moore Fifty persons at atthe atthe atthe
the lowest estimate were injured Those Thosemost Thosemost Thoacmost
most seriously hurt were carried to hos hospitals hospltals hospitals ¬
pitals in Birmingham Ala One woman womanMrs womanIrs womanMrs
Mrs Irs McCully died on the train trainAt trainAt trainAt
At Bergen cars wore blown from the therailroad theraUroad therailroad
railroad tracks and considerable other otheroperty otheropert otheroperty
operty destroyed destroyedLoss destroedY destroyedV
Y Loss of Life Appalling AppallingReports AppallingRlports AppallIngReports
Reports also say that the storm struck struckAlbertvllle struckAlbtrhlIIe struckAlbertville
Albertvllle Ala late this afternoon do doIng dolug dolug
lug much destruction to life and prop property propert property ¬
erty ert An unconfirmed report from this thissection thisslction thissection
section gives the death list as from fromthirty fromthlrt fromthirty
thirty thlrt to thirtyfive with scores of per persons perSO persos ¬
sons SO < lS injured A train was sent from fromBirmingham fromBirmingham fromBirmingham
Birmingham tonight carrying physicians physiciansand
and a squad of state militiamen to the thedistrict thedistrict thedistrict
district districtFrom districtFrom districtFrom
From Meridian Miss 1I5s comes a report reportthat reportthat reportthat
that Mrs Irs John Mlnnlce and her child childwere childwere childwere
were killed outright and John Minnice Minnlcewas Minnicewas Minnicewas
was seriously serlousI injured while a number of ofother ofothlr ofother
other persons were hurt and there was wasconsiderable wasconsiderable wasconsiderable
considerable destruction of property propertRIchmond
Richmond and Lamourie La were werestruck werostruck werestruck
struck by b the storm and nearly a fifth of oftheir oCtheir oftheir
their population Injured InjuredWinchester InjuredInchester InjuredWinchester
Winchester Miss a small town Is re reported reported reported ¬
ported wiped out though only two per persons persons perSons ¬
sons are known to have been killed killedMobile killedIoblle killedMobile
Mobile reported nine dead in Hatties Hattiesburg Hatttesburg Hattiesburg
> burg Miss lIss but this has not been con confirmed confirmed confirmed ¬
firmed firmedj firmedNQTUER</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020616/1908-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WED GET THJE NEWS FIRST
VOLUME 23.
ALBUQUERQUE. NEW MEXICO. SATURDAY, AFJUL 25. 190S.
NUM13ER 99
MORE THAN TWO HUNDRED DEAD
T
21
3
FROM
ORNA
Mississippi. AlabarfiUind Louisiana in
the Path of WorstV yrms That Have
Visited the Guif St s in Years-Five
Hundred Are Injuria and Many of
Them Will Die From Their Injuries
and Exposure.
WHOLE TOWNS SWEPT AWAY BY TWISTERS;
INHABITANTS BURIED UNDERNEATH DEBRIS
Five Towns Blown Down. One
tie Villages In Ruins Result From Wind Storms That
Raged Throughout Yesterday-Most of the Dead Are Nf
groes but Many Whites Lost Lives or Sustained Serious
Injuries In Storm-Relief Trains Bring Injured to Hospitals
Xc-.v Orleans, April 23. The dead, i
more than 200; injured at least BOO. I
These were grim fids which came I
to light tills morning when a little!
of tin wreckage of yesierday's torna
do in l,ouisrtna, M ississippi and Al
tibiinni had been cleared away,
The tornadoes lasted altogether
about 12 hours striking promiscuously
one town after the other from before
daylight Friday until midafternoon.
Many hours after they struck, trains
hearing nearly 200 injured came
t rawling cautiously out of the torna
do districts, leaving behind one town
J'urvis, Miss., utterly demolished;
five others practically blown away
and llfteen little villages in more or
less acute stage of ruin.
With these wounded came details
of one of the worst disasters in the
history of the gulf states.
First of allf it became known that
negro comprised the moat of the
dead, most -of their deaths occurring
In Itimsy cabins, and the most badly
wounded came from" the same
places.
Th" identified white dead early to-
clay numbered 42. In addition it Is
reported that four whites were killed
in YcO.UIum, Miss., which would
bring the white dead to 46. The
Lumber of negroes killer) was be
tween 150 and 175. The tiwna which
suffered the damage in addition to
1'urvis were Amite. Ia.. Mcl'allum, I
Mfljmirin and Winchester, Miss, and
Alhertgille, Ala. In Purvis, of about
200 dwelling, only seven were left
standing.
Twnnly IVrvvns Wnvkiil.
Atlanta, 5a., April 25. In all
nearly twenty towns were struck by
the "twlstrs," of which there seem
to have been nt least five.
The t irnado that tlrst appeared In
Concordia Parish, Ia., appears to
have bepn the most serious in respect
to number of victims ami territory
overed. Although It traveled through
a rural district and struck no Kirge
towns the known results of Its work
are f. 4 dead 'and at least 100 injured
with the prospect that the list wlTT be
considerably swtdled Moro than 50
of the dead are negroes whose log
cabins proved particularly fatal to
the oceupunts, being easily torn to
pieces while the weight of the tim
bers crushed the Inmates to death.
Alter leaving Concordia Parish the
storm crossed over into Mississippi j
and traversed portions of Adams,
Jefferson and 4. la bourne counties. Its
path being about 1.000 feet wide.
What appears to have been two
different tornadoes also struck in
western A t.i bp ma. one c laiming six
victims .it llergen and Thomas saw
mill, srn'tll place, and another strut k
A I hi "vlMe. where thirty persons are
reported to have been killed. This,
however, canno' be confirmed as all
wires are down.
Belief for the suffer, rs Is being
".isp,it. !). .1 from all avuiliblo points.
linlcr Martial Uvr,
,v Orleans. April 25. Amite,
was so badly damaged that it
put iind-r martial law it once
r lers of the mayor. Th.. .-Inrm
k 'here just about noun, killing
wh te pernios iin 1 thirteen ne-
".
Ui..
u as
by
si rui
two
fcroe. outright nr.. I injur,
cr-. mostly negroes.
The total death li.-t
d many oth-
Amite
rea. lies ,.,t l..;-t 23
It u :t .I" w as possibly
killed at Amite. Ho
to w i r ( his rliu red.
islle I n'-ting the bel
ltcv. Father
the first person
wis in the bell
bavins just fin
He was crush
fuliimr tower,
of Amite, was
ed -o letth
Mrs W.
eauuiit by tl
driving home.
by th.
I laden.
tornado as she was
A tree f. II items the
in, but she was un-
horse. k.lhnsT hi
bin".
Forty person
'mil tin rei.il hot
' a i r'o 1 a way tl
.liniiur at the
en the storm
f but none of
tlie diners were hurt
The pith of the tornado is about
two arid a half mile wile and when
il pas. .1 Amile stood w reeked. A
large number of farm animals were
killed. Th greatest loss of life
among the negroes occurred in t lie
Vicinity of Natchez, Miss. Twenty-five
persons were killed in Adams county
S IN 3 STATES
Demolished and Fifteen Lit
Miss., near Natchez, and thirty-five
in the neighborhood of Church Hill.
The tornado In this section was
about 1"0 miles north of the Amite
tornado and struck about breakfast
time. In this section a negro baby
was carried 300 yards land deposited
in a swamp, unhurt. An aged negro
woman was whired into the air and
her head almost severed by flying
timbers. The body of u little negro
boy was found In a field with a piece
of timber driven through his heart.
Only Two Whites l)eal.
Natchez, Miss., April 25. Two
bodies, both colored and badly man
gled, victims of yesterday's tornado,
were found between Giles Bend and
Pine Itidge thin morning, bringing
the Hist of dead in this section to 71,
of which number all are negroes hut
two. Several Injured are not expected
to live.
Nine Injure! negroes from the
Church Hill neighborhood were re
ceived at the Charity hospital this
morning. These arrivals were rein
forced by seven from the Lucerne
plantation In Concordia Parish, La.
Five Wore Killed.
Atlanta, Oa., April 25. Iteports re
ceived here today Fay a severe wind
storm struck Griffin, Ga., during tne
night, wrecking part of the town,
killing live and injuring at least llf
teen. The report declares a cotton
mill and other business houses were
blown down. From Columbus, Ga.
the Associated Press received a. dis
patch today saying that two persons
were killed and a dozen Injured by
a. storm there.
Communication (Hit Off.
.New Orleans. April 25. As the
result of terrific storms which yes
lernay swept, tne gu:r states, com
munication between cities in this
section of the country Is poor today
and In the majority of Instances
there Is no communication ul ali.
Trains coming into New Orleans on
various railroads report heavy dam
age all along the lines and it Is be
lieved the death list In Loulsana.
Mississippi, Tennessee and Alabamvi
Mill reach several hundred.
Mobile, April 25. Report. receiv
ed here today state that the town of
Fort Deposit. US miles from Mobile,
was almost wiped out by last night's
tornado.
I 'oui- Tim us ill's.! ii oil.
Atlanta, April 25. A telephone
message from the path of the storm
reports fitulities at Shipley, Harris
City, Mclionough and Locust Grove,
Georgia. It In reported hero that a
number of persons were killed in
the-e town. The storm in this sec
tion followed a path a few hundred
yard wide.
A telephone message fro,,. Griffin,
Ga.. sas Mrs. M. K. Greer and M. P.
Chapel w.re killed outright in their
1 .nines and Mrs. Harris and son have
die I since. The storm struck Griftin
about 2 this morning cutting a path
about a hundred yards wile through
tne city and destroying at least 25
Ili'U-cs besides tile liaptst church
and on,, or two other public leiii i-
'IX AS. Nil miters Were ll.jlll'eo.
Koine, Ga., April 25 A report
r. ached h. re tait tAeuij p. rsons
were killed by a terrific storm be
t w i . n Ceilntowii and Cave springs,
Ga.
S'i'i Francisco, A pill 23. Alexander
McAdie, ill charge of the Cnited
States weather bureau, reports a mod
erate earthquake here at 2:34 this
morning. No damage was done.
Pirmitigh.tm. Apr I 2 .Twenty
five per... ms are reported killed at Al.
liertviilt , Ala., in yest. rd.i . s tornado
1'iiniini.hani, Ala., April 25. Ue
ports though still somewhat meager
as to the result of the t..r:,a lo that
w.iit through Alabama yesterday. In
dicate that fifteen people lost their
live In this Mate and between sev
enty ami 100 are injured, mx or eight
fatally. Property damaged amounts
tit hundreds of fhonand of dollars
Many of the sufferers were poor'
people and there is considerable dis
tress.
Purvis, Miss., April 23. An air of i
death and desolation marks Turvis to
dny. The total death list In this vi
cinity has now reached 62 and It Is
believed particulars from the sur
rounding country will add materially
to these figures.
Mobile, April 25. Heports received
here today say that at MeCullam,
Miss., probably twenty were killed
anil several Injured In yesterday's
storm. The MeCullam trestle and
four hundred feet of track -were blown
off the right of way and nothing was
b it i.f the trestle but the piling.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85047084/1908-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW ORLEANS, April 25. Six distinct tornadoes are reported
yesterday from points in Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama, some
of them doing a great amount of damage, accompanied by heavy loss
of life. A total of two Hundred and fifty people have lost their lives,
and the number of injured amounts to many hundreds. The torna
does swept across the three States, wrecking towns and doing a great
amount of destruction.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058130/1908-04-26/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Half a Thousand Lives Lost in inDistricts inDistricts inDistricts
Districts Swept by the theTornado theTornado theTornado
Tornado TornadoOVER TornadoOVER TornadoOVER
OVER ONE HUNDRED HUNDREDFATALLY HUNDREDFATALLY HUNDREDFATALLY
FATALLY INJURED INJUREDTEN
TEN TIMES THAT NUMBER PAIN PAINFULLY PAINFULLY PAINFULLY ¬
FULLY HURT PROPERTY LOSS LOSSWILL LOSSWILL LOSSWILL
WILL AMOUNT TP T MILLIONS MILLIONSoclock MILLIONSJ MILLIONSAUnta
J tIanta Gn April 25Up to tooclock I Ioclock
< oclock tonight the dead and in inJured Injured Injurecl
< Jured In Fridays tornado are as asfollows astollows a arollows
< follows followsLouisiana tollowsLouisianaDead rollowse
< e Louisiana LouisianaDead Dead IDS 10 Injured
> 350 350Mississippi Mississippi MississippiDead Bead 159 Injured Injuredt
t 650 6
650Alabama
Alabama AlabamaDead Dead 31 injured 113 113Geprgla 113Gepr1aDeail 113QeprglaDeaLl
Geprgla Gepr1aDeail Dead 25 2 injured 100 100This 100This 100h
h This makes the dead for four fourstater fourw
w 0 state 323 injured In which whlchrnl whlchrnlnor ml mlnor 011nor
> nor Injuries are not Included 1213 1213New ln3J ln3New 1213NeW
J <
New Orleans La April 25 25Probably 25Probablyhalt Probably Probablyhalf
half a thousand lives lost a hundred hundredor
or more persons persons fatally injured and andmany andmany andniuiy
many times this thi number painfully painfullyhurt painfullyhurt painfullyhurt
hurt together with a 0 property loss lossrunning lossrunnIng lossruimln
running ruimln up In the millions Is the rec record record record ¬
ord so far of a tornado that originated originatedIn
In the west two days ago Sweeping SweepingTexas SweepingTexWl SweepingTexas
Texas Arkansas Louisiana Tennessee TennesseeAlabama TennesseeAlabama TennesseeAJbama
Alabama and Georgia it has left a apath apath apath
path of death desolation and want In InIts InIts Snits
Its wake w ke seriously Interrupted all allcommunication allcommunication alleommunicaUon
communication between cities in the thesouth the6Outh thesouth
south and brought about chaotic con conditions conditions conditlons ¬
ditions In the smaller towns townsMississippi townsMlsslss townsMIssIsspI
Mississippi Mlsslss 1 Worst Sufferer SuffererMississippi SuffererMississippi SuffererMississippi
Mississippi already alreal a sufferer from frommore frommore frommore
more than one tornado this year ear has hasagain hasagain hasigaIn
again borne the brunt of the vrinda and andrains andrains andrains
rains Estimates of the numberN number of ofthose ofthose ofthose
those who lost their lives in that state stateplace stateplace stateplace
place the death list near 300 with a atliousand athousand athousand
thousand or more more Injured InjuredIn
In Texas Louisiana Alabama and andGeorgia andG andGeorgia
Georgia G orgia the death lists are also laige largewlth laigewith laigewfth
with serious loss of life in Arkansas Arkansasand Arkansasand Arkailsasand
and and Tennessee Authentic information informationIs
Is I in many instances lacking owing to tothe tothe tothe
the crippled facilities for or communica communication comm1nItlonand a ation ¬
tion tlonand and the lack lacko of time to form formanything formanything formanything
anything like nn accurate estimate estImateot estImateotthe of ofthe
the damage done In many sections sectionsMartial sectionsMartial sectionsMartial
Martial Law Declared DeclaredIn
In half a dozen communities martial martiallaw martialbw martiallw
law has ha been declared so terrible was waathe wasthe wa wathe
the destruction and so helpless were werethe werethe werethe
the stricken people left by the disaster disasterSerious disasterSerlousdlsorders disasterSerious
Serious Serlousdlsorders disorders have occurred In some someplaces somelaces someiJaces
places laces Including1 Includtn Ami Amfte to La Looting Lootingnnd Lootingfind Lootingand
find other crimes have been reported reportedbut
but these Instances have been on the thewhole thehole theT
T whole hole rare rareSeveral rareSeveral rareSeveral
Several places have issued appeals appealsfor
for aid and in Mississippi Governor GovernorNoel GovernorNoel GovernorNoel
Noel has been asked to provide tents tentsfor tentsfor tentsfor
for the homeless homelessStorm homelessStorm homelessStorm
Storm Lasted Two Days DaysThe DaysThe DaysThe
The tornadoes lasted In all a period periodof
of nearly two days It was Thursday Thursdaynight Thursdaynight Thursdaynight
night that damage by tornadoes trav traveling traveling trayellng ¬
eling eastward was first reported from frompoints frompoints frompoints
points in Texas This was followed followedduring followedduring followedduring
during the next twentyfour hours by bysimilar bysimilar bysimilar
similar reports from Arkansas Louisi Louisiana Louisiana Loulsiann ¬
ana Mississippi and Tennessee Last Lastnight Lastnight Lastnight
night Alabama came camewithln within the flight flightof
of the storm and today toda reports of seri serious serious serleus ¬
ous damage by b the winds wlndsln in Georgia Georgiahave Georgiaha GeorIahave
have ha ve been recorded recordedWounded recordedWounded recordedWounded
Wounded and Helpless HelplessVtter Hclplessrtter HelplessVtter
Vtter misery of every sort was found foundtoday foundtoday foundtoday
today at Purvis Miss by b relief par parties parties parties ¬
ties Despite the fact that of the 2500 2500inhabitants 250ilinhabitants 2500lnhabflants
inhabitants which this little town townboasted townboasted townboasted
boasted yesterday morning there were wereonly wereonl30 woreonly
only 900 today still there were not notsufficient not8ufftclent notsufflclent
sufficient accommodations in the thewrecked thereeked thewrecked
wrecked village for even the woundedNegro woundedNegro wounded woundedNegro
Negro mammies and little black chil children children children ¬
dren lay wounded and helpless under underthe underthe underthe
the broiling southern sun Some had hadbroken hadbroken hadbroken
broken bones some were partly partlycrushed partlycrushed partlycrushed
crushed and others had been wound wounded ¬
ed by sticks and splinters These un unfoitunates unfortunates Unfoitunates
foitunates were lucky If they the had a ablanket ablanket ablanket
blanket or a stormwrecked couch couchupon couchupon couchupon
upon which to rest There was no noshelter nohelter noshelter
shelter In the town to protect them themfrom themfrom themfrom
from the sun and many of the walls wallswhich wallshlcb wallswhich
which hlcb remained standing had no roofs roofsand roofsand roofsand
and by a queer freak of the tornado tornadomany tornadomany tornadomany
many of the trees which had not been beenuprooted beenuprooted beenuprooted
uprooted had been snapped off a a few fewfeet fewfeet fewfeet
feet above the ground The grove of ofpines otpines ofpines
pines was mutilated In a manner so sothat sothat sothat
that It appeared apPE > ared as If a giant scythe scythehad scythehad scythehad
had swept through the grove about abouttwentyfive abouttwentyfive abouttwentyfive
twentyfive feet above the ground groundDistracted groundDistracted groundDistracted
Distracted Refugees RefugeesThe
The greater gr ater part of Purvis popula population population population ¬
tion today were refugees In Hattles Hattlesbnrg Hattiesburg Hattlesburg
burg and a d Lumberton Miss about 150 150of 150oftbem 150of
of oftbem them being badly injured Of those thosewho thosewho thosewho
who remained In town many appeared appeareddistracted appearedlstracted appeareddistracted
distracted and they th y told remarkable remarkablestories remarkablestorIes remarkablestories
stories 0 t the number of their fellow fellowtownspeople tellowtow115pcople fellowtownspeople
townspeople who had ad been killed killedMany killedMany killedMany
Many hurried ltUrrledlunerals funerals were held to today foday today ¬
day and a count of the visible dead deadrevealed deadr deadreycaled
revealed r vealed only thirtyfour about hall hallof haltot halfof
of them negroes Many negroes were werereported werereported werereported
reported killed In the vicinity of Pur Purvis Purvis Purvis ¬
vis visThe
The manner marm < r In which whl h the tornado tornadoContinued tornadoContinued tornadoContinued
Continued on Page 2</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1908-04-26/ed-1/seq-69/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DEATH IN PATH
OF TORNADO IN
SEVEN STATES
Rye Hahdrcd Killed ;MoreJliafl
/a fthoiasand Hurt by* Fear-; *
Southern towns . Laid ; Low by
i ,' Twisting Windl arid Loss H
.;•' -Reaches^Mfliidns:te
Scenes -of 4 Misery, and (Freakish
; : Incidents Mark Story oi : \u25a0 ,
, / ;V-, £3 j
::<AIXAJJTA;:: :< AIXAJJTA;: Go^ April SS^-Tp. to »
•'clock tonight the dead and lajvred Ilk
Frld*y*» tornado are \u25a0» follows:
* Lon»Uiaa— Dtad,' OD| Injured, 350.
'-" 31 ia«U»]ppi — D«ad, IS3; lajwred, «50. '
AlabluM— Dead,' 31 ; la jured,' 1 13.
* Gwiti*— Dead, 35 1 Injured,* 100.
-. ... T>l» . makes .the dead' for f oar "atstea
311} Injured, In rrhieh minor tajarle*
\u25a0xe"B»t lnelnded, I^l3. - :
, (An incomplete list of the dead and In
jured ' made up from \u25a0• t el egTaphic repor U
from'throughbut the. 'south" places "the
number of killed at 308 and the injured
at^l,o3l'a£'thV following points: .
;,TaTna~- \\u25a0'-'\ \u25a0' -' -\u25a0 . Killed. : lnjnrt4.
B«rsea. - Ala] ..'...'....11.:'..... 4. ,1S
Cedar, O^ArAlal^.l.V.,.-..^-. 8 13
D«igcr*t,;' > Al«C r -V.".^.. '...'..'.'.'. \u25a0••*.
Tttrt; Depart t.- A1a... V.-..'.i..«. -3«' !25 ; '
\u25a0BeedßT^Ala!*' .-."...•..... V5.. :..... 2- - * -3
Tkonnrrllle.. Ala. . ....... 1...'.\ . : 2 . . " 10*...
W»ir!or.' "AU. ". ."...'...«." 3 1 T-
J Tot*l;.for^. AJ*b«a»«. .'. ..... ... S2 V • " mr *
Anlte;'tiu^.. ;.*..'...-..'......... 13 •!«>'"
Aaii«.,L«.*.;.................;"' 2.' 10-
C»*l»ip«rl*a >.*..'...V..'«.V. : .'".T."^3 1 -? : »\.
BScilaad, -La. ... i ......:.:,^-.; i 4 x^ *;» V
"*; Total- for I/m151aaa^. ......... 23, »• 123
AcUartj »ontx. : Miss. ........*'... 25 .* IQO.-
BaxierrOl*. " ...'.J..-:... '8 10
ChaarßOl.N Mi«s.'- ........ ... 35; 100-.-
Colombo*. • Silas. -. .»../.."..'.. — .-I •, - \u25a0 -,4':\
JET«7«tt* % cwai ty •.;.... T;.',".. •••'. 3 • "r»3^"
McCaKam.^ MSm." * ."i . .'.'..*.'.*...*. .* 12' . • 35 ' 't*
\rcrata.jxu*.* ;..... .*:. V.'.:....«: •s* 1 '
Satchjn^jM^r . \u25a0.tr^.*.'^*. .*,, '."...'»:: .V 2OO A"
Port ;*oajf«u' iiiM.?l:;..::::.ii*ir "V* 1 V*i >
Pbttl«. !Ji taa." . . . . . . . Z . . ... 1 ... B2 " '-; " " 230 .. -
w»ki:«i. . mimT-1.T.:-.. :..:.-.. .."'s- * 33
TCHr»te,-MiM. • ..:.:..........., 3- . V^nco'
, Craad V tPUI ....-\u25a0.. ...'."~ ' ..^0S ;" .' lj»i^" '
'.'.. NEW :_ORLEA2N'S. April SS.^PTobably.
half a thousand lives lost; a hundred or
more persons fatally • Injured and many
times this number 'painfully,* hurt, to
gether with a prop'trty loss running up
in the millions. i 3 the record 20 far of
a tornado that originated in the west
two days] ago, •' sweeping Texas, Arkan
sas. - Lousiana. ' Tennessee. ': Mississippi
and Georgia. It has left a path of death,
desolation and, want In its' wake, seri
ously -Interrupted all communication be
tween ; cities T- In" the ; south and . brought;
about chaotic conditions in many small
er, towns. .
-V Mississippi.-, already, a . sn£f erer.; from
more, than one . tornado, this year, 'has
again -borne the brtmCbf : the- winds and
rains"': Estimates of the number.of thoW*
iWfeo;lo«t their lives In that state'plaCce ;
the death. list between 130 and I« s. with
a th'ou3an.d or more Injured.
t/ In >.Teias,^ Louisiana; : Alabama , and
Georgia, the death ; lists. are also-large,
with I serious ; loss "j"b? .' lif cV in Arkansas :
and -Tennessee - Authentic j Information '
Is_}n \u25a0 many, instances : lacking, 1 * owtogito ;
|the,*crippled, facilities"; f otfcoinmanlai-, 1
"tkiq.Vand i}hf j fack-i of % tlme"^; to' _f orm >
anything ' like an" accurate estlxnata of •
the. damage dona 'in man* sections..
. In half a doz;n commucities martial
law": bits been declared. •so terribl«*,waji :
the; destruction* and- so -helpless _were
the^ stricken people lef V.bythe disaster.
Serious disorders ha'v* occurred in some..
places/'lntlnaingYAmlte,' La. . * Looting"'
andTother crimes have, been reported.
botJthoWVinstanceslbave on the whole .
been rrkre.- > * : "'_ "'\u25a0"".\u25a0\u25a0''•;'.; • \u25a0
. 'Several'-'places -"'have^ issued appeals.
fof-_ : afdi andfln" Misfstssippl' GoveAio?
Nbe'l.: has*" been I asked" to 'provide' tents 4
{or^th^'aonieleas. - -.
:J. The>.tofßa.dQes ; lasted . In ; all a ' period .
of .nearly. Uwc-days. "It was .Thursday
night- that; damage by-tornadoes-trav
eling: eastward was 'first, reported from ;
polats.in Texas.* " ThlV.'-'was- followed : '
duringyjtheVjnei?^-?* jr^<>uv9 _by similar,'
reports^fromTA^k«iias^ : 'luoulsiana.'Mls^
aissippt £TenieVsee. .,- rnlght*
AlabJma^caSV-wlthlnv the- Sight of ithe ;
"storm.iaad * today£ reports of* "serious J
daliageiVby^the ;wlnds .ln'Georyhi ha.\9 ;
be«n P recbrd«d.^ ' \u25a0
-';' Utter"-mls'e,Vy,^Qf *. .every, sort ' was
\u25a0fbundT'tbday Purvis 'Miss.; by Ire- '
\M * p aHlosriiDf Iplte* the I facV tha t of
theijlioOMnhabltanis * which "^thisjHUle"
tbw*n^b\»astedly»«t«rday' rßoVnlng. ther*
>rere-oniy 900 today, \ still there -were
not^sufflclent accomtnodatlons la , the-
Vrecked Jfitlkgt: for. eves : the-: wo-^nded..
NegrV-mimniles* and, iitrle. black chtld
reVria^Vounlfled" and K.j*lpl« s"s under flhV
bVotling^scTuthera^ iun* '[, Some' . had.
broken b^ncs/sorae'were^'partly crushed,
"and'others'iiaa^ian
andjspilnters.f. These .unfortunates were
rtucky";lf they had "a \blank«tlor a storm
wrecked couch upon-, which .to • rest.
Tfiere"? "was V?ot i'eiiongh \ sbejter"; ln* the
k *t4wiajita protect "them ;from the^iun,
• and \u25a0 manor ISt "the ; wajls whlch T r«mained
standJngbadfn'O'roofs,- and. by a queer'
1 reak'of thetbrnado many of the tre«a</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87082863/1908-04-26/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW ORLEANS. April 2o. Proba
bly half a thousand lives wore, lost, a
hundred or moro persons fatally injured
and many times this number painfully
hurt, together with a property loss
running up into millions, is the reeord
so far of the tornado which originated
iu the west two days ago, sweeping Tex
as, Arkansas, Louisiana, Tennessee and
Georgia. It left a path o death, deso
lation and want in its wake, serious
ly interrupted all communication be
tween cities in the south and brought
about chaotic conditions in many small
er towns.
Mississippi, already a sufferer from
m&tc than one tornado this year, again
bore tho brunt of tho wind and rain.
Estimates of the number of those who
lost their lives in the state place tho
death list near 300. with over 1,000 in
jured. In Texas, Louisiana, Alabama and
Georgia the death lits are also large,
with a Forioiw loss of life in Arkansas
and Tonueaxoe. Autheutic information
in many instances is lacking, owing to
the crippled facilities for communica
tion, and lack of time to form anything
like an accurate estimate of the damage
doni 3.i man yscetious.
Martial 'Law Declared.
In a half do.en communities martial
lav; has been declared, so terrible is tho
destrnct'on, and -so helpless the strick
en people left by tho disaster. Serious
disorders occurred in norne places, in
cluding Amite, La. looting ai:d other
crimes have been reported, but theso
instances have won rare.
Several places have issued appeals for
aid in Mississippi and Governor Noel
has been asked to provide tents for tho
homeless.
The tornadoes lasted, in all, a period
of nearly ten days. Thursday night
damage was done by tornadoes traveling
eastward, first reported from points in
Texas. Those were followed during tho
next twenty-four hours by similar re
port front .Aaknnsas, Iiuiniana; Mis
sissippi and Tennessee. Last night Ala
bama came withiu the flight of tho
storm, and today reports of serious dam
age in Georgia aro recorded.
Gonditionr Aro Terrible.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84036008/1908-04-28/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DEATH AND I DESOLATION IN.
WAKE Of TORNADO WHICH
SWEEPS OVER SOUTH.
HUNDREDS KILLED
Martial Law Is Decljred In Dozen
Communities So Terrible Was De
struction-Several Paces Issue Ap
peals For Aid-Lasted Two Days
Wind'Doubles on Tracks.
New Orleans, April 25.--Probably
half a thousand lives lost, a hundred
o; more persons fatally injured and
many times this number painfully
hurt, together with a property loss
running into the millions, is the rec
ord so far of a tornado that originated
in the west two days ago, sweeping
Texas, Arkansas, Louisiana, Tennes
see, Alabama and Georgia. .It has
left a path of death, desolation and
want in its. wake, seriously interrupt
ed all communication between cities
ii the south, and bro'ught chaotic con
ditfons in many shaller towns.
Mississippi, already, a sufferer from
more than one tornado this year, has
again borne the brunt of the winds
and rains. Estimates of the number
of those who. lost their lives in that
state place the death list near 300,
wlth a thousand or more injured.
Appeal to Governor.
In Texas, Louisiana, Alabama and
Georgia, the lists are also large, with
serious loss of life in Arkansas and
Tennessee. In half. a dozen commun
ities martial law has been declared,
so terrible was the destruction and
so helpless were the stricken people
left by the disaster. Serious disorders
have occt red in some places, includ
ing Amite, La., looting' and other
crimes have been reported, but these
inttances have been, on the whole,
rare.
Several places have issued appeals
for aid and in Mississippi Governor
Noel has been asked to provide tents
for the homeless.
Travels Eastward.
The tornadoes lasted in all a period'
of nearly two days. It was Thurs
day night that damage by tornadoes
traveling. eastward was first' reported
from points in Texa's. This was fol
lowed during the next 24 hours ,by
similar reports from Arkansas, Louis
fana, Mississippi and Tennessee.
Last night Alabama came within the
flight of the sto'rm and today reports
of serious damage by the winds in
Georgia have been recorded.
Utter misery of every sort was
found 'today at Purvis, Miss., by re
lief parties. Despite the fact that
of the 2,500 inhabitants which this
little town boasted yesterday morn-'
ing, there were only 900 today; still,
there were not sufficient accopidda
tions Eh the village for even the
wounded: Negro mammies and little
black children lay wounded and help;
less under the broiling sun. 'Some
had -broken bones, some were partly
crushed and others had been wounded
by sticks and splinters.
Blanket a Luxury.
These unfortunates -Were lucky if
they had a blanket or a storm-wricked
couch upon which to rest. There was
lot enough shelter in thie town to pro
tedt them from'the,sun and many of
the walls which remained standinmg
had no roofs and by a queer freak of
the tornado, many of the trees which
had not been uprooted had been
snatched off a few feet above the
ground. The grove of pines was mut
ilated in a manner so that it appeared
as if a giant scythe had swept through.
the grove about 25 feet above the
ground.
The greater part of Purvis' popula
tion today were refugees' in 'Hattles
burg and Lumberton, Miss., about 150
of ihem beeing badly injured. 'Of those
who rematined in town many appear
ed distracted' and they told remark
able storieq of the number of their
townspeople 'whohad been kiled.
H "rHed Punerals.
Many lhurried funerals were held
today 'e. a co.nt of th6 visible dead
revealed only 34,; about halt of them.
negroes.
The manner in' which the tornado
acted at this village puizzled to those
who witnessed, it. Instead o4 enter
ing the town at' one.flide and passinig
out at the other, the storm swirled
and see-sawed about. Once or twice,
Judging from the lay of the debris
today, the wind veered so much as
nearly to double on its tracks' The
result was terrible for the inhabi
tantp, many of whom were caught
and either injuredt or killed, after
they had apparently escaped.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058245/1908-04-30/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HORROR OF FEARFUL STORM
THAT SWEPT OVER SOUTH
Storm Lasted for dearly Two Day
and In Places Twister Doubled
on Its Tracks Finishing
Work of Destruction
Now Orleans Mississippi al
ready a sufferer from more than ono
tornado ttila year has again borne tho
brunt of tbo winds and rains Esti
mates of tho number at those who
lost their lives In that state during
tho recent two days of terrific wind
storms pinto tho death list near 200
with several hundred Injured
In Texas Louisiana Alabama and
Georgia tho death lists aro also largo
with serious JOBS of life In Arkansas
and Tennessee
III hair a dozen communities mar
tial law has been declared so terrlblo
was tho destruction and so helpless
wore tho stricken people left by tho
disaster Serious disorders havo oc
curred In somo places Including
Amltc Lit Looting and other crimes
havo been reported but these In
stances have been on tho wliolo rare
Several places have Issued appeals
for aid and In Mississippi Governor
Noel has been asked to provide tents
for thn homeless
Tho tornadoes lasted In all a period
of nearly two days It was Thurs
day night that damage by tornadoes
traveling eastward was firm reported
from points In Texas This was fol
lowed during tho next twentyfour
hours by similar reports from Arkan
sas Louisiana Mississippi and Ten
nessee Friday night Alabama came I
within the lllglit of tho storm and
Saturday reports of serious damago
by tho winds In Georgia were record
ed An Incomplete list of tho dead
and Injured In lira storm made up
Irom telegraph reports from various
points through the south places tho
number of killed at 308 and Injured
at 1091
Utter misery of every sort was
fcund at Purvis Miss by relief par
ties Despite tho fact that of the
2500 Inhabitants which this little
town boasted there were only 900 loft
still there wore not sufficient accom
modations In tho wrecked village for
oven tho wounded
Tim manner In which tho tornado
acted at this village puzzled those
who witnessed It Instead of enter
ing tho town at ono side and passing
out at tho other tho storm whirled
and seesawed about Once or twice
judging from tho lay of tho debris tho
wind veered so much as nearly to
double ou Its trail The result was
tdrrlblo for tho Inhabitants many of
vhom wero caught and either injured
or killed after they had apparently
escaped in
The usual freaks wero played by
tho wind Twentyseven prisoners
wero In tho little town jail The roof
was lifted off but so terrorstricken
woro they that not ono gained his
freedom None of tho prisoners was
seriously Injured The wreckage
which remained on tho site of a lum
ber mill near town consisted largely
of splinters from the size of tooth
picks up to small sticks
GOLD STRIKE NEAR ARCTIC
Bishop Brings News of Find at Head
of Koyukuk River
Seattle1 T Howe bishop of the
Episcopal church for the territory ot
Alaska who arrived In the city Sun
day from the north on tho Yucatan
brings tho first detailed authentic In
formation regarding tho gold strike on
Nolan creek at tho head of Koyukuk
river Nolan creek Is only about 200
miles from the Arctic ocean Tho
strlko was made at a depth of about
ICO feet It is estimated that the
cleanup at tho end of the summer will
Teach 1000000
Many Victims of Storm
Atlanta Ga Belated reports from
Alecon Miss say that fifteen persons
wero killed In that neighborhood and
a number of others Injured in Fridays
cyclonic disturbances Much property
destruction was also reported Mrs
J C Coleman a Gyearold child of
W E Bobbo and Emmot Russell died
in a hospital nt Albortvlllo Sunday
as a result of Injuries received in Fri
days storm making a total of eleven
whites and two negroes dead at that
place A second violent storm swept
Fort Deposit Ala Sunday
Taft Has No r Intention of Resigning
Washington Tho story is wholly
unauthorized declared Secretary of
War Taft when
his attention was
called to tho statement from Havana
stating that Thomas P Egan of Cin
cinnati In an Interview Is quoted as
saying positively that Secretary Tart
wpuld resign Immediately If nominat
ed at tho Chicago convention and
that Governor Magoon of Cuba would
succeed him as secretary of war The
secretary added that so far as JIO
know there was no foundation for tho
statement
Twentyeight Are Missing
London Tho total number of dead
and missing of tho Gladiators crow as
a result of a collision between tho
American liner St Paul and tho Brit
ish cruiser off tho Isle of Wight Is
twentyeight Th opinion among ship
ping men and naval olIl ers and offi
cials appears to bo unanimous that
tho accident was unavoidable being
cue of the chances of tho sea which
all seamen must risk All witnesses
of tho disaster agree practically that
both crows behaved as well as possi
blo
tORNADO D O STRIKS
THE S SUNNY SOUTH
Two Hundred and flay Residents
of Alabama Louisiana and Mis
sissippi Meet Death
Mot of Those Killed Wore Negroes
Whose Flimsy Cabl lere Swept
Away Like So I Paper
Property Loss Enormous
Atlanta Ga Reports Indicate that
at least 250 persons were killed and
about 400 injured in storms of great
violence whch passed over sections of
Louisiana Mississippi and Alabama on
Friday Several towns wero almost
totally swept away and Uio property
damage will run into largo figures
Most of those killed were negroes
whoso cabins wero swept away like
so much paper
Natchez Miss reports that of sixty
four persons killed In 1 that section only
two were whites
Into reports from Amlte a small
town In southeastern Louisiana say
that the town was almost entirely de
stroyed and the estimates place tho
number killed at between twontyflvo
and fifty while at least seventyfive
were Injured
At McLnln Miss eight are reported
to have been killed at Vldalla Ia
ono white woman and six negroes are
dead at Qultman Landing eleven ne
gioes were killed at Purvis Landing
Miss three whites and nine negroes
were victims of the storm and reports
of from one to live deaths come from
many towns scattered over the storm
swept area
In Louisiana It Is estimated that a
score of small towns were destroyed
or partially wrecked They Include
Amlto City Arcadia and Independ
ence while Bello Grove Velton Lor
man Pine Hldge Qultman Landing
Falrchllds Creek Purvlso and Lum
btrton Miss are reported seriously
damaged by the storm
In Alabama Dora was the chief suf
ferer This town Is also known as
Bergen Four or more poisons were
killed Fifty persons at tho lowest
estimate were Injured Those most
seriously hurt were carried to hos
pitals In Birmingham Ala
Ulchland and Lamourie La were
struck by tho storm and nearly a fifth
of their population Injured
Winchester Miss a small town Is
reported wiped out though only two
persons are known to have been
killed
Mobile reported nine dead in Hat
tlesburg Miss
What appears to have been two dif
ferent tornadoes also struck western
Alabama ono claiming six victims at
Bergen and Thomas sawmill small
places and another striking Albervllle
where thirty persons are reported to
have been killed</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86075153/1908-04-30/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1908&index=11&rows=20&words=tornado+tornadoes&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1908&proxtext=tornado&y=17&x=7&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>VICTIMS OF STORM
Southern States Visited by Hurricanes
Devastating in Their Character.
ý.,.1 lost, a
r. , fatally in
number
' i a pro
' millions,
-' t. ' tornado
*;4l, : rt two days
" Arkansas,
' ,,. \ 1lana and
i, atio, desc
se. orious
".iatioýn be
, tiith and
:litiofns in
sufferer
.1flado this
'' ' i. I ru: t of
' mates of
:heir lives
death list
, or more
, .aba'na and
ao-,a large,
T . , n Arkansas
Srinforma
Si:. lacking,
, i ' , 1',i t :facilities for
S liack of time
S t , '.: i anl accurate
- f aiage done in
iaf a z cdliiiUnities mar
. ha teen , ' i -a ' d, so terri
Ste vstruti~.ui and so help
e tri cke Peole left by
,rr. S-en1,us disorders have
k in sun places, including
,. Lot'ng and other crimes
Sr''lorted, but these in
S-have 1>e(n on the whole
erl laces have isued appeals
for aid, and in Mississippi Gov. Noel
has been asked to provide tents for
the homeless.
The tornadoes lasted a period of
nearly two days. It was Thursday
night that damage by tornadoes
traveling eastward was first report
ed from points in Texas. This was
followed the next twenty-four hours
by similar reports from Arkansas,
Louisiana, Mississippi and Tennes
see. Last night Alabama came with
in the flight of the storm and to
day reports of serious damage by
the winds in Georgia have been re
corded.
At Mclain, Miss., eiglit are re
ported to have been killed; at Vida
lia, La., one white woman and six
negroes are dead; at Quitman Land
ing, eleven negroes were killed; at
Purvis Landing, Miss., three whites
and nine negroes were victims of
the storm and reports of from one
to five deaths come from many
towns scattered over the stormswept
area.
In Alabama, Dore was the worst
sufferer. The town is also known
as Bergen. Four or more persons
were killed, among them the wife
and daughter of Section Master
Moore. Fifty persons at the low
est estimate were injured. Those
most seriously hurt were carried to
hospitals in Birmington, Ala. One
woman, Mrs. McCully, died on the
train.
Reports also say that the storm
struck Albertville, Ala., late yester
day afternoon, doing much damage
to life and property. An uncon
firmed report h.ere gives the
death list as thirty to thfrty-five,
with scores of persons injured.' A
train was ent from DUWh.
last night carrying physicians and a
squad of state militiamenr to the dis
trict.
From Meridian, Miss., came a re
port that Mrs. John Minnice and her
child were killed outright and John
Minnice was seriously injured, while
a number of other persons w er
hurt and there was considerable de
stuction of property.
At Richland, La., the storm killed
four persons, fatally injured a num
ber and destroyed thousands of dol
lars' worth of property. About a
hundred or more people were more
or less seriously injured. Ephraim
Pearce and his wife and baby were
killed when their house was blown
down upon them, and a negro child
was killed. Two negroes were fa
tally injured.
At Bergen, in Alabama, two per
sons were killed and fifty injured.
Four persons were found dead in
the woods. Albert Ville is reported
destroyed. Many were injured and
killed by the tornado.
New Orleans, April 25.-Amite,
La., was so badly damaged that it
was put under martial law at once
by order of its mayor. The storm
struck just about noon, killing two
white persons and thirteen neg:-oes
outright and injuring many others.
mostly negroes, so badly that physi
cians who were rushed into the town
in relief trains from several points
said the total death list of Amite
would reach at least twenty-five.
Rev. Father Felix Pumpf was
possibly the first person killed at
Amite. He was in the bell tower of
his church, having just finished
ringing th, noonday bell. He was
crushed to death by the falling
tower. Mrs. A. N. Ogden was
caught by the tornado as she was
driving to her home. A tree fell
acrss her horse, killing the animal,
but she was unjurt. Forty persons
werest dirter in the commercial
hoite hben he storm struck and
rf owaS carried away, but not
one of the diners was hurt. The
path of the tornado was about two
and a half miles wide, and when i t
had passed,' Amite stood a wreck.
Large numbers of farm animals
were killed.
The greatest loss of life amorg
negroes occurred in the vicinity of
Natchez. In Concordia Parish, Loui
siana, across the Mississippi from
Natchez, thirteen lives were lost, all
except two of the dead being ne
groes. Twenty-five persons were
killed in the vicinity of Church
ill. The tornadoes in this section
were about one hundred miles due
north of the Amite tornado, and
struck about breakfast time. It
was in this section that a negro baby
was caught in the wind, carried three
hundred yards and deposited in a
swamp unhurt. An aged negro
woman was whirled into the air and
her head almost severed by flying
timbers before she fell in the cotton
field a hundred yards from where
her cabin had stood. The body of
a little negro boy was found in a
field with a piece of timber driven
through the heart.
Natchez, Miss., April 25.-Two
bodies, both colored and badly man
gled, victims of yesterday's tornado,
were found between Giles Rend and
Pine Ridge this morning, bringing
the list of dead in this section to
seventy-one, of which number all
are negros but two.
Five died at the local hospitals
duriiig the night. Some of the in
jured are not expected to live.
Three wagon loads of injured ne
groes from Churchill neighborhood
with three victims in each were re
ceived at Natchez charity hospital
this morning. These arrivals were
reinforced 1y seven from Lucerna
plantation in Corcordia Parish, La.
One negro boy was almost wrapped
around a tree, his leg being broken
in four places and his right arm be
ing broken. His mother and two
sisters were killed. His father is
dying from a fractured skull and
four of his brothers also were injur
ed. All of the physicians volunteer
ed services and four white volun
teer nurses are assisting in the
hospitals.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88056094/1908-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1908&index=0&rows=20&words=DIXIE+TORNADO&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1908&proxtext=dixie+tornado&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TORNADO TEARS
TOWNS IN DIXIE
Carries Death and Destruction to
Southern States
ATLANTA, Ga., April 25.—Re
ports today indicate that 225 persons
were killed and at least 1000 injured
in storms of great violence which
passed over sections of Louisiana,
Mississippi and Alabama yesterday
nd last night. Several towns were
lmost totally swept away and the
roperty damage will run into large
gures. Most of those killed were
egroes, whose cabins were swept
way like so much paper.
At Nachcz, 64 Die.
Natchez, Miss., reports that of 64
ersons killed in that section only
were whites.
Late reports from Amite, La., a
mall town in southeastern Louisi
ana, say that the town was almost
ntirely destroyed and that estimates
lace the number killed at between
5 and 50, while at least V 5 were In
ured.
At MoLaln, Miss., eight are report
to have been killed, at Vidaia, La.
e white woman and six negroes are
~ad; at Quitman landing 11 negroes
ere killed.
The latest report at hand comes
om Purvis Landing, Miss., where 30
bites and 50 negroes were victims
jf the storm and reports of one to
ve deaths come from many towns
mattered over the storm-swept area
etaiis at present are meager.
Wires I town.
New Orleans and Mobile were cut
from wire communication with
( outside world for several hours
day and the telegraph companies
port wires down in ail directions.
Last night the storm swept
rough Georgia, but beyond torren
1 rains, accompanied by high winds
d brilliant electric displays, no se
us damage or loss of life has been
ported.
In Louisiana it is estimated that a
■ore of small towns were destroyed
partly wrecked.
They include Amite City, Arcadia
d Independence. Belle Grove,
leton, Lorman, Pine Ridge, Quit
n Landing, Fairchilds Creek, Pur
Landing and Lumberton, Miss.,
reported damaged by the storm.
Fifty Hurt at Dora.
In Alabama, Dora was the chief
fferer. This town is also known as
rgen. Four or more persons were
lied, among them the wife and
ughter of Section Master Moore,
fty persons at the lowest estimate
ere injured. Those most seriously
iart were carried to hospitals in Bir
ingham, Ala. One woman, Mrs.
cCully, died on the train.
Reports say that the storm also
ruck Albertville. La., late yesterday
iternoon, doing much destruction to
and property. An unconfirmed
port from this section gives the
ath list as from 30 to 35, with
ores of persons injured. A train
i sent from Birmingham last night
carry physicians and a squad of
te militiamen to the district.
Towns Wiped Out.
From Meridian, Miss., comes a re
rt that Mrs. John Minniero and her
lid were killed outright and John
lnniero seriously injured, while a
rnber of other persons were hurt
d there was much destruction of
perty.
Rysland and Lamourie, La., were
ck by the storm and nearly a
of their people injured.
Winchester, Miss., a small town,
reported wiped out, though only
o persons are known to have been
led.
Mobile reported nine dead at Hat
Lurg. Mias., but this has not been
firmed.
In all, nearly 20 towns were struck
the "twisters." of which there
ra to have been at least five.
The tornado that first appeared in
ncordla pariah. La., appears to
▼e been the most serious, both In
P*°t to number of victims and ex
t of territory covered. Although
covered a rural district and struck
large tows, the known results of
work are C4 dead and at least 100
rad. with the prospect that the
will be much swollen by morn
More than SO of the dead are ne
| groes. whose log cabins proved par
ticularly fatal to the occupants, be
ing easily torn to pieces, while the
* weight of timber crushed the inmates
to death.
Relief to Sufferers.
W'hat appears to have been two
different tornadoes struck in western
Alabama, one claiming six victims
at Bergen and at Thomas' sawmill,
another storm striking Albertville,
where 30 persons are reported to
have been killed. This can not be
confirmed, as all wires are down.
Four Dead at Richland.
ALEXANDRIA, La., April 25.—A
tornado which struck Richland, La.,
16 miles south of here, killed four
people, fatally Injured two and de
stroyed thousands of dollars' worth
of property
About a hundred or more people
were more or less seriously injured.
Ephraim Pearce and his wife and
baby were killed when their home
was blown down upon them, and
negro child was killed. Two negroes
were fatally injured.
At Bergj-n, Two Killed.
BIRMINGHAM, Ala., April 26.—
Bergen, Walker county, is reported
to have been struck by a tornado,
two persons being killed and 50 In
jured. Four persons were found
dead In the woods. Albertville Is re
ported destroyed; many were injured
and killed by a tornado.
Five Dio at Vidalia.
NATCHEZ, Miss., April 25.—Five
persons were killed and several in
jured in a tornado which swept over
Vidalia, La.
Town of Wails Destroyed.
MEMPHIS, Tenn., April 25. — A
tornado swept over Walls, Miss., and
is reported to have destroyed the
town.
Three persons are reported killed,
anti several injured. Telegraph and
telephone wires are down between
Memphis and Walls.
The roof of the Yazoo & Missis
sippi Valley railroad depot was blown
off and the building wrecked. A re
lief train has left Memphis for the
scene. Walls is on the Yazoo A
Mississippi Valley road, a few miles
below Lakeview.
Demolishes Walls • Stores
MEMPHIS, April 25. — At the
Memphis office of the Yazoo A Mis
sissippi Valley railroad it was report
ed that several persons had been
killed at Walls.
At Mason, Tenn., the Methodist,
Presbyterian and Episcopal churches
and several residences were blown
down. In Memphis the wind reached
velocity of 60 miles an hour, up
rooting trees, blowing down tele
graph and telephone poles and forc
ing in plate glass windows.
Amite's Death List Heaviest.
NEW ORLEANS, April 25. —
Amite, a small town in southwestern
Louisiana, was almost entirely de
stroyed by a tornado. The dead are
estimated at from 25 to 50. The
first details were brought to New Or
leans by train, along with 17 injured,
and the dead list was placed at 45.
Physicians who have been engaged in
relief work at Amite asserted that
this estimate was correct. Corre
spondents on the scene, however, as
sert that not more than a dozen were
killed outright, but that so many suf
fered fatal injuries that the list will
reach 25.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038485/1908-05-08/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1908&index=1&rows=20&words=Dixie+tornadoes&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1908&proxtext=dixie+tornado&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Tempestuous Weather
The weather this spring has not been ■
calm and normal although it has as a
rule been pretty good for the growing j
crops. There has been an element in
it, however, tnat bred tempests and i
tornadoes, and scarcely any change in |
it has been free from dangerous winds.
The storm that swept over four states 1
in the last days of April‘will be long |
remembered, and besides that great j
storm weekly, if not daily', hurricanes
have visited some part of Dixie Land.
Few tornadoes have been reported
in the northwest or central west, and
for some reason not clearly or fully i
explained the south has been this year j
the chief theatre of winds and violent !
storms. These eccentricities of nature !
will soon, let us hope, subside and
cease altogether to be. We do not ‘
need any more this year. The spring !
of 1908 has already made a storm rec- j
ord, and it should be content to rest on [
its abnormality by letting normal
weather return to this section of the
country.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85049554/1913-04-01/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=outbreak+tornado&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=tornado+outbreak&y=13&x=23&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92070450/1920-11-11/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20&words=Alabama+Georgia+Louisiana+Mississippi+tornadoes&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=tornado%2C+Mississippi%2C+Georgia%2C+Louisiana%2C+Alabama&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89064515/1908-05-01/ed-1/seq-9/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Alabama+Georgia+Louisiana+Mississippi+tornado&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=tornado%2C+Mississippi%2C+Georgia%2C+Louisiana%2C+Alabama&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>New Orleans, April 25.—Tha dead
more than 300, the Injured at least
1,000 the3e are the grim facts which
came to light when the wreckage
of the tornado in Georgia, Louisiana,
Mississippi and Alabama had been
cleared away. The tornadoes lasted
altogether about twelve hours, strik­
ing promiscuously one town after the
other. Many hours after they struck
trains bearing nearly 200 Injured came
crawling cautiously out of tha tor­
nado districts, leaving behind them
one town, Purvis, Miss., utterly de­
molished, five others practically blown
away and forty little villages in
more or less acute stages of ruin.
With these wounded came the details
of one of the worst wiud disasters in
the history of the Gulf states.
First of all it became known that
negroes comprised most of the dead,
that the picturesque darky cabins,
noted for their flimsy, happj' go lucky
construction, had been converted by
the wind into wholesale death traps.
It was in the fall of these cabins,
which went down almost without
warning, that most of the negro deaths
occurred. These always overcrowded
cabins also furnished most of the
badly wounded.
The destruction of Purvis, Miss.,
was complete in a few minutes time.
Of about 200 dwelling houses only
seven were left standing. The court­
house, the only other building in town
to withstand the wind, was immedi­
ately packed with dead and injured
and served as the only available hos­
pital within many miles.
Amite, La., Under Martial Law.
Amite, La., was so badly damaged
that it was put under martial law by
order of its mayor. The storm killed
two white persons and thirteen ne­
groes outright and injured many oth
ers, mostly negroes, so badly 'that
physicians say the total death list of
Amite would reach at least twenty
live. Rev. Father Felix Rumpf was
possibly the first person killed. He
was in the bell tower of his church,
having just finished ringing the bell.
He was crushed to death by the fall­
ing tower.
The path of the tornado was about
two and a half miles wide and when
It had passed Amite stood a wreck.
Large numbers of farm animals were
killed.
Forty-six towns report serious
wreckage by the storm, in which 2,
500 business houses and habitations
were laid in ruins. The following is
a list by sfites of the forty-six towns
reporting more or less damage:
Louisiana—Lucerne, Kenmore, La
inourle, Richland, Amtte, Essie, Pine,
Angle, Franklinton, Sheridan, Avard,
Eunice. Total, twelve.
Mississippi—Gilles Bend, Purvis,
Churchill, Lorman, Tillman, Malton,
Baxterviiie, Braxton, Sunflower, Wa­
halak, Wingate, Columbus, Walls,
Fairchilds Creek, Quitmana Landing,
McLaurin, McCallum, Winchester,
Pine Ridge. Total, nineteen.
Georgia—Columbus, Chipley, La
Orange, Harris, Griffin, McDonough,
Locust Grove, Cedartown, Cave
Springs. Total, nine.
Alabama—Albertville, High Mound,
Hatton, Leesburg, Settlement, Blounts
vHle. Total, six.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96060765/1920-11-12/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=13&rows=20&words=Alabama+Georgia+Louisiana+Mississippi+tornadoes&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=tornado%2C+Mississippi%2C+Georgia%2C+Louisiana%2C+Alabama&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92064044/1908-10-30/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=1908+tornadoes&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=tornadoes+1908&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85034082/1908-04-30/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A destructive tornado last Friday
night struck Mississippi, Louisiana,
Georgia and Alabama, touching forty
six towns, killed about 850 people, in
jured 1,213, and made thouasands home
less. The Rushton Cotton Mills, near
Griffin, Ga., was destroyed.
Dikp.—Mrs. C. H. Martin, wife of Mr.
H. T. Martin, died in this city at the
home of the family on Maple avenue
last Thursday afternoon of cancer of
the face. She was 58 years of age, and
a good Christian woman. She leaves a
husband and four children. Her fu
neral was conducted by Rev. A.R.
Bond. The interment was at Mt
Bethel. We sympathize with the be
reaved family.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90000523/1920-09-09/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=10&rows=20&words=Alabama+Georgia+Louisiana+Mississippi+tornadoes&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=tornado%2C+Mississippi%2C+Georgia%2C+Louisiana%2C+Alabama&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
